<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hearthstone | theScore</title>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">10445</guid>
  <title>Dignitas release Hearthstone players</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10445</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 21:10:24 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/6114/w1080xh810_dignitas.jpg?ts=1445374148">
    <media:credit>Team Dignitas</media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>Team Dignitas have released all of their Hearthstone players and will no longer support Hearthstone, the organization <a href="http://team-dignitas.net/articles/news/Hearthstone/10192/team-dignitas-releases-hearthstone-squad">announced</a> Saturday.</p><p>Dignitas originally entered Hearthstone in August 2014 with the signing Nick "<strong>Cookmysock</strong>" Li, Lewis '<strong>Blackout</strong>' Spencer and James '<strong>Greensheep</strong>' Luo to the team. In the two years of its existence, Dignitas players have won the 2015 HWC - Asia-Pacific Championship, DreamHack Valencia 2015 and DreamHack Austin 2016.</p><p>Dignitas' Hearthstone lineup was as follows:</p><ul><li>Lewis '<strong>Blackout</strong>' Spencer</li><li>James '<strong>Greensheep</strong>' Luo</li><li>Kahjun '<strong>Kranich</strong>' Baek</li><li>Todd '<strong>Anakins</strong>' Rolls</li></ul><div><span style="font-size:18px; line-height:27px">None of the players have yet to join another organization.</span></div><p><em>Preston Dozsa is a news editor for theScore esports. <a href="https://twitter.com/prestondozsa">You can follow him on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">10400</guid>
  <title>Amaz gives Adrianne Curry a lesson in Hearthstone</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10400</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 21:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12010/w1080xh810_GettyImages-521406748.jpg?ts=1473975241">
    <media:credit>Greg Doherty / Getty Images Entertainment / Getty</media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>Bud Light brought model and actress Adrianne Curry together with Hearthstone expert Jason &quot;<strong>Amaz</strong>&quot; Chan under the guise of a Hearthstone arena lesson on their stream, but fans may have learned more about Amaz than they learned about Curry.</p><p>Curry, who is best known for winning the first season of America's Next Top Model, started the stream by admitting that she hasn't played the game in eight months, but Amaz promised that with his guidance, she would make it through with all the new cards in the game. The action kicked off in the arena, which mostly taught Amaz about Curry's appetite for card-based bloodlust.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/182911040" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure><p>Curry spent a good portion of the stream interviewing Amaz about his age. Amaz, 25, is nine years younger than Curry, which led to something of a divide between the two. Warcraft III was Amaz's first game, while Curry was already an adult the first time she played it. Of course, this being the internet, Curry decided to lean into the memes.</p><p>"Am I your mom?" she asked Amaz. "Twitch is also saying 'mom' so maybe I'm your mom? Have you looked into that?"</p><p>Of course, once Curry got a handle on how young Amaz was, she went right back to looking for blood, taking Flame Lance in a Discover roll from Ethereal Peddler because "those really f**k faces."</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/182912256" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure><p>With Amaz's guidance and her own hyper-aggressive play, Curry went 6-3 in her Arena run, though she did throw the last game due to time concerns. To end her stream, Curry proved to the audience that she really had embraced the memes and signed off with six simple words.</p><p>"Harambe. You know what to do." </p><p><em>Daniel Rosen is a news editor for theScore esports. <a href="http://twitter.com/daniel_rosen">You can follow him on Twitter.</a></em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">10380</guid>
  <title>Curator and Barnes are putting on a show at Hearthstone AM Summer Championships</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10380</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 19:27:37 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11160/w1080xh810_KarazhanHeader.jpg?ts=1469810874">
    <media:credit>Blizzard Entertainment</media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>This weekend is the HCT Americas Summer Championship, where the <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9995" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9995">eight players who qualified at the NA preliminaries</a> will do battle for a coveted spot at Blizzcon 2016.</p><p>Alongside old favorites, like Anyfin Paladin and Malygos Token Druid, a number of players are experimenting with newer configurations. In addition to the integration of Karazhan cards, like Curator and Barnes into Dragon Warrior and Midrange Hunter set-ups, there's also a surprising diversity in Shaman decks with both Midrange Totem and Bog Control variants making appearances.</p><p><strong>1. Abar's Curator Dragon Warrior</strong></p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><a href="http://i.imgur.com/kY4Nn03.png"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/kY4Nn03.png"></a></figure><p>The Curator was a card that many didn't know what to do with when Karazhan was first announced. After all, what kind of deck simultaneously runs Dragons, Beasts, and Murlocs? However, Karazhan's local Arcane Guardian will be seeing a lot of play at the Summer Championships, with several players including him in their Dragon Warrior Decks.</p><p><strong>Abar</strong>, in particular, integrates it into his Dragon Warrior to target Sir Finley and one of his two Fierce Monkeys — Sir Mrrgglton provides some late game adaptability, potentially switching out Armor Up for Steady Shot to go face or Life Tap to draw cards, Fierce Monkey provides heavy survivability. Combined with Curator's 4/6 body, Fierce Monkey's 3/4 stats create a whole lot of late game Taunt to keep Abar alive until Grommash, Deathwing, or Ragnaros destroys his opponent.</p><p><strong>2. Pascoa's Midrange Shaman</strong></p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><a href="http://i.imgur.com/9xjG7SX.png"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/9xjG7SX.png"></a></figure><p>While Aggro Shaman has dominated the meta with powerful minions like Flamewreathed Faceless and the dreaded Doomhammer-Rockbiter combo, the Championship is seeing a resurgence of the Midrange Archetype.</p><p>For instance, Pascoa's Shaman deck still has stalwarts like Flamewreathed, Doomhammer, and Thing From Below, but it also seeks to get the most value possible for Spirit Claws through the decidedly un-aggro Spell Damage/Cycle cards Azure Drake and Bloodmage Thalnos. Their Spell Damage combined with the Wrath of Air Totem could potentially turn Maelstrom Portal and Lavashock into significant damage dealers.</p><p><strong>3. Tarei's Barnes Hunter</strong></p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><a href="http://i.imgur.com/65cKewN.jpg"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/65cKewN.jpg"></a></figure><p>Recent Hearthstone releases have seen Hunter receive a number of Secrets and Deathrattle minions, Karazhan alone giving them Cloaked Huntress and Cat Trick, but we've yet to see a viable Secret/Deathrattle Control set-up go the distance in a major tournament.</p><p>Jeffery &ldquo;<strong>Tarei</strong>&rdquo; Liu and others at the Championship hope to change that by using Barnes to fill the board with strong Deathrattles like Savannah Highmane and Infested Wolf, potentially setting up a rare Princess Huhuran play. Additionally, it could dig Cloaked Huntress out of his deck, allowing Tarei to play one or both of his Freezing Traps for free. However, should Barnes summon a Houndmaster, Tarei will only get a 1/1 minion that does not synergize with the rest of the deck. Another issue is that Tarei will have to pace himself, considering the fact the deck has no card draw outside of Quickshot&#39;s last-ditch secondary effect. However, if all else goes wrong, he can always Unleash the Hounds or send out the Call of the Wild.</p><p><strong>4. Rooftrellen's Control Shaman</strong></p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><a href="http://i.imgur.com/vP4ZsP1.png"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/vP4ZsP1.png"></a></figure><p>In addition to Midrange Shaman, the tournament will also see Control Shaman show up. While Tarei is packing a slower Midrange Shaman with Thunder Bluff Valiant and Al'Akir the Windlord as win conditions, <strong>Rooftrellen</strong> has a very unique set-up geared wholly towards defending Ragnaros with powerful taunts like Earth Elemental, Thing from Below, and Bog Creeper as well board clears like Elemental Destruction and Lightning Storm. Those spells combined with Hallazeal the Ascended's healing effect has the potential to bring Rooftrellen back to full health as well as wiping out an aggro player's momentum. One issue he could face is getting locked down by too many Overload cards, but Lava Shock, Emperor Thaurissan and Far Sight could alleviate that.</p><p><strong>5. HOTMeowth's Lance Carrier Zoolock</strong></p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><a href="http://i.imgur.com/78UYRML.png"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/78UYRML.png"></a></figure><p>Edwin “<strong>HOTMeowth</strong>” Cook made <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zZ1D0nKbSOo">a splash at the preliminaries</a> with interesting decks and an interesting style. He looks to cement his reputation at the Championship with a very interesting Zoolock set-up: he has replaced Power Overwhelming with Lance Carrier. Whereas traditional Zoolocks pack Power Overwhelming to trade low-cost minions with heavy threats and to set-up unexpected lethals, Lance Carrier's Battlecry gives minions half the damage (+2 attack) without killing them. While at first it seems quite a sacrifice, Dark Peddler makes up for it somewhat, since it has a good chance of generating a Power Overwhelming. Additionally, Lance Carrier combined with Brann Bronzebeard's effect gives minions the full four damage without killing them the same turn. Also notable is his use of Malchezaar's Imp, which makes Doomguard less of an all-in proposition, and Demonfire which could provide removal or buff minions as needed.</p><p><em>Sasha Erfanian is a Loot Hoarder for theScore esports, mind if he rolls need? <a href="http://twitter.com/sashaerfanian">Follow him on Twitter</a>. </em></p><p> </p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">10393</guid>
  <title>BlizzCon Opening Week to feature all group stage matches for Overwatch, Hearthstone</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10393</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 15:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12007/w1080xh810_BlizzConHeader1.jpg?ts=1473954519">
    <media:credit>theScore esports / Blizzard Entertainment</media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>For competitors in every Blizzard game, BlizzCon is a big deal, but not all of the matches will take place on the big stage from Nov. 4-5.</p><p>The schedule for BlizzCon Opening Week was <a href="https://blizzcon.com/en-us/news/20271915">announced Thursday,</a> and it detailed which matches will take place in the week preceding the event. </p><p>The Overwatch World Cup, which features national teams from countries across the globe, will hold all of their group stage matches from Oct. 29-31 during Opening Week. Eight teams will then enter the single-elimination bracket that will be played at BlizzCon proper.</p><p>Hearthstone, too, will hold all of the $1,000,000 World Championship&#39;s group stage matches from Oct. 26-30 during Opening Week. Eight players will take to the stage to play though a single-elimination bracket at the big event.</p><p>For Heroes of the Storm, BlizzCon is the site of the $1,000,000 Fall Global Championship. That event will feature two group stages, and the first — which will narrow the field to eight teams — will take place during Opening Week from Oct. 26-28. Some of the second group stage's matches will also happen during Opening Week, but all of the Top 8 will get the opportunity to play on the stage at BlizzCon.</p><p>StarCraft II will also narrow the field to eight during Opening Week. The $500,000, single-elimination tournament features best-of-five matches and a best-of-seven Grand Final.</p><p>World of Warcraft's eight teams will play some group stage matches on Oct. 28, and then all fly to the venue where they will fight for the $250,000 prize pool.</p><p><em>Josh "<strong>Gauntlet</strong>" Bury dropped the beat, it broke, and it isn't under warranty any more. <a href="http://twitter.com/ThrownGauntlet">You can find him on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">10369</guid>
  <title>Hunting the Unicorn: How pros would purify Priest</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10369</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 18:26:05 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/7560/w1080xh810_Anduin_Wrynn.jpg?ts=1454160223">
    <media:credit>Blizzard / n/a</media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>With the launch of One Night in Karazhan, the real joke wasn’t the Medivas or <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dKY29qji2a8">Lord Jaraxxus’s karaoke skills</a>, but a two mana version of <a href="http://www.hearthpwn.com/cards/544-silence">Silence</a> that only worked on friendly minions and drew you a card.</p><p>The reveal of the new Priest spell, <a href="http://www.hearthpwn.com/cards/42061-purify">Purify</a>, drew so much criticism from the Hearthstone community and figures like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cucw9HNp4KA">Octavian &quot;</a><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cucw9HNp4KA"><strong>Kripp</strong></a><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cucw9HNp4KA">&quot; Morosan</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4FGEMtLkXJI&amp;t=5m34s">Dan &quot;</a><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4FGEMtLkXJI&amp;t=5m34s"><strong>Frodan</strong></a><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4FGEMtLkXJI&amp;t=5m34s">&quot; Chou</a>, that Hearthstone lead designer Ben Brode had to post a special edition of his <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ot7nlHXPLqU">Developer&rsquo;s Insights videos</a> explaining the thought process behind the card.</p><p>"Sometimes we want to allow players to make crazy decks and some players actually like winning with bad cards," Brode said in the video. "If that’s not you that’s fine. We try and make competitive cards to shake up the meta-game, but that’s not the only type of cards that we make."</p><p>Adding a "bad card" to a class that was already languishing at the bottom of the meta, particularly after one of <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/hearthstone/comments/4q10ra/why_are_the_overwatch_devs_so_much_more/d4q0pik?context=3">Brode’s Reddit comments</a> was misconstrued to mean there was a mythical "Unicorn Priest" deck hiding in the ether, was a cruel joke that launched a conversation about the problems Priest’s main archetypes face in the current Standard meta. PC Gamer even <a href="http://www.pcgamer.com/here-are-the-results-of-our-hearthstone-priest-card-design-competition/">ran a highly successful contest</a> asking people to design a card that would “Make Priest Great Again.”</p><p>Priest’s poor performance on ladder has extended to tournament play, with most professional players far too frightened of Anduin’s inconsistent performance to include him in their lineups, despite counter potential.</p><p>&quot;The only reason to play Priest in tournaments is to counter some decks like maybe Shaman and Zoo. I don&#39;t think it is too consistent in the end,&quot; said Tugay &ldquo;<strong>Mryagut</strong>&rdquo; Evsan, progenitor of the <a href="http://www.hearthstonetopdecks.com/decks/mryaguts-season-21-oil-rogue/">Oil Rogue</a> archetype, said. &quot;It has way too many situational cards like Silence, Purify, taunts and board clears.&quot;</p><p>While Priest was once a Tier 1 control deck, many meta shifts have seen it drop steadily throughout most tier lists. Most recently, the introduction of Standard and Whispers of the Old Gods changed the meta dramatically, speeding the game up with a proliferation of aggro strategies and removing old Priest standbys like <a href="http://www.hearthpwn.com/cards/12174-velens-chosen">Velen&rsquo;s Chosen</a>.</p><p>According to Thijs &quot;<strong>Thijs</strong>&quot;<strong> </strong>Molendijk, who came in 3-4th at HWC 2015 with a <a href="http://www.hearthstonetopdecks.com/decks/thijs-blizzcon-2015-dragon-priest/">Dragon Priest</a> deck in his lineup, the class now lacks the tools to combat swarms of early, low-cost minions unleashed by Zoolocks and the like while also being able to set up a board that facilitates its combo plays.</p><p>"Priest has really good anti-aggro tools, but the thing is you have to actually make your deck that way," he said. "Priest has really good anti-aggro cards and has really good anti-control cards, but you have to choose one road." </p><p>Both he and Mryagut agree Priest could use buffs to its early game, particularly in the form of a strong two-drop minion who can hold the line until reinforcements like <a href="http://www.hearthpwn.com/cards/42056-priest-of-the-feast">Priest of the Feast</a> and <a href="http://www.hearthpwn.com/cards/656-auchenai-soulpriest">Auchenai Soul Priest</a> arrive to save the day.</p><p>"I definitely like a two-drop idea, being a two mana 2/3 that makes a minion of your opponent's minus two attack or something," Thijs said. "Like, we had the <a href="http://www.hearthpwn.com/cards/12197-shrinkmeister">Shrinkmeister</a>, but let it be an effect that stays so you just decrease [attack] off your opponent's minion by two and it also gives really nice combinations with <a href="http://www.hearthpwn.com/cards/315-shadow-word-pain">Shadow Word: Pain</a>. You get combinations with even<a href="http://www.hearthpwn.com/cards/147-cabal-shadow-priest"> Cabal Shadow Priest</a> and I think it fits the design of the class."</p><p>Mryagut suggested that adding a 2/2 Discover a Spell, <a href="http://www.hearthpwn.com/cards/27243-dark-peddler">a Light Peddler </a>essentially, could have a strong effect on the class and give it more options to react to early pressure from a variety of opponents.</p><p>The two also say it would be interesting to see Priest’s Hero Power provide more early game value.</p><p>"On board, it's the best Hero Power. Off board, it's the weakest Hero Power. I don't think it's necessarily a big problem, it's just the early turns, like Priest passing Turn 2, Turn 3, it's something that they just totally pass instead of like making a Totem, Armoring Up," Thijs said. "Maybe it's cool that there could be an extra future for them to use their Hero Power a little bit for the early game. Let's say you can go above 30 life, I think that sounds cool, but maybe some use in the early game can make it better." </p><p>"I don't think it is weak. You can just not get any value out of it in the beginning," Mryagut said. "If priest would get better 1 and 2 drops it would actually be pretty strong."</p><p>As much ire as Purify drew in the lead-up to Karazhan, several of the adventure’s new cards have been used by pros like <a href="http://www.hearthstonetopdecks.com/decks/amazs-resurrect-barnes-control-priest-august-2016-season-29/">Jason “<strong>Amaz</strong>” Chan</a> and <a href="http://www.hearthpwn.com/decks/622099-rank-3-firebat-resurrect-priest">James "<strong>Firebat</strong>" Kostesich </a>to create a new archetype: the Resurrect Priest. The basic idea is to use <a href="http://www.hearthpwn.com/cards/14461-resurrect">Resurrect</a> and <a href="http://www.hearthpwn.com/cards/42058-onyx-bishop">Onyx Bishop</a> to get more use out of powerful minions who draw removal. Additionally, it can establish strong board presence early through resurrecting <a href="http://www.hearthpwn.com/cards/209-injured-blademaster">Injured Blade Master</a> without triggering his Battlecry, bringing back a <a href="http://www.hearthpwn.com/cards/42021-barnes">Barnes</a>-summoned minion with full stats and through removal options like Shadow Word: Pain and <a href="http://www.hearthpwn.com/cards/25-wild-pyromancer">Wild Pyromancer</a>.</p><p>A significant issue with the deck is that it is heavily RNG dependent, but when RNGesus smiles upon you and you resurrect a full-stat, Barnes-summoned Legendary on Turn 5 after it was killed, your opponent has few options outside of conceding.</p><p>Thijs is one of the players pioneering <a href="http://www.hearthpwn.com/decks/613079-thijs-new-resurrect-priest">the new archetype</a>, but even he doubts its tournament viability in the current meta.</p><p>&quot;I think the Resurrect Priest has really good potential. I don&#39;t think it&#39;s a Tier 1 deck, but it can become [a Tier 1 deck], in the right control meta,&quot; he said. &quot;I think there&#39;s a lot of potential where you can cut some of the early game, can go a little bit greedier and still having really good ways to deal with single minions. The Resurrect Priest seems to be still really promising to me.&quot;</p><p>As powerful as Resurrect Priest can be under the right conditions, it still exhibits the same weaknesses of traditional Priest decks: reliance on a good opening hand, reliance on setting up combos, and no strong minions to summon in Turns 1 or 2.</p><p>In Tempo Storm’s latest <a href="https://tempostorm.com/hearthstone/meta-snapshot/standard/2016-09-09">meta snapshot</a>, the first since all wings of Karazhan took flight, they rank Resurrect Priest in Tier 3, saying "after the initial rush in trying to make Priest a competitive class, things have settled down and we find Priest to be in tier 3 yet again. Priest lists are still not consistent enough to grant a high-ladder finish, while still being slower than their counterparts."</p><p>According to HCT Spring Americas 2016 winner, Julien “<strong>Cydonia</strong>” Perrault, the class’s real issue isn’t necessarily the lack of two-drops or the conditions of the meta, but that its identity is too tied to a specific play-style.</p><p>&quot;First of all, I don&#39;t really have fun playing Priest because if you manage to get some minions on board early like a 3/6 or a 2/5 or whatever, you can just heal that minion over and over again and you end up with your hand full of cards because you get a card&#39;s worth of value with your Hero Power every turn and just snowball and win. And if you don&#39;t get that, you never get the board and just lose, unless you can get your combo Auchenai Circle or whatever and manage to clear the board,&quot; he said. </p><p>&quot;I just feel Priest has identity and design problems and that it&#39;s boring to play and it&#39;s boring to play against and it&#39;s just better right now that if there&#39;s a class that has to be worst, that it&#39;s Priest because it&#39;s the least interesting class in the game.&quot;</p><p>While other classes have a lot of variety in the configurations they can field, Face Hunter vs. Midrange Hunter, Tempo Mage vs. Freeze Mage, OTK Warrior vs. C&rsquo;Thun Warrior, etc., Priest&rsquo;s strategies all seem to rely on outlasting their opponents. While certainly appropriate for a healing class, the lack of aggro options severely limits its deck building potential. Priest may have its aggressive Shadow cards, inspired by the Shadow Priest talent tree in World of Warcraft, but Cydonia and Mryagut say there isn&rsquo;t yet enough of them for a competitive deck.</p><p>"I feel like the most interesting cards that Priest got lately are cards like <a href="http://www.hearthpwn.com/cards/12278-shadowbomber">Shadowbomber</a> and the <a href="http://www.hearthpwn.com/cards/22357-spawn-of-shadows">Spawn of Shadows</a>, that card is interesting," Cydonia said. "Those are cards I tried to make work, but obviously, like, they're just too weak to work as there's not enough support for it. But maybe some kind of Shadow Priest that's more tempo and more damage-oriented could be interesting in the future if they make more cards to support that, but the Priest as is right now is kind of uninteresting."</p><p>"Yeah I would like to see Aggro Priest," Mryagut said. "It is the only class that can't make an aggro deck right now. Shadowform Priest might also be fun but I would much rather see a Control Priest working first."</p><p>Ultimately, while Karazhan has provided strong new tools to Priest in the form of Priest of the Feast and Onyx Bishop, the Unicorn still remains out of reach. While there is still hope for Resurrect Priest and even Silence Priest going forward, at the moment they’re little more than pale nags with cones tied to their heads. Even the faithful must wonder, does the Unicorn Priest even exist?</p><p>&quot;I would love to say yes, but I just can&#39;t see it,&quot; Thijs said, laughing. &quot;So, at the moment no, Ben Brode, you really have to prove yourself first to get my belief in it.&quot;</p><p><em>Sasha Erfanian is an Injured Kvaldir for theScore esports. <a href="http://twitter.com/sashaerfanian">Follow him on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">10359</guid>
  <title>PGL Bucharest Tavern Tales to feature $25,000 prize pool, Thijs, Xixo in attendance</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10359</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 17:53:16 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11990/w1080xh810_gaara.jpg?ts=1473787886">
    <media:credit>PGL </media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>DreamHack Buacharest will host the latest PGL Tavern Tales tournament, with a $25,000 prize pool and a closed 16-player bracket. </p><p>In addition to the 14 invited players, Vlad<strong> &quot;Angeloshaggy&quot;</strong> Dumitru and Cosmin<strong> &quot;Drujbanul&quot;</strong> Panfil qualified for the tournament through an open bracket. </p><p>The invited players are: </p><ul><li>Radu &quot;<strong>Rdu&quot;</strong> Dima </li><li>Frederik &quot;<strong>Hoej</strong>&quot; Nielsen </li><li>Sebastian &quot;<strong>Xixo</strong>&quot; Bentert </li><li>Jan &quot;<strong>Ek0p</strong>&quot; Palys </li><li>Petar &quot;<strong>Gaara</strong>&quot; Stevanovic </li><li>Simon &ldquo;<strong>Crane</strong>&rdquo; Raunholst</li><li>Nicklas &quot;<strong>Tessin</strong>&quot; Dittmer </li><li>Stanislav &quot;<strong>StanCifka</strong>&quot; Cifka </li><li>Adrian &quot;<strong>Lifecoach</strong>&quot; Koy </li><li>Thijs &quot;<strong>Thijs</strong>&quot; Molendijk </li><li>Esteban&quot;<strong>AKAWonder</strong>&quot; Serrano </li><li>Jan &quot;<strong>SuperJJ</strong>&quot; Jan&szlig;en</li><li>Jon &quot;<strong>Orange</strong>&quot; Westberg</li><li>Aleksandr &quot;<strong>Kolento</strong>&quot; Malsh</li></ul><div><span style="font-size:18px; line-height:27px">The players will be separated into two groups, with four players advancing to a double-elimination playoffs bracket from each group. </span></div><p><span style="font-size:18px; line-height:27px"><span style="font-size:18px; line-height:27px"><span style="font-size:18px; line-height:27px"><span style="font-size:18px; line-height:27px"><span style="font-size:18px; line-height:27px"><span style="font-size:18px; line-height:27px">PGL Bucharest Tavern Tales runs from Sept. 16-18.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p><p><em><span style="font-size:18px; line-height:27px"><span style="font-size:18px; line-height:27px"><span style="font-size:18px; line-height:27px"><span style="font-size:18px; line-height:27px"><span style="font-size:18px; line-height:27px"><span style="font-size:18px; line-height:27px">Daniel Rosen is a news editor for theScore esports. He loves him some RNG. <a href="http://twitter.com/daniel_rosen">You can follow him on Twitter.</a></span></span></span></span></span></span></em></p><div> </div><div> </div><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">10288</guid>
  <title>ESL partner with AEG</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10288</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 18:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/10768/w1080xh810_20160708_Helena-Kristiansson_ESLOneCNG_4337__1_.jpg?ts=1468022369">
    <media:credit>Helena Kristiansson / ESL</media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>ESL has announced a new partnership with AEG, a sports and entertainment presentation company with a network which includes stadiums and other sports and entertainment venues around the world.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">ESL and <a href="https://twitter.com/AEGworldwide">@AEGworldwide</a> partner up long-term to bring esports to more iconic venues worldwide! <a href="https://t.co/zg5xwTkgE0">https://t.co/zg5xwTkgE0</a> <a href="https://t.co/LXYnXMY6iy">pic.twitter.com/LXYnXMY6iy</a></p>— ESL (@ESL) <a href="https://twitter.com/ESL/status/773880333288763393">September 8, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>Among the venues in AEG&#39;s network are the Barclay&#39;s Center in Brooklyn, New York, the O2 in London. It also includes stadiums familiar to esports fans like The Mercedes Benz Arenas in Berlin and Shanghai (which hosted the 2015 League of Legends World Championship finals and The Shanghai Major in early 2016 respectively) and Key Arena in Seattle, home to The International for the past three years.</p><p>In ESL&#39;s announcement, Bob Newman, the president of AEG Facilities, promises fans &quot;new events that will unite the community and celebrate players, teams and leagues.&quot;</p><p><em>Annabelle "<strong>Abelle</strong>" Fischer is a writer for theScore esports with a love for Dota 2, birds and cheese. <a href="https://twitter.com/Abelle/">You can follow her on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">10276</guid>
  <title>Amaz says Archon will wind down, Amnesiac is open to offers from other teams</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10276</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:33:27 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/7619/w1080xh810_ArchonHeader.jpg?ts=1454522984">
    <media:credit>theScore eSports / Team Archon / Blizzard Entertainment</media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>Jason &quot;<strong>Amaz</strong>&quot; Chan says that now that he has been <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/10255" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10255">signed by NRG eSports</a>, Team Archon plans to shut down operations, and is helping its star Hearthstone player William &quot;<strong>Amnesiac</strong>&quot; Barton field offers from other sponsors.</p><p><a href="https://www.twitch.tv/amazhs/v/88062263">On-stream on Wednesday</a>, the Team Archon founder answered fan&#39;s questions about what would happen to the team in the wake his decision to join NRG. Amaz said that Archon is winding down and that Amnesiac, the only player still signed to the team, is looking for a new organization.</p><p>&quot;Basically we are slowly just stopping Archon for a bit,&quot; Amaz said. &quot;If anyone wants Amnesiac to be on a Hearthstone team they should contact Amnesiac, they should contact me, and we can sort something out basically. And I think you&#39;d want Amnesiac because he is awesome, he is really really good, that&#39;s why I picked him in the first place.&quot;</p><p>Amaz said Archon was not making money on its investments and that he had been personally bankrolling the team. He claimed that Archon struggled to maintain its sponsorship revenue when Kinguin stopped sponsoring Hearthstone players and events, and its main competitor, G2A, no longer felt it needed to invest as heavily to compete for airtime.</p><p>Amaz nonetheless defended G2A as a sponsor. &quot;Without G2A we wouldn&#39;t have so many Hearthstone tournaments,&quot; he said. &quot;Every time I see someone like, &#39;G2A sucks so bad,&#39; and whatnot &mdash; well if it wasn&#39;t for them, Hearthstone wouldn&#39;t be where it is right now. All the big streamers are sponsored by G2A too, like Kripp, Trump, and all those guys. Without G2A, the Hearthstone scene would be much slower. Obviously it wasn&#39;t very good that they lowered everybody&#39;s money but we just kinda have to deal with that.&quot;</p><p>NRG chairman Andy Miller told theScore esports Tuesday that Amaz is signed to the organization as both a streamer and competitive Hearthstone player, but Amaz said on stream that he&#39;s mostly looking to stream and produce tournaments, rather than compete. </p><p>&quot;Overall, why I decided to join NRG was because I wanted to focus on doing the things I like, and the things I like are tournament production and streaming,&quot; he said. </p><p>&quot;Even when I made Team Archon, I always focused on that, because that&#39;s what I&#39;m good at. I&#39;m good at organizing tournaments. ... I joined NRG because one of the owners, Andy, really supported the idea of me just making stuff. That&#39;s kinda what happened, it kinda clicked.&quot;</p><p><em>Daniel Rosen is a news editor for theScore esports. <a href="http://twitter.com/daniel_rosen">You can follow him on Twitter.</a></em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">10266</guid>
  <title>Na`Vi dissolve Hearthstone division</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10266</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 14:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/7394/w1080xh810_naviheadergeneric.jpg?ts=1453465408">
    <media:credit>theScore eSports / Natus Vincere</media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>Natus Vincere have elected to suspend their Hearthstone operations and have released Sebastian "<strong>Xixo</strong>" Bentert, Sebastian "<strong>Ostkaka</strong>" Engwall, Frederik "<strong>Hoej</strong>" Nielsen, and Jung Soo "<strong>Surrender</strong>" Kim from their lineup, according to <a href="http://read.navi-gaming.com/en/team_news/hs_team_parted_ways">a press release</a>.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I blame yogg Kappa, had a great year with <a href="https://twitter.com/natusvincere">@natusvincere</a> tho, no regrets.</p>— Sebastian Bentert (@NaViXiXo) <a href="https://twitter.com/NaViXiXo/status/773510868088815617">September 7, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>&quot;It is sad to inform that we&#39;ve decided not to prolong the contracts with our Hearthstone team,&quot; Na`Vi eSports director Eugene &quot;<strong>HarisPilton</strong>&quot; Zolotarev said in a statement. &quot;However, we want to focus our resources and efforts on the top disciplines, basing on the region, where our main fan base is located. Nevertheless, it was very pleasant to work with the guys. We can surely say that the year of our presence in the discipline was successful.&quot;</p><p>According to Zolotarev, the players will stay on until the end of September and the organization will help find them new teams.</p><p>Na`Vi entered Hearthstone last September with the signings of Xixo, Hoej, and Ostkaka. The investment quickly paid off when <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/4722" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/4722">Ostkaka won HCT 2015</a> handily with a 3-0 victory over Dylan &quot;<strong>Hotform</strong>&quot; Mullins at Blizzcon.</p><p><strong>RELATED: <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/3965" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/3965">Na`Vi opens Hearthstone division, signs Xixo, Ostkaka, Hoej</a></strong></p><p>The rest of the roster didn't do too badly in the year they had with the team either, with Hoej coming in 3-4th at both Dreamhack Winter 2015 and Dreamhack Summer 2016 while <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/8993" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/8993">Xixo won Season 2</a> of StarLadder i-League StarSeries. </p><p>Surrender rounded out the roster in January 2016. He represented the team at OGN Hearthstone Seoul Cup World Invitational in May where he came in 3-4th. </p><p>&quot;Though I&#39;ve worked only for 5 months with the guys, I feel like they&#39;re my family,&quot; said Na`Vi&#39;s Hearthstone manager, Andrew &quot;<strong>kimi</strong>&quot; Kvasnievsky in a statement. &quot;First of all, on behalf of the organization and myself I&#39;d like to express gratitude to the players for always presenting Na`Vi at the highest level, for always being professionals regardless the matter. Unfortunately, we are forced not to continue our cooperation. But who knows? We might work together in future! Go, guys! You are born to win!&quot;</p><p><em>Sasha Erfanian is a news editor for theScore esports. <a href="https://twitter.com/SashaErfanian">Follow him on Twitter</a>, it'll be great for his self-esteem.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">10255</guid>
  <title>NRG sign Amaz, future of Team Archon uncertain</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10255</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 19:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/6393/w1080xh810_NRG1.jpg?ts=1447710325">
    <media:credit>NRG eSports</media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>NRG eSports have entered Hearthstone by signing one of the scene&#39;s most popular personalities, Jason &quot;<strong>Amaz</strong>&quot; Chan.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Mind if we roll need? <a href="https://twitter.com/Amaz">@Amaz</a> has joined the NRG family! Catch him live on <a href="https://t.co/Kzu6xdRhuL">https://t.co/Kzu6xdRhuL</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WelcomeAmaz?src=hash">#WelcomeAmaz</a> <a href="https://t.co/oFBdKc1Fu9">pic.twitter.com/oFBdKc1Fu9</a></p>— NRG eSports (@NRGgg) <a href="https://twitter.com/NRGgg/status/773227222329069568">September 6, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>&quot;After talking to Andy Miller (co-owner of NRG), I found out that we have a lot in common,&quot; Amaz stated in a press release. &quot;He expressed interest in the projects I&#39;m pursuing in Hearthstone, and it&#39;s always nice to have someone who can relate. NRG has been accomplishing a lot in the eSports scene, and I always loved supporting passionate teams in this community &mdash; that&#39;s why I love hosting Hearthstone tournaments so much.&quot;</p><p>In addition to being a popular streamer, Amaz has competed in Hearthstone tournaments in the past, and was a co-founder of Team Archon. Amaz has previously played for ROOT Gaming and Team Liquid, though he hasn&#39;t competed in a tournament since December 2015, when he placed in the Top 6 of the SL i-League StarSeries Qualifier with a 3-1 record in the Group Stage. Amaz later dropped out of the tournament, with<a href="https://twitter.com/hsstarladder/status/689538432025137152?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"> StarLadder stating on Twitter </a>that he &quot;refused&quot; to attend the tournament.</p><p>"He is such a big, fun personality that we thought he would fit in great with the NRG vibe," NRG chairman Andy Miller told theScore esports. Miller also said that Amaz was signed as both a streamer and competitor. </p><p>The future of Team Archon is currently unclear. Over the past few months, the team has lost most of its pro players, with only William &quot;<strong>Amnesiac</strong>&quot; Barton still signed to the team. On-stream, Amaz said that there is an announcement coming about the future of Archon, and that he is &quot;not supposed to say anything yet.&quot;</p><p><em>Daniel Rosen is a news editor for theScore esports. <a href="http://twitter.com/daniel_rosen">You can follow him on Twitter.</a></em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">10236</guid>
  <title>Fr0zen wins ONOG 2016 Finals</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10236</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 00:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/6372/w1080xh810_LuminositySplash_copy.jpg?ts=1447545850">
    <media:credit>Luminosity Gaming</media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>Frank "<strong>Fr0zen</strong>" Zhang has won the One Nation Of Gamers 2016 Circuit Finals with a 4-4 win over his Luminosity Gaming teammate Keaton "<strong>Chakki</strong>" Gill .</p><p>In the Grand Finals, Chakki took Fr0zen to 4-0, but Fr0zen brought it back, taking wins with his own Rogue, Token Druid, Midrange Hunter and Tempo Mage. Chakki and Fr0zen faced off in a Dragon Warrior mirror match for the last round, where Chakki played out his Deathwing while Fr0zen had an Execute in his hand and enough cards to repopulate the board.</p><p>Chakki played Dragon Warrior, Questing Rogue, Aggro Shaman, Tempo Mage and Malygos Druid on his way to the grand finals beating David &quot;<strong>Shoop</strong>&quot; Steinberg 4-1 in the winners&#39; semifinals, before he lost 4-3 to Fr0zen in the winners&#39; finals.</p><p>Fr0zen will be taking home $10,000 for the win, while Chakki will win $5,000. </p><p><em>Daniel Rosen is a news editor for theScore esports. <a href="http://twitter.com/daniel_rosen">You can follow him on Twitter.</a></em></p><p> </p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">10174</guid>
  <title>ikealyou's visa rejected, may not attend European Summer Championship</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10174</link>
  <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 17:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11445/w1080xh810_Whispers_of_the_Old_Gods_Key_Art.jpg?ts=1471373245">
    <media:credit>Blizzard Entertainment</media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>After making the Top 8 at the HCT Summer Preliminaries, Polish player Bartłomiej "<strong>ikealyou</strong>" Zawadzki says he may not be able to attend the 2016 HCT European Summer Championships after his US visa was rejected.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">My visa application got rejected i guess my dream just got crushed <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HCT?src=hash">#HCT</a></p>— Bartłomiej Zawadzki (@ikealyou) <a href="https://twitter.com/ikealyou/status/771603872993251328">September 2, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>When his Facebook post about the situation was posted<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/hearthstone/comments/50s55w/ikealyou_polish_player_wont_be_able_to_compete_in/"> on Reddit</a>, ikealyou <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/hearthstone/comments/50s55w/ikealyou_polish_player_wont_be_able_to_compete_in/d76l3en?context=3">went on /r/hearthstone</a> to say that Blizzard and his team, Illuminar Honor Gaming, are working on an appeal.</p><p>"Let's hope everything goes right and i'll be able to compete in USA at EU Championship (everyone laughs at me when i say that :D). I have 3 weeks which is very little time but it might still happen," ikealyou wrote. "Overall i was crushed when i first walked out from the embassy but atm i am doing everything i can to ensure that i'll be able to participate despite these obstacles and i have a lot of help from Blizzard, Illuminar Honor Gaming and my family." </p><p>While ikealyou was defeated 3-1 by DrHippi in the Round of 16 at the preliminaries, he was able to make it through to the Top 8 through the Loser&#39;s Bracket.</p><p><em>Sasha Erfanian is a news editor for theScore esports. <a href="https://twitter.com/SashaErfanian">Follow him on Twitter</a>, it'll be great for his self-esteem.</em></p><p> </p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">10168</guid>
  <title>Chakki weighs in on Karazhan deckbuilding, the strengths of Questing Rogue and how to break a new meta</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10168</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 19:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/9583/w1080xh810_20160312_Carlton-Beener_ESL_Hearthstone_AmericasWinterChampionship_0160.jpg?ts=1462913404">
    <media:credit>Carlton Breener  / Blizzard Entertainment</media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>In the weeks since One Night in Karazhan’s release Keaton “<strong>Chakki</strong>” Gill has resisted conventional deck choices in favor of a skill-intensive Rogue deck and a new teched-out Hunter build. All to find a competitive edge, as new expansions put a lot of pressure on innovative deck building.</p><p>For Chakki One Night in Karazhan, meant balancing risk and reward, breaking Barnes and a resurgence of the Hunter class as he prepared for the HCT Americas Preliminaries and the Insomnia Truesilver Championship.</p><p>Chakki says that the first question he asks himself when a new set comes out is, “did anything that was already good get better?” and then he moves on from there. In the case of Karazhan he said that his first step was with Arcane Giant in Druid. He then looks to decipher which weaker decks, might have a chance to make a splash in tournament play with new additions.</p><p>“Going into Karazhan, Beast Druid and Tempo Mage weren't really top tier, but Menagerie Warden and Firelands Portal might change that,” Chakki said. “In general, a new card has to be really, really powerful for me to take it to a tournament after a few days of testing versus another deck that I've tested for months and know works well. As an example, at Truesilver I didn't run Barnes in my Rogue. After thinking about it, it's probably going to end up being good, but I didn't have time to make sure of that.”</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><a href="http://i.imgur.com/k3K4Mde.png"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/k3K4Mde.png"></a></figure><p>From a deck building perspective, Chakki said staggering the wings of a new adventure can be a hindrance to competitive play, though he recognizes that it can be more fun for casual players</p><p>“Staggering the wings has a negative effect on competitive Hearthstone overall. As a player, you don't really have any time to play with the cards between tournaments; and as a viewer, you might not care to watch a tournament knowing the entire meta will shift the next week,” Chakki said. “Ideally, at least the official HCT preliminaries would have happened after the entire release.”</p><p>Chakki has been part of a small group of pro players who’ve decided to ban Shaman and play more unconventional classes and archetypes rather than the standard Druid, Shaman, Zoo and Warrior makeup. At Truesilver Champs he brought Hunter, Druid, Shaman and Questing Rogue — a deck that he has been playing a lot of since Karazhan came out. He was one of the only players in the elimination rounds at Truesilver sporting a Valeera in his classes.</p><p>“Rogue's resurgence is kind of interesting, because it didn't really gain anything, it just sort of gained from other decks falling out of the meta. When Standard first came out, Rogue was super popular and players moved to counter it,” Chakki said. “Since the metagame has moved towards classes like Druid and Warrior, Rogue can have a place in a lineup banning Shaman. Specifically in LHS, Rogue has made the finals of almost every Standard tournament, only missing at Dreamhack Valencia.”</p><p>He’s been playing the Questing Adventurer version instead of the traditional Violet Teachers. This, Chakki, says is just the correct way to build the deck and has given him a strong advantage in being able to play more aggressively.</p><p>“Simply put, the Questing list is just better than Teachers,” he said. “It gives you a very strong alternative win condition and is massively powerful against any class that easily beat the Teacher tokens before. VanCleef used to be a reason you would outright win some games, and now the deck essentially runs three copies.”</p><p>Chakki feels as though part of his success being one of the only top players playing Rogue is that he plays his Rogue a little differently, favoring a more aggressive play pattern. He even said that Gadgetzan Auctioneer — often looked at as the deck’s key threat — is not as strong as it once was.</p><p>“I think realistically Auctioneer could be cut if the deck could find anything better to fit in,” he said.</p><p>In addition to the Rogue at Truesilver, Chakki was one of the only players sporting a Hunter deck, another class that benefits greatly from banning Shaman. An interesting characteristic of his Hunter, was the lengths he went to ensure that his Barnes hits were as good as possible. Most players building these Hunter decks have been playing a Standard midrange build and making their Barnes have about a 50 per cent chance of hitting something good. Chakki’s list looks to optimize the new legend. He also went with a more midrange version, rather than the Cloaked Huntress secret-heavy version many players like.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><a href="http://i.imgur.com/r5KDkD1.png"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/r5KDkD1.png"></a></figure><p>“I think Barnes is a card where he's powerful enough if you hit it X percent of the time. We're really not sure what that X is yet, but it doesn't have to be 100 percent for it to be powerful,” Chakki said. “I never really thought of Cloaked Huntress as a good card and still don't. It's slightly better than Kirin Tor Mage, a card that Mage never plays, but Hunter secrets are very lacking outside of Freezing Trap. I don't think the new Hunter trap will really change that.”</p><p>Looking back at the event, Chakki was happy with his decks and result. He thought his Hunter filled some his lineup’s weaknesses and fit well with his ban strategy and was positive about the rest of his choices. He did add that he’d look to try Barnes in his Rogue as well going forward.</p><p>“Besides maybe a card or two I wouldn't have changed anything. At the end of the day, my lineup just failed in a single best-of-five where I got the bad end of the opening matchup and then lost a favorable matchup after,” he said. “Not much to be said about that and I feel like the lineup was pretty powerful and capable of beating the other players that went far in the tournament.”</p><p><em>Keith Capstick is a Toronto journalist and card game elitist. He&#39;s also interested in harsh music, root beer and casting the magic card Dark Confidant. You can <a href="https://twitter.com/KeithCapstick">follow him on Twitter </a>for a below 50 per cent hit-rate when attempting to utilize &quot;wit.&quot;</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">10158</guid>
  <title>Collegiate Colosseum to hold $100,000 multi-game collegiate esports tournament</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10158</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 21:33:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11685/w1080xh810_icon_2.jpg?ts=1472676105">
    <media:credit>Collegiate Colosseum</media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>Collegiate Colosseum has announced a multi-game esports event for North American university and college students, which will offer $100,000 in scholarships and prizes spread across competitions in Overwatch, League of Legends, Super Smash Bros. for Wii U, Super Smash Bros. Melee and Hearthstone.</p><p>The event promises to pit 100 university and college esports teams against one another, and expects as many as 2,000 participants in Las Vegas on Dec. 19-21. It&#39;s billed as a first-of-its-kind event, and the largest collegiate-level tournament in NA this year.</p><p>&quot;CCNA&rsquo;s vision is to introduce a competitive environment at the collegiate level, while helping students pay for tuition and bridging the gap to the professional leagues,&quot; event director Kitty Nguyen said in a press release.</p><p>The organization&#39;s first esports event was held earlier this year in Orange County, with 15 schools participating in tournaments for Heroes of the Storm, Counter-Strike: Global Offensive, Street Fighter V, Smash 4 and LoL. Tournament organizers said they have seen enough interest from university and college teams to take their next event national. </p><p>In addition to offering prizes and scholarships for competitors, CCNA said it plans to match each prize with an equal-value contribution to the school each winner represents.</p><p>Registration for Collegiate Colosseum is open from Aug. 31 to Sept. 22, and online qualifiers will be held between Sept. 23 and Dec. 2.</p><p><em>Daniel Rosen is a news editor for theScore esports. <a href="http://twitter.com/daniel_rosen">You can follow him on Twitter.</a></em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">10146</guid>
  <title>AKAWonder, Xixo, Crane333 to compete at Deck Gauntlet 3</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10146</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 15:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/167/w1080xh810_Anduin_Wrynn.jpg?ts=1423031662">
    <media:credit>Blizzard PR / Blizzard</media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>Esteban &quot;<strong>AKAWonder</strong>&quot; Serrano, Sebastian &quot;<strong>Xixo</strong>&quot; Bentert and Simon &quot;<strong>Crane333</strong>&quot; Raunholst are among the 14 players set to compete at Deck Gauntlet 3 next week.</p><p>Set to run from Sept. 5-9, players from Natus Vincere, compLexity Gaming, SK Gaming, Virtus.pro and ANOX will compete for a $5,000 prize pool in the online tournament, which will be streamed on Stream.Me.</p><p>The full list of players competing in Deck Master 3 are as follows:</p><ul><li>Na`Vi - Sebastian "<strong>Xixo</strong>" Bentert, Frederik "<strong>Hoej</strong>" Nielsen</li><li>compLexity - Tugay "<strong>MrYagut</strong>" Evsan, Simon "<strong>Crane333</strong>" Raunholst, Jan "<strong>SuperJJ</strong>" Janßen</li><li>SK Gaming - Harald "<strong>Powder</strong>" Gimre, Esteban "<strong>AKAWonder</strong>" Serrano, Sebastian "<strong>Spo</strong>" Sjöbec</li><li>Virtus.pro - Raphael <strong>"BunnyHoppor"</strong> Peltzer, Artem "<strong>DrHippi</strong>" Kravets, Artem "<strong>Carry</strong>" Ruslanovich</li><li>ANOX - <strong>NickChipper</strong>, Aleksey "<strong>ShtanUdachi</strong>" Barsukov, <strong>Pawel</strong></li></ul><p><em>Preston Dozsa is a news editor for theScore esports. <a href="https://twitter.com/prestondozsa?lang=en">You can follow him on Twitter.</a></em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">10116</guid>
  <title>Barnes, Maelstrom Portal and Arcane Giant: Innovation at the Insomnia Truesilver Championship</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10116</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 20:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11651/w1080xh810_Crowpal.jpg?ts=1472500823">
    <media:credit>Blizzard / theScore esports</media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>This past weekend at the third Insomnia Truesilver Championship we finally got see the One Night in Karazhan’s coming out party in competitive Hearthstone.</p><p>Jan “<strong>Ekop</strong>” Palys ended up coming out on top over Sebastian “<strong>Xixo</strong>” Bentert — who seemingly can’t miss the elimination rounds of a tournament — in what was a star-studded Top 16 including both Hearthstone world champions and both of the previous two Truesilver champions.</p><p>Though Ekop played more or less standard decks in his sucessful run at the tournament, over the course of the last two weeks at the HCT Preliminaries around the world we saw players dip into the Karazhan card pool and add new cards to some existing decks. This weekend &mdash; despite only the first two wings being available for deck building &mdash; the world&rsquo;s best players showed us their prowess making big alterations to some of the game&rsquo;s best classes.</p><p>Ekop did end up bringing a fairly stock class lineup in Zoo, Aggro Shaman, Yogg Druid and C’Thun Warrior however. While his finals opponent Xixo brought a little more spice with Zoo, Rogue, Anyfin Paladin and Yogg Druid.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Here are the lists i used to win <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/i58?src=hash">#i58</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Truesilver?src=hash">#Truesilver</a> Championship. &quot;old but gold&quot; <a href="https://t.co/nlAepmrOeW">pic.twitter.com/nlAepmrOeW</a></p>&mdash; Ekop (@Ekop) <a href="https://twitter.com/Ekop/status/770272693782450176">August 29, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><h3><strong>Yogg Druid Reigns King </strong></h3><p>Of all of the non-aggro archetypes that saw a good amount of play at the event Yogg Druid of all shapes and sizes was by far the most dominant. Players vary in the way they build this deck, with some opting for more controlling versions while others like Sebastian “<strong>Ostaka</strong>” Engwall opted for more top-end minions like Y’Shaarj, Rage Unbound. Xixo even played a Gadgetzan Auctioneer variant with Malygos and Moonfire at the top of the curve for a combo-esque finish.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Sure, I had 3 other decks too, but no one cares about the other decks.<br>This was the druid I played at insomnia. <a href="https://t.co/PnbFqz33NR">pic.twitter.com/PnbFqz33NR</a></p>&mdash; Sebastian Bentert (@NaViXiXo) <a href="https://twitter.com/NaViXiXo/status/770342177977294848">August 29, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>All these variations aside, they all featured the conventional Druid ramp package of Wild Growth and Innervate with Arcane Giants and Yogg-Saron, Hope’s End as the few unified finishers among all the different versions. What was interesting was the ways these players played their unique versions. The deck operates in a way where it presents impressive threat after impressive threat looking to just run the opponent out of resources.</p><p>The all-in ramp version looks to be paired against the non-aggressive classes and dominate the mirror, while the conventional version with more removal looks to play as consistent as possible, while the Malygos version has the potential for late-game explosiveness even after your opponent casts their Yogg.</p><p>Week in and week out players will now be pressed with the decision of what Druid mash-up they should play. With its success this weekend and the relative uncertainty of the list, we could see Druid become banned much more than we’ve seen in recent weeks.</p><h3><strong>Maelstrom Portal is an Auto-Include</strong></h3><p>As if Aggro Shaman needed more.</p><p>Seemingly every player was featuring two copies of this new card in their Shaman lists as a way to counteract one of their worst matchups in Zoo while also being just a strong card in general. Turns out it’s not actually that difficult to find value in an extra one damage to your opponent's board in matchups where Forbidden Rituals aren’t flying around but the key here is the Zoo of course.</p><p>It’s hard to overstate how much this one new card alters the way players pick their decks in sequence and decide their bans going into tournaments. For a long time players could play Zoo as their Warlock class in order to avoid the Aggro Shaman sweep in Last Hero Standing, which then allowed them to ban Warrior. What we saw this weekend was more and more players leaving Warrior open and banning Shaman in fear of not being able to pick up a win against the aggressive menace.</p><p>This change showed its true impact in the Grand Final where Xixo picked his Aggro Shaman right into Ekop’s Zoo. Feeling favoured enough in the matchup overall and looking to pick up a huge win that redefined the matchups for the rest of the series.</p><h3><strong>Building with Barnes</strong></h3><p>Likely the most popular neutral card from Karazhan across all classes was Barnes. The new legendary was a staple of Hunter, Druid and Paladin decks all weekend but was generally underwhelming. The floor on Barnes is very high, in that 4/5 worth of stats for four mana is just generally good, with the upside of it sometimes being insane when you hit a Ragnaros. </p><p>What Barnes decks showed this weekend was that the card is likely good enough to go even deeper into your deckbuilding arsenal for. Keaton &ldquo;<strong>Chakki</strong>&rdquo; Gill brought a Hunter list with what looked like almost zero &ldquo;misses&rdquo; for Barnes. This was also a feature of Ostaka&rsquo;s Ramp Druid which was designed to make Barnes just about as broken as possible. Both decks looked to be good examples of pushing the envelope to enhance the power level of Barnes and get yourself some &ldquo;free wins.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s likely we see these kinds of builds, in particular Chakki&rsquo;s Hunter, going forward as players keep looking to push Karazhan cards to their limits.</p><p><em>Keith Capstick is a Toronto journalist and card game elitist. He&#39;s also interested in harsh music, root beer and casting the magic card Dark Confidant. You can <a href="https://twitter.com/KeithCapstick">follow him on Twitter </a>for a below 50 per cent hit-rate when attempting to utilize &quot;wit.&quot;</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">10037</guid>
  <title>Mryagut joins compLexity</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10037</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 12:43:58 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/9713/w1080xh810_coLHeader.jpg?ts=1463408197">
    <media:credit>theScore esports / compLexity Gaming</media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>compLexity have signed iconoclastic German meta-breaker Tugay &ldquo;<strong>Mryagut</strong>&rdquo; Evsan. While he&#39;s mostly focused on streaming since getting knocked out of the European Qualifiers of HCT 2014, Mryagut is one of the most innovative deck makers in game, having pioneered Bubble Rogue, Midrange Hunter and Oil Rogue, a variant of which Firebat used in Kinguin Pro League Season 1.</p><p>"I am excited and happy that I finally joined team compLexity Gaming and will compete in more tournaments," Mryagut said in a statement.</p><p>He will represent compLexity at Insomnia58, a $30,000 LAN tournament in Birmingham, alongside Jan "<strong>superJJ</strong>" Janßen and Simon "<strong>crane</strong>" Raunholst.</p><p>"I am personally very happy to finally have gotten the ‘yes’ from Mryagut," said compLexity Gaming manager Sören "<strong>Fantasy</strong>" Vendsahm in a statement. "We’ve been in pursuit for his talent for a long time and to have him represent the brand at a major LAN event right away feels very special. Can’t wait to see him in red and black!"</p><p><em>Sasha Erfanian is a news editor for theScore esports. <a href="https://twitter.com/SashaErfanian">Follow him on Twitter</a>, it'll be great for his self-esteem.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">9995</guid>
  <title>HCT NA Summer Preliminaries: Karazhan creeps into the meta</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9995</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 22:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11559/w1080xh810_HOTMEOWTH.jpg?ts=1471988158">
    <media:credit>Twitch</media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>The Americas Summer Championship Top 8 was decided this past weekend at the HCT Summer Prelims, in what was our first look at what One Night in Karazhan cards add to competitive Hearthstone. Despite Aggro Shaman and ZooLock lists continuing to dominate, the Top 8 was sprinkled with some new cards, and we saw a resurgence of one of the game’s premier late-game strategies — Freeze Mage.</p><p><strong>Abar, </strong>Manny “<strong>Dude7597</strong>” Eckert,<strong> </strong>Edwin “<strong>HOTMeowth</strong>” Cook, Mark<strong> </strong>“<strong>Monsanto</strong>” Ormandy,<strong> Pasco, Rooftrellen, </strong>Jeffery “<strong>Tarei</strong>” Liu<strong> </strong>and<strong> Topoablo11 </strong>all cemented their spots at the Summer Championship Sunday in the elimination rounds of the grueling double-elimination, Conquest-format event.</p><p>Despite only the first wing of Karazhan being legal for play at the event, the game’s newest expansion certainly left its mark. Ivory Knight was in all three of the Paladin decks in Top 8, an impressive showing for a class that has been underrepresented in recent tournament play. The finalists' decklists also featured a few copies of Cloaked Huntress to round out the new cards that performed well on the weekend.</p><p>Despite the fresh Karazhan cards, there was a high number of grindy Freeze Mage decks being played over the weekend. As an archetype that according to top players has strong matchups against some of the format's top decks — Zoo in particular — it hasn’t seen a lot of tournament action lately, but the NA Prelims bucked the trend.</p><h3><strong>Why Now? Why Freeze Mage?</strong></h3><p>Freeze Mage has an interesting relationship with tournament play. More than any other deck in the game, it benefits from knowing exactly the metagame it’s going to be competing against. When you’re seeing your entire deck every game, the amount of Flamestrikes, Blizzards or extra card draw in a list can mean the difference between winning and losing. This weekend felt like a coming out party for the high-level Freeze Mage players who took the time to tune their decks against the Dragon Warrior, ZooLock and Aggro Shaman field.</p><p>Zoo was of course a highly represented deck this weekend, and it has perennially been a nigh-unloseable matchup for Freeze Mage. And despite Ragnaros, The Firelord being one of Hearthstone’s most frequently played legends, he has seen less play lately. Of the big four archetypes, Rag only shows up in stock Dragon Warrior decks. This is huge for Freeze Mage, as the card’s resistance to Freeze effects has made it one of the best cards against Freeze Mage for a long time.</p><h3><strong>Ivory Knight in Murloc Paladin </strong></h3><p>Is a six-mana 4/4 good enough? Apparently it is. Although this card was an oversight during spoiler season, it has certainly made a splash in competitive Hearthstone. Despite its weak base stats, the combination of mid-game heal and board presence benefits all of the controlling variations of Paladin decks, unlike Lay on Hands and Forbidden Healing.</p><p>The thing that pushes the card over the top in the Murloc Paladin Archetype is its ability to fetch a third and fourth copy of Anyfin Can Happen. A lot of the control matchups with this deck involve counting win conditions versus sweepers. So, for example against C&rsquo;Thun Warrior, the Paladin deck wants to play its last Anyfin after both Brawls have been played. Ivory Knight gives you a chance at extra copies of your win condition, while not having to play them in the actual decklist. It lets players get their greedy late game, while not losing points against aggressive decks by shoehorning more win conditions into their list.</p><h3><strong>The Future of the One-Turn-Kill</strong></h3><p>OTK Warrior had a big weekend at the top of the standings, and despite Warrior being close to an auto-ban at the event, it looked good when it got its chance to play. Unlike a lot of archetypes, OTK Warrior<span style="line-height:1.5em"> looks like it will be just as strong even when all of Karazhan is released. </span></p><p><span style="line-height:1.5em">The addition of Arcane Giant to these strategies is something pro players have been streaming a lot, and it's been the buzz of the community. Raging Worgen, seen by many as a "bad card" that was necessary for the combo, can now be replaced with an objectively powerful Giant, which makes for a scary deck. Expect to see more OTK action once Karazhan’s second wing becomes tournament-legal.</span></p><p><em>Keith Capstick is a Toronto journalist and card game elitist. He's also interested in harsh music, root beer and casting the magic card Dark Confidant. You can <a href="https://twitter.com/KeithCapstick">follow him on Twitter </a>for a below 50 per cent hit-rate when attempting to utilize "wit."</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">9986</guid>
  <title>DreamHack Bucharest to host PGL Tavern Tales</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9986</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 16:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/1656/w1080xh810_dhbucharest.jpg?ts=1429789185">
    <media:credit>Pyrax (CC BY-SA 3.0 ro) / Wikimedia Commons</media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>PGL Tavern Tales will hold its final event of 2016 at DreamHack Bucharest, the organization announced Tuesday.</p><p>The event will run from Sept. 16-18 in Bucharest, Romania, and will feature 16 players competing for a $25,000 prize pool. Fourteen of the players will be invited to the event, with the remaining two slots to be filled through local qualifiers.</p><p>All matches will be best-of-fives using the Last Hero Standing format, with players having to bring decks from all nine classes to each match.</p><p>The last PGL Tavern Tales tournament was held in February in Bucharest, and was won by Romanian player Marius &quot;<strong>xTrackyStyle</strong>&quot; Nistor, who took home $8,000 USD and 15 HCT points.</p><p><em>Preston Dozsa is a news editor for theScore esports. <a href="https://twitter.com/prestondozsa?lang=en">You can follow him on Twitter.</a></em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">9913</guid>
  <title>The Old Gods unite at the HCT NA Summer Preliminaries</title>
  <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9913</link>
  <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 23:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator/>
  <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/8444/w1080xh810_WhispersHeader2.jpg?ts=1457726726">
    <media:credit>theScore esports / Blizzard Entertainment</media:credit>
  </media:content>
  <content:encoded>
    <![CDATA[<p>The NA Preliminaries for HCT&#39;s Summer Championship are set to run between Aug. 19-21 and while most competitors are packing the usual mix of Control Warriors, Aggro Shamans, and Token Druids, some others have gotten a bit more... creative.</p><p>From Reno Shaman to a Reno/Pirate/Dragon/Unicorn Priest, here are the weirdest, wildest decks seeing play this weekend. </p><p><strong>Of Portals and Chess Pieces</strong></p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11161/cropped_KarazhanCards.jpg?ts=1469811775"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>With only two wings of Karazhan released, it&#39;s understandable few players are willing to experiment with untested cards like Moroes or Barnes. However, the Karazhan cards some players are experimenting with are less-so powerful minions like Kindly Grandmother, Enchanted Raven or Cloaked Huntress, but tentative use of the new portal cards.</p><p>For instance, as predicted by <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9833" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9833">theScore esports's Keith Capstick</a>, Firelands Portal is seeing a lot of play in Tempo Mage setups with over a dozen players packing at least one, and some packing twins.</p><p>Maelstrom Portal was also included in about 10 Shaman decks, a couple including Master of Evolution which could get eke more value out of the Portal&#39;s random one-drop.</p><p>Possibly the most popular Karazhan card in the preliminaries, however, is the Ivory Knight which has gone into 15 or so Murlock and N&#39;Zoth Paladin decks.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="imgur-embed-pub" lang="en" data-id="a/SJMsA"><a href="//imgur.com/SJMsA"></a></blockquote><script async="" src="https://s.imgur.com/min/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p><strong>tripp's Old Gods Warlock</strong></p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="imgur-embed-pub" lang="en" data-id="a/EcdvW"><a href="//imgur.com/EcdvW"></a></blockquote><script async="" src="https://s.imgur.com/min/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>Many decks have taken their name from one of the feared Old Gods since WoToG descended on Hearthstone, but only one player to date has dared take a deck featuring all four into a tournament. While&#39;s tripp&#39;s Old Gods deck is mostly geared towards buffing the dread C&#39;thun, it also dares contain N&#39;Zoth the Corruptor (despite having no Deathrattle minions), Yogg-Saron, Hope&#39;s End (despite having only six spells) and even Y&#39;shaarj Rage Unbound, whose fury and unreliable card effect have prevented him from seeing much competitive play.</p><p><strong>Fr0zen's Sort-of Freeze/Reno Deck</strong></p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="imgur-embed-pub" lang="en" data-id="a/cMEC0"><a href="//imgur.com/cMEC0"></a></blockquote><script async="" src="https://s.imgur.com/min/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>While some Freeze Mage players like to include Reno Jackson in their list in case their opponent withstands all their Blizzards and Fireballs and just need to last longer than them in Fatigue, few would bother including him when their deck contains 11 duplicate cards. Ignoring the possibility of two duplicates getting stuck at the bottom of his deck, Fr0zen would still have to play more than a third of his deck before seeing any use out of Reno. </p><p><strong>TheRealDrWho's Reno Shaman</strong></p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="imgur-embed-pub" lang="en" data-id="a/GGlFB"><a href="//imgur.com/GGlFB"></a></blockquote><script async="" src="https://s.imgur.com/min/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>Shaman is easily one of the most powerful classes in the current meta, with powerful spells, unbeatable combos and even the infamous four-mana 7/7 at their disposal. However, the same qualities that make for wicked Aggro and Concede decks aren&#39;t necessarily conductive to a successful Reno deck. While I would never accuse Shaman of being a one-trick pony reliant on a handful of overpowered cards, TheRealDrWho&#39;s Reno Shaman raises some questions over how enthralling Thrall the Shaman truly is.</p><p><strong>tripp's Unicorn Priest</strong></p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="imgur-embed-pub" lang="en" data-id="a/IQqvM"><a href="//imgur.com/IQqvM"></a></blockquote><script async="" src="https://s.imgur.com/min/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>The same player who brought us the combined power of all four Old Gods of Azeroth, might also have unlocked the secret behind Ben Brode&#39;s mythical Unicorn Priest. With a mix of Pirates, Dragons and even Reno Jackson, tripp&#39;s Unicorn Priest lacks a number of main stays usually associated with the class like Healing Circle or Auchenai Soul Priest. But perhaps it&#39;s that aggro set-up not usually associated with Hearthstone&#39;s resident healer that will free Anduin Wrynn from the bottom of the Standard Meta.</p><p><em>Sasha Erfanian is a news editor for theScore esports. <a href="https://twitter.com/SashaErfanian">Follow him on Twitter</a>, it'll be great for his self-esteem.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
  </content:encoded>
</item>
  </channel>
</rss>
