<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>LoL | theScore</title>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10474</guid>
            <title>The History of the World Championship</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10474</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 16:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Tim "Magic" Sevenhuysen</dc:creator>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12119/w1080xh810_maxresdefault.jpg?ts=1474387836">
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>In the five years since its first World Championship, League of Legends has gone from a budding game to an esports juggernaut known the world over. What started out as a small, $100,000 event, has ballooned into one of the most prestigious, popular tournaments in all of esports.</p><p>With this year's World Championship promising to be one of the best yet, we thought it was only right to look back on the previous iterations of the tournament and take a look at the road that brought us to now.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><iframe width="480" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9T8hq3N8u2E" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></figure><p>Here is a history of the World Championship.</p><p><em>For more video interviews and highlights, be sure to subscribe to theScore esports on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCSCoziKHqjqbox3Fv3Pb4BA">YouTube</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10246</guid>
            <title>The Road less traveled: I MAY's unconventional playstyle</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10246</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 14:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12105/w1080xh810_1CUN0170.jpg?ts=1474231375">
                <media:credit>刘一村's album / LPL</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>If you aren&rsquo;t particularly good in lane, why bother to stay there? The League of Legends Pro League&rsquo;s I MAY have yet to come up with a reason why facing your opponents head-on in 2v2s or 1v1s is a necessity, even in a post-patch 6.15 world where the importance of laning phase and direct matchups has been emphasized by players and commentators globally.</p><p>That doesn&rsquo;t mean they lane swap. In fact, I MAY haven&#39;t yet experimented very much with post-five minute lane swaps like many other teams attending Worlds. Prior to Patch 6.15, they didn&rsquo;t have a particularly high lane swap rate either, having only started with a different number of players in the bottom and top lane after three minutes in 30 percent of their regular season games.</p><p>I MAY just don&rsquo;t stay in lane if they can trade an advantage on one side of the map for a loss on another. A mixture of a roaming-oriented style and generally poor laning phase skill has made top laner Shek &quot;<strong>AmazingJ</strong>&quot; Waiho the only player on the team aside from support Yun &quot;<strong>Road</strong>&quot; Hangil to average a CS lead over his opponent at 10 minutes, and it&rsquo;s a modest lead of 0.7. With the exception of AD carry Xie &quot;<strong>jinjiao</strong>&quot; Jinshan, who averages a deficit of 6.6 CS at 10 minutes, I MAY&rsquo;s players remain even enough in lane that they can push the wave out and look for opportunities to find picks between lanes.</p><p>Following I MAY&rsquo;s 3-2 victory over Team WE in the 2016 LPL Regional Final, Coach Son &quot;<strong>Kezman</strong>&quot; Daeyoung proclaimed, &quot;When I first came to China and joined the LSPL team, having just started to look at these players, I thought that bringing them up would be very hard. Later, when we took the LSPL Championship, upon accepting our trophy, [AmazingJ] said our goal was to make it to the World Championship. I asked myself isn&#39;t this person a bit abnormal?&quot;</p><p>A characterization of AmazingJ as slightly insane for making an emotional speech about returning to the World Championship after they had to struggle to beat out LSPL team Young Miracles isn&rsquo;t out of line. I MAY&rsquo;s form under the banner of EDward Esports was less than ideal. They made mistakes in lane that allowed Young Miracles to get massive leads and only managed to come back as a result of YM&rsquo;s poor Baron play. Given similar circumstances in the fifth game of I MAY&rsquo;s World Championship qualifying series against WE, it appears not everything changes &mdash; but certainly a lot has.</p><p>Two of I MAY&rsquo;s players, Kang &quot;<strong>BaeMe</strong>&quot; Yanghyun and jinjiao, transferred to EDward Gaming&rsquo;s substitute roster after AD Gaming, EDward Gaming&rsquo;s sister team, failed to qualify for the LPL in 2015 LPL Spring. They and now-Apex Gaming-top laner Jeon &ldquo;<strong>Ray</strong>&rdquo; Jiwon were shuttled to the main squad in hopes that they would gain experience and supplement the EDG roster before returning to the LSPL.</p><p>In the meantime, AD Gaming managed to get itself relegated at the end of 2015 LSPL Summer. After multiple roster changes, they had only started to improve with the addition of Road near the end of the split, and even then AD Gaming were a sinking ship. Only the ex-Xenics support remained to try to perform feats of strength to get ADG to win any games. That&#39;s when Road first won his identity as I MAY&#39;s carry, an identity he has retained since.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12103/cropped_1CUN9688.jpg?ts=1474231125"><figcaption>Photo: 刘一村</figcaption></figure><p>When BaeMe and jinjiao returned to LSPL after EDward Gaming purchased a replacement spot under the banner of EDward Esports, they had lost star top laner Ray to the North American LCS. jinjiao and BaeMe focused primarily on holding their lanes while Ray played glass cannon Jarvan IV or Ryze to drag the team to wins. The team's new talent, Road, roamed frequently and assisted the jungler to gank other lanes, but EDE didn’t have a star yet.</p><p><strong>RELATED: <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/8245" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/8245">A blinding Ray: A look at Ray's history as he transitions to Apex Gaming​</a></strong></p><p>AmazingJ was a dubious choice, especially after a depressing World Championship performance earned him a spot on the fanbase’s all-bei guo (literally pot-back, meaning the player bears the burden of blame for the team’s loss and acts as a scapegoat) team as the top laner who performed the worst of the three LPL teams attending Worlds. Prior to AmazingJ’s unfortunate international disgrace, he had a lot of support as Energy Pacemaker’s main carry. His flaws largely came down to not playing well without a lot of jungle attention, something he had grown accustomed to on EP. Ming "<strong>clearlove</strong>" Kai, never known for ganking the top lane, spent most of his time on the bottom side of the map while AmazingJ continued to play aggressively, as if his jungler were nearby, and he was punished for it against SK Telecom T1’s top and jungle combination.</p><p>To make this transition easier, AmazingJ was joined by an old teammate from his days on Hong Kong's You Can’t Stop Me in late 2013. Fan "<strong>Avoidless</strong>" Jun Wei had strong synergy with AmazingJ almost immediately, in particular because Avoidless wasn’t initially comfortable speaking Mandarin Chinese over Cantonese, and he could allegedly communicate with AmazingJ more easily. Over time, Avoidless fell in line with the rest of the team and even conducted a few post-match interviews in Mandarin.</p><p>Avoidless was a prized asset on the new lineup. He transferred from another high-ranked LSPL team, Legend Dragon, comprised almost entirely of Hong Kong and Taiwanese players. Over time, the creative pathing of Avoidless made him the starting jungler of I MAY, though he competed with the likes of Wang "<strong>BayBay</strong>" Youchun — who was loaned to EDE from ahq e-Sports Club while they were in LSPL as part of the close relationship between the two organizations. Avoidless also competed with EDG's substitute Zhao “<strong>Mitty</strong>” Zhiming, previously known as Firelol or Blackloli, who was dubbed "clearlove's student" due to the lessons he received on stream from EDG's famous starting jungler.</p><p>Finding creative solutions in weak jungle matchups or assuming his laners will lose to minimize loss make Avoidless shrewd. He more often looks for counterganks than moments to initiate, in part because he has struggled to react to the LPL’s more deadly countergankers like clearlove or Choi “<strong>DanDy</strong>” Inkyu when he's the one taking initiative. Avoidless demonstrated his ability to adapt well in series throughout the LPL playoffs in particular, starting wolves camp to maintain vision and taking opportunities to apply pressure to top side, which allowed AmazingJ to play aggressively.</p><p>It may seem strange to call I MAY&rsquo;s main laning carry their top laner when the only champions AmazingJ played more than five times this split are all tanks: Ekko, Shen and Trundle. But AmazingJ carries primarily through flanking in fights and locking down targets as part of I MAY&rsquo;s pick style &mdash; as the team more often than not will avoid straight 5v5s unless they can find a creative Teleport flank or are far ahead of their opponents.</p><p>After I MAY qualified for the LPL, two of EDward Gaming&rsquo;s substitutes joined the roster. One was Mitty, who only played a handful of games before being permanently benched for Avoidless and becoming something of an interview personality doing content with a third-party media. The other was ex-Ever mid laner, Kang &quot;<strong>Athena</strong>&quot; Hawoon, who had played two series in the LPL with EDward Gaming the previous split.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12106/cropped_1CUN9827.jpg?ts=1474231560"><figcaption>Photo: 刘一村</figcaption></figure><p>The addition of Athena created an interesting dynamic for I MAY. With the exception of the Regional final against Team WE, I May continued to rotate their mid laners throughout the split, and over time, though their two mid laners began with a great deal of similarities in style, Athena and BaeMe began to develop distinct identities. When Viktor and Azir were most popular, BaeMe and Avoidless played a similar style of staying confined to mid lane and constantly pushing the wave, but BaeMe&rsquo;s champion pool worked in more aggressive picks with a heavier roam focus like Twisted Fate and LeBlanc.</p><p>Athena remained a more stable player who simply played lane to shove, giving I MAY a constant point in games, while BaeMe complemented I MAY&rsquo;s higher mobility playstyle. Perhaps one of I MAY&rsquo;s most interesting games was their <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o5znhcBvBOQ">Game 3, third-place match</a> against Team WE in the LPL playoffs. BaeMe picked the second Aurelion Sol of the summer split to complement jinjiao&rsquo;s Kog&rsquo;Maw.</p><p>Every time AmazingJ&rsquo;s Ekko had Chronobreak, he could Teleport to a location, and both BaeMe and Avoidless&rsquo; Rek&rsquo;Sai could assist in the dive. This allowed I MAY to pick up an early lead bottom and build their control.</p><p>This kind of early dive approach is not atypical of I MAY. In publicly acknowledging, &ldquo;with our individual strength, we are not the best,&rdquo; Coach Kezman admitted that I MAY cannot look for a standard approach toward winning the game. They can overload on globals, rely upon roaming opportunities, or wait for their opponents to make a mistake.</p><p>One of I MAY&rsquo;s favorite strategies is in using Road to facilitate mid lane action. If Athena plays in the mid lane, Road will look to roam mid before Level 6. If he accomplishes a successful gank, he can nullify a disadvantageous matchup. This allows Athena to play within a more limited champion pool and suffer less of a punishment if he gets counterpicked. As a result, I MAY will usually save their counterpick on red side for a different role, bucking the general LPL trend.</p><p>Because of Road's frequent roams, it’s hard to judge jinjiao based on his apparent poor laning phase performance. When he plays Sivir, he will either look to rapidly push out the wave to give Road a roaming opportunity, or he will play Jhin and hug his turret or roam with Road as well.</p><p>This makes I MAY&rsquo;s early game somewhat readable when Athena plays. In the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m2Ju8l_JccQ">second game between I MAY and WE</a> in the 2016 LPL Regional final, WE support Yoon &ldquo;<strong>Zero</strong>&rdquo; Kyungsup read Road&rsquo;s roam attempt, and the two supports spent nearly two minutes trading wards in river and staking out the lane before returning to the bottom lane.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12104/cropped_1CUN9666.jpg?ts=1474231195"><figcaption>Photo: 刘一村</figcaption></figure><p>When Road does lane with jinjiao, they usually allow the wave to be pushed into them or push out when they coordinate a dive on bottom lane with their team. When BaeMe plays, I MAY will organize more dives and teamfights early in the bottom lane for dragon control. I MAY get most of their bottom lane advantages by punishing over-aggression. Road is good at reacting to dives and punishing aggressive bottom lanes, but if he initiates a play in the 2v2, he more often than not will put himself out of position. In this way, he tends to be more suited toward roaming.</p><p>Part of the reason AmazingJ has stuck more to tank tops is the heavy crowd control they bring. Even picks like Nautilus, a champion AmazingJ played five times throughout the regular season, provide a lot of lockdown and make successful top lane ganks easier. It also makes the threat of a Teleport much stronger in the bottom lane. AmazingJ can play his matchup more aggressively if the opponent knows his jungler is lurking, and he has the crowd control to lock them down and punish them.</p><p>I MAY&rsquo;s greatest strength is in how these pieces work together in the early game for them to create opportunities to gain advantages with creative plays. Of all the teams at Worlds, I MAY are more likely to give up or trade advantages in one lane for another. This can actually turn out to be a productive strategy if it means they give up pressure in one lane for a surprise gank in the bottom lane and manage to come away with first turret gold. This will create an advantageous trade in their favor and allow them to snowball.</p><p>For this reason, I MAY averaged a gold lead at ten minutes of 450, above LPL champions EDward Gaming. Despite this, I MAY seem unsure what to do with their advantages. When turrets fall and the enemy team starts grouping, I MAY lose their surprise advantage. In dragon fights, jinjiao becomes more of a liability, as he&rsquo;ll often just step forward and misposition. Coordination also appears to be lacking between solo laners, and the team has often joked that at least one of their mid laners doesn&rsquo;t seem to like talking. I MAY&rsquo;s teamfighting on an even footing, despite the LPL stereotype, is not particularly spectacular.</p><p>But because of their tendency to lose control of mid game, their late game resilience is the other impressive part of I MAY. The team&rsquo;s sense for creative warding and Teleport flanks gives them the ability to create interesting comebacks. As long as they draft a high quantity of wave clear champions (as in the Regional Final with Sivir, Nautilus, and Malzahar), I MAY can stall a game out long enough to capitalize on a mistake. This means setting up wards in side lanes or behind the Baron pit to look for collapses from AmazingJ.</p><p>Even with a poor individual laning phase and inability to execute in the midgame, however, I MAY&rsquo;s greatest failing is their predictability. Attempts to diverge from an early pick strategy lead to more losses for I MAY in the regular season, and they triggered their upswing with the re-introduction of Alistar into the LPL meta. Road&rsquo;s ability to get a pick on the champion, especially around Baron, allowed I MAY to maintain momentum and close games more completely, despite also giving their bottom lane 2v2 matchup more weaknesses.</p><p>I MAY&rsquo;s greatest variability comes from the mid laner they choose to run, but whether they run Athena or BaeMe only determines whether their mid laner will look to hold the lane or create more dives around the map. As a result, more pressure goes to Avoidless to try to make unpredictable moves. His ability to outmaneuver Royal Never Give Up&rsquo;s Liu &ldquo;<strong>Mlxg</strong>&rdquo; Shiyu and WE&rsquo;s Xiang &quot;<strong>Condi</strong>&quot; Renjie increased as the season progressed, suggesting an increase in Avoidless&rsquo; comfort in the jungle as well as his ability to read his opponents.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/10583/cropped_210195.jpg?ts=1466969732"><figcaption>Photo: 刘一村</figcaption></figure><p>But for their quirky playstyle, what truly makes I MAY unique are their moderate expectations. In the history of LPL teams attending the World Championship, none of them have touched down with more conservative expectations than I MAY. Following the Regional Final, I MAY Coach Kezman and both AmazingJ and jinjiao told journalists that they were merely aiming to escape groups. This was before the team had even seen the draw.</p><p>Aside from AmazingJ, team analyst Huang &quot;<strong>FireFox</strong>&quot; Tinghsiang is the only other I MAY member to have previously attended a World Championship. As a novice coach for LGD Gaming, he bore a great deal of blame for LGD&rsquo;s confusing drafts, earning the title of the all-bei guo<strong> </strong>Coach among 2015 World Championship attendees. His words left the deepest impression at I MAY&rsquo;s final press conference.</p><p>“If we lost," FireFox said, "it just means that our strength was not enough, if we win, it also means I want to continue to encourage them, because our play in this best-of-five had a lot of deficiencies. As the coach said, we don't just rely on our individual strength to win. So, if we will represent the LPL at Worlds, we must improve our ability in order to bring greater honor to the LPL.”</p><p>I MAY&rsquo;s drafts and patch adaptation have been an unsung positive for the team. Despite having limited champion pools and strategies in many instances, they seem to understand meta priorities quickly. I MAY have a very composition-focused approach to drafting, choosing champions that complement each other, such as Shen and Kog&rsquo;Maw or multiple globals, even if it also means choosing losing lane matchups. FireFox receives a fair amount of credit from the team for such compositions.</p><p>From FireFox&rsquo;s words, it&rsquo;s clear he&rsquo;s focused on redemption. Failing to respond to meta swings this time around isn&rsquo;t an option. I MAY know they&rsquo;re underdogs, which means that they share the perhaps unique distinction of a team coming to Worlds from the LPL primarily to learn from foreign teams without expecting to escape Groups as a foregone conclusion.</p><p>I MAY are dangerous because they&rsquo;re unconventional, but they&rsquo;re even more dangerous because of how far they&rsquo;ve come in a short time and the improvements they&#39;ve made since their scattered squeak into the LPL against Young Miracles. Given the steep competition in Group B, they aren&rsquo;t expected to make it to quarterfinals, but if they did &mdash; well, it certainly wouldn&rsquo;t be the strangest thing about them.</p><p><em>Header image credited to <a href="http://migrator.alltuu.com/act/actId2683/sepId4314">刘一村's album</a></em>.</p><p><em>Kelsey Moser is a staff writer for theScore esports. You can <a href="http://twitter.com/karonmoser">follow her on Twitter</a> to tell her her puns are bad.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10404</guid>
            <title>Korean BBQ with ROX Tigers: the perks of Worlds in NA, sound booths and Twitter
                wars
            </title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10404</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 19:49:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>theScore esports Staff</dc:creator>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12114/w1080xh810_maxresdefault.jpg?ts=1474314200">
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Coming off their 2016 LCK Summer Split win and after an arduous day of practice for the upcoming World Championship, the ROX Tigers were ready to eat.</p><p>theScore esports got the chance to sit down with the team at a Korean BBQ restaurant to discuss the perks of having Worlds take place in North America this year, what advice the veteran players would give to jungler Han "<strong>Peanut</strong>" Wang-ho and to share their thoughts on when pros take to Twitter to argue.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><iframe width="480" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rQkRQ267PRM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></figure><p><em>For more video interviews and highlights, be sure to subscribe to theScore esports on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCSCoziKHqjqbox3Fv3Pb4BA">YouTube</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10247</guid>
            <title>One of these things is not like the others: Samsung's unlikely Worlds
                appearance
            </title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10247</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 19:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12079/w1080xh810_SSGteam.jpg?ts=1474035483">
                <media:credit>KeSPA / LCK Summer 2016</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Samsung Galaxy were not the first casualty of the Korean Exodus, but they were certainly the most notorious. No Korean League of Legends organization lost as many players as Samsung during the 2014-15 offseason — a stunning turn of events following their two teams’ dominion over much of the 2014 competitive year.</p><p>Following SK Telecom T1 K’s undefeated run through OnGameNet’s Champions Winter 2013-14, Samsung Coach Choi Yoon-sang pushed for one of the most famous LoL roster swaps in history, bringing Samsung Galaxy White’s Bae <strong>“dade”</strong> Eo-jin to their sister team Blue for Heo <strong>“PawN”</strong> Won-seok. This ushered in the era of Samsung.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12077/cropped_15385586617_f5e95e71da_k.jpg?ts=1474035405"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Both teams were chock full of top-tier talent, including one of the greatest junglers of all time in Choi <strong>“DanDy”</strong> In-kyu, AD carries Gu <strong>“Imp”</strong> Seung-bin and Kim <strong>“Deft”</strong> Hyuk-kyu and one of the greatest supports of all time in Cho<strong> “Mata” </strong>Se-hyeong. By the end of 2014, the organization had two Champions Finals appearances, one Champions title courtesy of Samsung Blue, and were reigning world champions courtesy of Samsung White. They were known as an organization that could bring out the best in some of LoL unrivaled talents.</p><p>This year’s Samsung team is decidedly not that.</p><p>In the past two years, since losing their most famous playmakers, Samsung have come nowhere close to regaining their prior dominance. Unlike the two previous Samsung representatives at League of Legends' largest international event, 2016 Samsung Galaxy are an anomaly — the team was not expected to even qualify. It took well over a year after losing both 2015 starting rosters for Samsung to assemble a roster that could contend for playoffs.</p><p>Lucrative contract offers from China combined with the dissolution of sister teams resulted in all players from both Samsung White and Blue leaving Samsung for various Chinese organizations in the 2014-15 offseason. On Dec. 2, 2014, Samsung cobbled together a roster with well-known solo queue Fizz player Park<strong> </strong>“<strong>BlisS</strong>” Jong-won (formerly known as “<strong>Bell Park</strong>”<strong> </strong>on the ladder), jungler Seo “<strong>Eve</strong>”<strong> </strong>Jun-cheol, and top laner Lee<strong> </strong>“<strong>CuVee</strong>” Seong-jin. These three solo queue pickups were joined by former Prime Optimus AD carry Lee “<strong>Fury</strong>” Jin-yong (then known as “<strong>ZetNjin</strong>”), and former ahq Korea support and SK Telecom T1 K substitute Kwon “<strong>Wraith</strong>” Ji-min (formerly known as “<strong>Loray</strong>,” “<strong>IcebearB</strong>” and “<strong>Casper</strong>”).</p><p>Perhaps more significant than the loss of all ten of their players, was the departure of key Samsung staff members who had helped bring home the Summoner’s Cup, including Coach Choi. Lacking any semblance of cohesion on the Rift, this new Samsung team performed so poorly that their title as reigning world champions — a badge of honor that SK Telecom T1 had carried into early 2014 with an undefeated season — was quickly forgotten.</p><p>BlisS looked lost in lane and was regularly -7.1 CS behind his laning opponents, last of all mid laners in LCK Spring 2015. Eve had trouble coordinating with his side lanes, especially given the lack of mid lane pressure, while top and bot also struggled to synergize with the rest of their team. Samsung won only two series in total during LoL Champions Korea Spring 2015, finishing in last place. The team fared slightly better in LCK Summer 2015. Acquiring mid laner Lee <strong>“Crown” </strong>Min-ho, Samsung often took opponents to three games throughout the summer split, even in a loss, showing a bit of improvement that placed the reigning world champions in seventh this time around.</p><p>Seventh place certainly wasn’t good enough for the reigning world champions. After SK Telecom T1 became successors to Samsung Galaxy White’s crown in late October 2015, the majority of Samsung’s roster left the team, leaving the once-illustrious organization again picking up the pieces in the offseason.</p><p>Samsung’s most high-profile signing in the 2015-16 offseason was that of legacy CJ Entus player Kang <strong>“Ambition” </strong>Chan-yong, who had just completed his first season as a jungler after an already distinguished mid lane career. Despite his experience and dedication to the game, he was still a fledgling jungler.</p><p>While jungling for CJ in 2015, Ambition was taught two things: how to farm as a jungler, and how to gank the mid lane for their star carry, Shin<strong> “CoCo”</strong> Jin-yeong. Of all starting junglers in LCK Summer 2015, Ambition had the highest CS differential at ten minutes (3.3) and tied for the second-highest CS per minute (3.4), but showed a distinct lack of creativity and variety needed to keep opponents guessing for long. His arrival on Samsung at the start of LCK Spring 2016 was accompanied by little fanfare. Ambition wasn’t the worst, but he certainly wasn’t near the best in his position. He wasn’t even the best role-swapped jungler to come out of the rocky restructuring year, with KT Rolster’s Go<strong> “Score”</strong> Dong-bin finding his footing alongside support Lee <strong>“Piccaboo” </strong>Jong-beom in late LCK Summer 2015 and KT’s 2015 World Championship run.</p><p>Fortunately for Ambition, what Samsung did have was a strong support that was willing to partner with the new jungler to cover the map early — be it through roaming ganks or coordinating vision to secure safer jungle routes. Unlike Hong “<strong>Madlife</strong>” Min-gi, who was more content to match the pace of his laning partner, the presence of Samsung’s Wraith visibly improved Ambition’s early pathing, even if his end goals — farming until the mid or late game — remained similar. Tied for first of all LCK Spring 2016 starting junglers, Ambition averaged a whopping 4.9 CS per minute and became a key DPS carry in Samsung’s teamfights. Ambition had already functioned as a fifth laner while jungling for CJ, and the former mid only grew throughout the LCK Spring 2016 season. His early blind invades, and subsequent early deaths, were curbed as Samsung molded to Ambition’s pace, becoming a late-game 5v5 teamfighting squad that relied on Crown’s stable of wave-clear champions and Ambition.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/9798/cropped_samsungteam1.jpg?ts=1463885624"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Throughout this past spring, Samsung were considered good enough for playoffs, but not good enough for a deep run. They were expected to qualify as the fifth seed in the spring gauntlet, and would have had it not been for those meddling Afreeca Freecs, who finished their second round robin 7-2 to Samsung’s 4-5. Despite an impressive win over the ROX Tigers in Week 9 that showcased just how much Ambition had learned as a jungler up until that point, Samsung was thoroughly lackluster through the back half of the spring season, helping the Freecs earn their first playoff spot in the organization’s short history.</p><p>Summer 2016 saw a different Samsung, an aggressive teamfighting team built around rookie AD carry Park <strong>“Ruler”</strong> Jae-hyuk — previously known as <strong>“Bung”</strong> from Korean challenger team Stardust. Ambition transitioned again, becoming more of a teamfight facilitator rather than DPS carry. Crown began to make his case as one of the top mid laners in Korea. Even CuVee, cited as the weakest member of their team, had his standout performances.</p><p>Samsung jumped out to an early undefeated streak in the LCK Summer 2016 before falling to SK Telecom T1 in Week 3. New AD carry Ruler was a hot rookie in Korea along with MVP jungler Kim<strong> “Beyond”</strong> Kyu-seok, but questions regarding his champion pool and flexibility rose throughout the split. </p><p>Ruler played only six different champions total this past regular season, which in and of itself wasn't a problem due to a relatively stagnant AD carry meta. However, he overly relied on both Sivir and Ashe — the two combined made up 70 percent of his regular season games — with Ezreal as his third pick, and was far less comfortable outside of these three picks. Where his Korean counterparts had pocket off-meta champions, picked up Jhin quickly or simply looked better on a wider range of champions, Ruler's pool became increasingly suspect as the season wore on.</p><p>Top laner CuVee continued to have difficulty standing up to Korea’s best, and Samsung still struggled to find a modicum of consistency when it came to choosing teamfights. Their coordination also decreased significantly during AD-carry-turned-support Jo <strong>“CoreJJ”</strong> Yong-in’s few starting stints over Wraith as the team clumsily attempted to implement him into their gameplan before inevitably returning to Wraith seeing how Ambition’s pathing and the general team dynamic was far better with their starting support in the game.</p><p>Prior to the playoff gauntlet, CoreJJ was winless in his three total games as Samsung’s support in LCK Summer 2016. Yet CoreJJ was the support that Samsung chose to face both Afreeca and KT Rolster in the qualifying gauntlet, and the winning support when all was said and done.</p><p>The Korea Regional Finals were expected to play out similar to the LCK Summer 2016 playoffs — Afreeca would lose to Samsung, Samsung would lose to KT Rolster. Samsung Galaxy had not won a single game against KT since 2014 coming into the gauntlet and had not shown any higher level of play in recent playoffs that could indicate a successful run. CuVee’s inconsistency was still there, Ruler’s champion pool issues were still there, and Samsung as a team had yet to figure out when to fight their opponents and when to back off. The sight of CoreJJ in the booth for Game 1 over Wraith was considered confusing at best — despite his appearance in the Afreeca series, KT was a vastly superior opponent — and a half-hearted white flag at worst.</p><p>After an exhausting five games with CoreJJ starting all five, Samsung not only ended their winless streak against KT Rolster, but claimed the Korean third seed for the 2016 World Championship in a 3-2 series victory. They showed a significantly stronger understanding of the current patch, obviously using their time between their crushing playoff loss to KT and the qualifier to improve.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11795/cropped_Screenshot_2016-09-03_08.31.01.jpg?ts=1472906023"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Unlike their 2014 predecessors White and Blue, Samsung isn&rsquo;t heavily-favored. They&rsquo;re not a team of superstars. Of all members on the current roster only Crown and Wraith can compete with the best in their position in Korea and the latter may not even start. Despite White&rsquo;s 2014 success, Samsung Galaxy have had a tumultuous relationship with the League of Legends World Championship since 2013, when Samsung Galaxy Ozone had just been freshly minted under the Samsung banner and failed to make it out of groups. As a team that defied the odds to even qualify, the current Samsung squad is vastly different. They may not impress on paper, but they&rsquo;ll make up for it with careful preparation and diligence.</p><p><em>Emily Rand is a staff writer for theScore esports. You can follow her <a href="https://twitter.com/leagueofemily">on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9822</guid>
            <title>Everything you need to know about the 2016 World Championship</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9822</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 14:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>theScore esports Staff</dc:creator>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11820/w1080xh810_WorldsHeader1.jpg?ts=1473175596">
                <media:credit>Dennis Gonzales / Riot Games / theScore esports</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>The 2016 Season World Championship will give League of Legends fans the answers to the many questions accumulated over weeks of intra-regional competition.</p><p>The 16-team group stage will run in a double round robin format, so each team will get two best-of-ones against the other teams in their group.</p><p>But only two teams can emerge from each group and make it to the knockout stage, where the bracket will be randomly seeded with each group's top finisher facing a second-place team from another.</p><p>Can the ROX Tigers take it all, and will they have to exorcise the demons collectively known as SK Telecom T1 along the way? Will North American teams surprise the world, or be surprised themselves? </p><p>theScore esports is here to keep you up to date on everything Worlds-related: from the group stage in San Francisco all the way to the finals in Los Angeles.</p><h3><strong>Features</strong></h3><ul><li><a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/10246" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10246">The Road less traveled: I MAY&#39;s unconventional playstyle</a></li><li><a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/10247" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10247">One of these things is not like the others: Samsung&#39;s unlikely Worlds appearance</a></li><li><a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9827" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9827">Their Time is Now: Team SoloMid in 2016</a></li><li><a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9826" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9826">Royal Never Give Up and the myth of the Uzi Worlds buff</a></li><li><a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9825" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9825">Peace at Worlds: The subtle joys of a one-path meta</a></li><li><a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/10385" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10385">The Offscreen Play: Sencux and Splyce&#39;s slow build​</a></li><li><a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9823" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9823">theScore esports&#39; top players at LoL World Championship 2016</a></li><li><a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9824" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9824">Meiko or Break: Why EDward Gaming&#39;s support is their MVP</a></li><li><a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9821" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9821">An evening with the ROX Tigers</a></li><li><a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/10366" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10366">Kelsey Moser explains her World Championship power rankings</a></li><li><a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9819" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9819">theScore esports&#39; World Championship 2016 power rankings</a></li></ul><h3><strong>Interviews</strong></h3><ul><li><a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/10361" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10361">The Third Time is the Charm: INTZ's Tockers on going to the World Championship</a></li><li><a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9820" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9820">The Bad Matchup: Odoamne and H2K's year</a></li></ul><h3><strong>News</strong></h3><ul><li><a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/10368" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10368">Reignover coaching Xmithie at CLG pre-Worlds bootcamp</a></li><li><a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/10323" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10323">Kelsey Moser: Group draw rapid reaction</a></li><li><a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/10322" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10322">LoL community reacts to the 2016 World Championship group draw</a></li><li><a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/10322" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10322">2016 World Championship group draw results: Tigers vs. G2 in Group A, TSM vs. Royal in Group D</a></li></ul><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10480</guid>
            <title>DinTer alleges that Olleh pressured team to remove him from Regional Finals
                roster
            </title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10480</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 18:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/9565/w1080xh810_HKES1.jpg?ts=1462813774">
                <media:credit>theScore esports / Hong Kong Esports</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Hong Kong Esports jungler Shiue "<strong>DinTer</strong>" Hung-Wei has alleged that former HKE support Kim "<strong>Olleh</strong>" Joon-sung had him taken off the starting lineup for the 2016 Taiwan Regional Finals by threatening to leave with AD carry Jeong "<strong>Raison</strong>" Soo-bin.</p><p>Speaking<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q9FKX7SxIU0"> on-stream earlier this month,</a> DinTer alleged that there were tensions forming among members of the HKE roster which led to arguments between certain members of the team. At some point prior to the regional finals, DinTer alleges that tensions came to a head, resulting in Olleh threatening to take Raison and fly back to Korea immediately if DinTer was not subbed out for the tournament.</p><p>HKE did start Lai "<strong>Wind</strong>" Chap Yin in the jungle instead of DinTer in the regional finals. The team placed 3rd-4th after a 3-0 loss to ahq e-Sports Club, and announced that Raison and Olleh had parted ways with the organization shortly after. At the time, HKE stated that Raison's contract had expired, while Olleh's was terminated. </p><p>In the video, DinTer alleges that Olleh was made aware of the fact that he was being removed the roster ahead of time and attempted to work around it. According to DinTer, Raison would refuse to play with new supports from the Korean server that the team would trial, allegedly stating that he preferred to play with Olleh. This relationship formed over the course of the two players&#39; time on HKE, and DinTer alleges it eventually led to Olleh threatening to take him with him if DinTer was not taken off the roster.</p><p>HKE finished fourth in both the 2016 LMS Summer Season and the Summer Playoffs with Raison, Olleh and Dinter on the roster. Raison joined the roster in May of 2015, but was suspended from the LMS in July 2015 for Elo boosting, and returned to the active roster in April 2016 once his suspension ended. </p><p>Olleh joined HKE in January 2015 after leaving CBLOL team paiN Gaming and finished the 2016 LMS Summer Split with a 3.10 KDA, his lowest regular-season KDA he has ever had while with HKE. </p><p><a href="http://twitter.com/daniel_rosen"><em>Daniel Rosen is a news editor for theScore esports. You can follow him on Twitter.</em></a></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9827</guid>
            <title>Their Time is Now: Team SoloMid in 2016</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9827</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 14:39:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11753/w1080xh810_NALCS_Finals_-_Air_Canada_Centre_-_TSM_v_C9-88.jpg?ts=1472751606">
                <media:credit>Jose Silva / theScore esports</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Like 2015 Fnatic and 2014 Cloud9 before them, 2016 Team SoloMid now enters the World Championship as the Western team to beat. A quick glance over the past four World Championships tells a tale of Korean dominance with China not so far behind until their dramatic collapse at the 2015 tournament. Since the Season 2 World Championship, five of the eight total finalists have come from Korea. China has produced two Worlds finalists, and Taiwan’s Taipei Assassins took home the Summoner’s Cup in 2012. </p><p>No North American team has reached the semifinals of a League of Legends World Championship, since TSM made it to the losers&#39; finals in Season 1. Now, TSM aim to change that narrative.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/8923/cropped_26172789676_8f633dd4e7_k.jpg?ts=1460059705"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Team SoloMid were the clear winners of the 2015-16 offseason. Once again centering their team around star mid laner S&oslash;ren <strong>&ldquo;Bjergsen&rdquo;</strong> Bjerg, TSM acquired talent from both Europe and North America to produce a stacked roster that had fans and analysts slavering to see in action.</p><p>Their two most notable acquisitions formed what looked to be one of the West&rsquo;s strongest bottom lanes in Yiliang <strong>&ldquo;Doublelift&rdquo; </strong>Peng and Bora <strong>&ldquo;YellOwStaR&rdquo;</strong> Kim. A former rival of TSM, Doublelift, was ousted from Counter Logic Gaming &mdash; an organization almost synonymous with his own personal brand &mdash; and appeared on TSM&rsquo;s doorstep within 24 hours, eager to prove them, and the world, wrong. New TSM top laner Kevin <strong>&ldquo;Hauntzer&rdquo;</strong> Yarnell was a rising NA star from the now-defunct Gravity Gaming and Dennis <strong>&ldquo;Svenskeren&rdquo;</strong> Johnsen had dazzled EU LCS audiences even as SK Gaming fell further in the EU standings and viewers&rsquo; esteem.</p><p>The question for TSM going into this past spring was not of when the team would come together, but how quickly. Most fans expected another strong regular season from TSM. The team&#39;s previous iteration had run its course. Between TSM&rsquo;s 2015 World Championship group stage exit and top laner Marcus <strong>&ldquo;Dyrus&rdquo;</strong> Hill&rsquo;s retirement, it was time for the team to move on. On paper, the organization&#39;s celebrated new roster seemed to herald an even brighter future for one of NA scene&rsquo;s founding fathers.</p><p>Instead, TSM could never get all of their pieces to fit together, and finished the 2016 NA LCS Spring Split in sixth place, their lowest finish in NA LCS history. The playoffs proved to be just what TSM needed to find their stride, but, by the time the finals rolled around, they were still slightly behind CLG in terms of coordination. CLG had slowly improved throughout the course of the split, and relied on a strong team dynamic, smart objective trading, and efficient management of their resources to secure their wins. To paraphrase CLG&rsquo;s comms prior to their Game 5 showdown with TSM at Mandalay Bay, TSM had just learned to be a team, whereas CLG&rsquo;s teamwork had been honed throughout their regular season and playoff run. CLG went to the 2016 Mid-Season Invitational and performed well above expectations, finishing the tournament in second place just behind Korea&rsquo;s SK Telecom T1. Meanwhile, TSM went back to the drawing board.</p><p>It&rsquo;s unlikely that rookie support Vincent <strong>&ldquo;Biofrost&rdquo;</strong> Wang was the only puzzle piece that TSM needed to succeed. TSM&rsquo;s 2016 NA LCS Summer Split dominance is a product of a myriad of factors, most of which are impossible to know from the outside looking in. Yet Biofrost&rsquo;s arrival ushered in a new era of communication and coordination that made a dramatic difference on the Rift. TSM lost only one best-of-three series in the regular season and only dropped a single game to Cloud9 in the 2016 NA LCS Summer Finals en route to another North American title.</p><p>This has led to no small amount of anticipation for their performance at the 2016 World Championship, where they&#39;re expected to do the best of all western teams in attendance.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12013/cropped_17615878201_6676ce4796_k.jpg?ts=1474019314"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>TSM were similarly thought of as favorites to go far at an international event at the 2015 Mid-Season Invitational. The results couldn’t have been more contrary to their initial favorable outlook.</p><p>Surprise winners of the 2015 IEM World Championship at Katowice, TSM were touted as the best western team in the world at that time. The 2015 EU LCS Spring Split Finals series between Fnatic and Unicorns of Love had been a 3-2 bloodbath that made both teams look shoddy, whereas TSM were coming off of a 3-1 finals win over C9. Yet, Fnatic rose to prominence throughout the 2015 MSI tournament, taking Faker&#39;s SK Telecom T1 to five games in their semifinal bout. They performed well above all expectations, relying on the duo of top laner Heo <strong>&ldquo;Huni&rdquo; </strong>Seung-hoon and jungler Kim <strong>&ldquo;Reignover&rdquo;</strong> Yeu-jin along with then-Fnatic support YellOwStaR, who stood out as their team visibly improved the deeper they went into the tournament. TSM only managed to take one game during the round robin group stages &mdash; a victory over Turkish International Wildcard representative Beşiktaş e-Sports Club.</p><p>While Fnatic took teams by surprise as they grew their coordination and map movement, TSM appeared stale. Teams figured them out easily and TSM were ill-prepared to shift their gameplan. Thy bore no small amount of criticism for sacrificing Dyrus, placing Bjergsen on the likes of Ziggs and Urgot, and generally struggling to find a playstyle that opponents could not take advantage of early. It was impossible to tell prior to the tournament that teams would so easily best TSM &mdash; little by the way of their Summer performance, and Fnatic&rsquo;s performance, previewed their diverging paths at the 2015 MSI.</p><p>Now TSM are fresh off of one of the organization&rsquo;s most dominant regular season stretches, and only dropped one game to C9 in the Finals and they have to deal with the rising hype and promotion that surrounds their upcoming 2016 World Championship appearance. Similar buildup accompanied NA teams in the past, only to see them shown the door time and again during the Round of 8.</p><p>For North American fans, the conversation now shifts from this specific iteration of TSM’s journey to the 2016 World Championship to how they could potentially break North America’s Worlds Semifinals-less streak.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11291/cropped_27890723793_98b11aa111_k__1_.jpg?ts=1470518687"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>The first, and most obvious, fact cited in talk of TSM as a possible semifinalist is that the current metagame appears to fit TSM like a glove. Strong lanes are where TSM have thrived over the past split. Doublelift has been incredible this past summer with Biofrost by his side. Bjergsen can smoothly transition from DPS carry, to waveclear and zone control, to ruthless assassin, to teamfight maestro depending on what TSM wishes him to be for that particular game. Svenskeren learned how to stymie his adversaries in their own jungles and has became TSM’s primary teamfight initiator while Hauntzer also had a career split. TSM’s bread and butter was already strong lanes that overwhelmed opponents early, allowing them to snowball their advantages to inevitable victories. Now, the time has come to see how their lanes stack up against international competition in a meta that wholly supports their preferred playstyle.</p><p>Amidst the rise of Hauntzer, Doublelift’s stunning split, and Bjergsen’s continued reign over the NA mid lane, has also been the much-improved performance of jungler Svenskeren.</p><p>A glance at Svenskeren’s pathing while on his former team, SK Gaming, reveals a distinct lack of understanding of how to facilitate his teammates in their lanes, rather than becoming the team’s carry. As SK Gaming crumbled around him, Svenskeren went to work. When SK Gaming won a game in the 2015 EU LCS Summer — all six of them, good enough for a ninth-place finish overall — Svenskeren had something to do with it. Of all EU junglers that split he did the most amount of damage per minute (305) despite having fairly mediocre numbers across the board. </p><p>Upon arriving to TSM, his adjustment took time and no small amount of effort. He often looked lost on the map and coordinated poorly with his lanes. It wasn’t until the 2016 NA LCS Spring Playoffs that Svenskeren began to look comfortable, and these matches deferred to his preferred carry playstyle. Becoming a DPS carry for the team meant greater resources that allowed him to take over games on Graves and Nidalee. Yet this dynamic was not sustainable for TSM in the long term, especially with how many resources it took away from other members of the team, mainly Doublelift, as the meta shifted away from carry junglers.</p><p>This past summer, Svenskeren has once again faded into the background &mdash; no longer a DPS carry but still a key part of TSM&rsquo;s gameplan. He has a significantly better understanding of how and when to affect his side lanes, partnering with Bjergsen for ganks, dives and teamfight initiation. His increased presence on the map eased enemy pressure on TSM&rsquo;s lanes, allowing them to exert their own pressure or farm more freely.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11771/cropped_NALCS_Finals_-_Air_Canada_Centre_-_TSM_v_C9-99.jpg?ts=1472753851"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>The question now is how TSM will continue to play their game against stiff international competition. Their group &mdash; composed of Splyce, Samsung Galaxy and Royal Never Give Up &mdash; is already tough one, but a necessary challenge for a team that wants to be the best. It&rsquo;s now up to TSM to eschew the narrative that North American teams either choke, or are simply outclassed come Worlds quarterfinals.</p><p>Their time is now.</p><p><em>Emily Rand is a staff writer for theScore esports. You can follow her <a href="https://twitter.com/leagueofemily">on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9826</guid>
            <title>Royal Never Give Up and the myth of the Uzi Worlds buff</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9826</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 18:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11694/w1080xh810_2683-4311-239042.jpg?ts=1472718023">
                <media:credit>刘一村 / LPL / 刘一村's album</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Until Snake’s near-miraculous run at the Regional Qualifier this year, the longest day of matches for any team in Chinese League of Legends esports was Sept. 8, 2013, the day Royal Club Huang Zu played nine straight games to qualify for the 2013 World Championship as China’s first seed. In the final series, the crowd, more lukewarm than they would have been had fan favorite Team WE made an appearance, waved blinking green batons as Royal Club and Oh My God settled into their chairs. Not only was it Royal’s third series of the day, but it was the second time they played against Oh My God; they had started their run by losing 1-2 and dropping to the loser’s bracket of the tournament.</p><p>In part because they were denied their Annie support pick, Royal didn&rsquo;t choose their duo lane mid strategy for <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CKeK3fsxgVA">the first game</a>. They instead used the aggressive Elise against Yin &quot;<strong>Lovelin</strong>&quot; Le&rsquo;s farming Yorick by first ganking mid to burn Yu &quot;<strong>cool</strong>&quot; Jiajun&rsquo;s flash, then pressuring with an invade that Royal mid laner Lo &quot;<strong>Wh1t3zZ</strong>&quot; Punwai could follow up with easily for first blood. The deadly Elise and Gragas combination slayed cool and snowballed from there, adding Jian &quot;<strong>Uzi</strong>&quot; Zihao&rsquo;s assassin Twitch to the mix for a 26-minute opening devastation. Royal 3-0&rsquo;d the series against China&rsquo;s most dominant team of 2013, a team they&rsquo;d already lost a best of three to earlier that day.</p><p>In 2013, pick compositions and deep vision reigned supreme with supports buying inventories full of wards. Oh My God started the LPL revolution themselves, but Royal took it even further with strategies that pressured the mid lane with the duo lane, using Twitch to take advantage of gaps in vision and the zoning power of Annie as a support to control the jungle. When people remember Royal’s climb from a three-way tie for second place in the LPL regular season to the finals of the 2013 World Championship, they highlight Uzi’s Vayne, the power of Royal’s duo lane and the "raise the puppy" strategy.</p><p>Royal’s innovations conveniently slip out of the narrative, as does their impressive, nine-game Regional run to claim first seed from a powerhouse OMG that went toe-to-toe with SK Telecom T1 K, the eventual tournament winners, in their first game of the group stage. When people think of Royal Club at the World Championship, they call it an inexplicable "Uzi World Championship buff." They expect that, no matter how poorly Royal Never Give Up have been doing domestically in 2016, the same mysterious Worlds Buff will re-emerge.</p><p>This buff doesn’t actually exist. Both seasons, Royal Club had upswings, in part due to synergy finally coming together, in part due to familiarity with their opponents coming to fruition, and in part due to favorable meta changes. This persistence in form carried over with them to the World Championship. The same upswing didn’t occur for Royal Never Give Up this year. Instead, they spent most of the summer split looking progressively worse.</p><p>The announcement that Uzi would return to Royal Never Give Up came after the team’s devastating defeat at the hands of SK Telecom T1 at the Mid-Season Invitational. Cho "<strong>Mata</strong>" Sehyoung <a href="http://imgur.com/oUUbc5p">informed Chinese press</a> that, if he could choose four LPL players to face SKT again, he would select himself and the rest of the existing members of RNG, with one exception — he would change the AD carry to Uzi.</p><p>Uzi rejoining Royal seemed logical on paper. Though Jang "<strong>Looper</strong>" Hyeongseok and Li "<strong>xiaohu</strong>" Yuanhao had both had impressive moments at MSI, Royal needed a closer, and Uzi’s team fight targeting could have provided that for them. For a while, it worked out, as Royal Never Give Up used raw strength to sweep through their lanes for the early part of the 2016 LPL Summer split.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/9580/cropped_looper.jpg?ts=1462908624"><figcaption>Looper at MSI (Photo: lolesports flickr)</figcaption></figure><p>Over time, however, Royal appeared increasingly strained. Their inability to close remained. For most of the regular season, they averaged a gold lead over 1700 against their opponents at 15 minutes, the highest of any team in the five major regions. Yet they tunneled on Baron. Their side wave control lacked, and Mata got caught out continuously warding on his own.</p><p>On the topic of Mata and Uzi, their synergy never seemed to truly set in. In the third game between Royal Never Give Up and EDward Gaming during the regular season, Uzi and Mata’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V5ZnpyJVw68">engage went awry</a> in part when Uzi tried to retreat while Mata had EDward Gaming AD carry Kim "<strong>deft</strong>" Hyukkyu stunned, only one of many trade-based awkward moments for the duo.</p><p>This isn&rsquo;t the first time it has taken Uzi a while for his rhythm to align with his support&rsquo;s. Yoon &quot;<strong>Zero</strong>&quot; Kyungsup often seemed to play catchup with Uzi when he would dive aggressively in 2014, and many of Uzi&rsquo;s ex-teammates from 2013&rsquo;s iteration of Royal Club remember him clashing with Wong &quot;<strong>Tabe</strong>&quot; Pakkan. In his retirement video, Royal Club top laner Xiao &quot;<strong>GodLike</strong>&quot; Wang <a href="http://www.acfun.tv/v/ac2058838">described Uzi</a> as demanding, criticizing his teammates excessively for any misplay, and when Tabe had had enough and threatened to leave, GodLike said Uzi re-directed his ire toward the team&rsquo;s jungler instead.</p><p>These factors, in addition to the perceived reduced impact of solo laners xiaohu and Looper, even when they’re over their opponents in creep totals, have resulted in several criticisms of Uzi’s stubbornness. To compound the situation, Royal’s gold distribution has drifted drastically toward Uzi in the LPL summer compared to the team’s peak form at MSI with Wang "<strong>wuxx</strong>" Cheng.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12083/cropped_royalchanges.jpg?ts=1474050054"><figcaption>Difference in percentage of team gold from tournament average. For Royal@MSI, the average is the MSI average. For Royal in LPL Summer, the average is the LPL average.</figcaption></figure><p><strong>Royal Never Give Up's Gold Distribution in MSI and LPL Summer</strong></p><figure class="article-segment--table"><div class="table-responsive"><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Role</th>
<th>Royal@MSI</th>
<th>Royal in LPL Summer</th>
<th>Difference</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Top</td>
<td>20.3</td>
<td>20.0</td>
<td>-0.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Jungle</td>
<td>21.6</td>
<td>20.2</td>
<td>-1.4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Mid</td>
<td>23.2</td>
<td>21.8</td>
<td>-1.4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>ADC</td>
<td>24.5</td>
<td>26.7</td>
<td>2.2</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Support</td>
<td>10.5</td>
<td>11.4</td>
<td>.9</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table></div></figure><p>There is certainly some validity to these criticisms. Uzi’s laning is very confrontational. When forced to choose between contesting the opponent’s last hit and last hitting his own creep, Uzi said near the end of the 2016 Spring season, "I generally choose to harass if I see the enemy AD carry will last hit. If I do this, it’s very easy to get a CS lead and pressure out the other ADC."</p><p>Part of Uzi’s struggles against SKT in the 2013 World Championship finals came when he tried to constantly play aggressively against Chae "<strong>Piglet</strong>" Gwangjin and Lee "<strong>PoohManDu</strong>" Jyeonghyeon, at times disregarding the minion flow. EDward Gaming’s bottom lane has often been able to get advantages against Royal’s despite generally better laning technique on the part of Uzi and Mata because they always prioritize pushing out the wave, while Uzi will try to trade and lose control of the flow of the minions.</p><p>Uzi also demands jungle attention. Both Uzi and jungler Baek "<strong>Swift</strong>" Daehoon affirmed that Uzi needed more jungle attention than QG Reapers’ other ADC, Yu "<strong>HappyY</strong>" Rui. "I like to go for lane trades a lot more. Because of this, our jungler will go to bot side a lot more when I’m playing," Uzi said.</p><p>GodLike, in his retirement video, also said that Uzi’s style restricted Royal Club Huang Zu from playing more split-push oriented strategies, and they could "only play raise the puppy compositions" in 2013. While these tendencies are visible, it’s also unfair to completely blame Uzi for Royal Never Give Up’s recent decline in form.</p><p>"I think that my playstyle is different [from 2013 and 2014]," Uzi said, "in that I’m much more stable than at that time … AD carries don’t really get ahead a lot in the early game. There aren’t as many opportunities to get ahead. Usually go through laning phase, then the teamfights."</p><p>Though Uzi is far from a completely different player, his approach to teamfights has become less all-in. While he will still tunnel on the ideal target and not appear to think as much about how he can get out of the fight, it happens less often than it did two years ago, and he’s become much better at managing games from behind. Mlxg’s pathing has also been somewhat more creative than one might assume given the fact that Uzi himself has said he will frequently call his jungler to his lane.</p><p>In fact, during the LPL Summer playoffs, jungler Liu “<strong>Mlxg</strong>” Shiyu ganked nine times in total in the first ten minutes of Royal Never Give Up’s games. Only two ganks went to the bottom lane. The majority of the ganks were directed toward xiaohu’s lane in mid.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/9562/cropped_xiaohu.jpg?ts=1462810289"><figcaption>Photo: lolesports flickr</figcaption></figure><p>Despite having two accounts in the Top 20 of the Korean solo queue ladder, xiaohu’s form in competitive games has been dubious. He’s made simple mistakes in trading and map positioning in the side lanes, getting caught repeatedly by EDward Gaming’s global compositions. Lissandra and Syndra, both known as strong champions for xiaohu, didn’t have the same impact as they’ve had when he has played them in the past.</p><p>Focusing more toward the mid lane may be an attempt on Royal Never Give Up’s part to give xiaohu more responsibility and confidence to carry games. So far, it isn’t working. xiaohu’s story this split has shared some similarities with that of Luck "<strong>Perkz</strong>" Perkovic’s of the EU LCS’ G2 Esports. The jungle and mid lane duo owned Royal in Spring, but he's been displaced. Two champions he relied upon heavily earlier, Azir and LeBlanc, fell out of favor, and xiaohu’s confidence plummeted, even as he was able to latch onto Taliyah.</p><p>"In my current state," <a href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/lol/news/10161">xiaohu said at the press conference</a> following the LPL final in Guangzhou, "I feel like, no matter which mid laner I face, I won't be a match for him." He has tried unsuccessfully to find a new place on a team that is increasingly bottom lane focused.</p><p>For Uzi’s successful teams in the past, the mid laner’s go-to has been Orianna. Even in an assassin-driven meta, Orianna was Wh1t3zZ's most picked champion at Worlds. Orianna was one of two champions Star Horn Royal Club mid laner Lie "<strong>corn</strong>" Wen was known to play with a high degree of competency, and at the 2014 World Championship, Orianna, Lulu and Zilean were played in 70 percent of Royal’s games.</p><p>This time around, buffs to Orianna hit on patches 6.16 and 6.17, but recent basic mistakes made by both xiaohu and Mata, two of Royal’s strongest assets at the Mid-Season Invitational, indicate it isn't likely to make a major difference. If Uzi is impacting their under-performance, it isn't directly.</p><p>The missing link for Royal, this time around, is a surge in synergy and strategy. In 2013, Tabe’s innovation with Annie support, and the team’s decision to run the duo in the mid lane to increase jungle control gave them a boost against their domestic competitors, especially the mid and jungle-centric OMG.</p><p>In 2014, despite clashes between Uzi and jungler Choi "<strong>inSec</strong>" Inseok behind the scenes, the sudden shift to the 2v2 bottom lane meta with increased dragon gold and the buffing of Lucian allowed Uzi and Zero to pressure advantages while inSec ganked bottom lane heavily. It was hard for the enemy team to punish Uzi’s over-aggression when mid lane champions like Orianna and Lulu were a staple, and the support meta swung to include the disengage and protective powers of Janna.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/8669/cropped_15327153417_6703704772_c.jpg?ts=1459284934"><figcaption>The 2014 Star Horn Royal Club (Photo: lolesports flickr)</figcaption></figure><p>2014's same perfect meta storm could come to fruition, but the thing that seems to be missing most from this iteration of Royal, however, is the ability to identify opponent tendencies and learn from them. Almost every game in the LPL this summer, Royal tunneled on the same invade-based strategies, they contested buffs, they relied on bottom lane getting ahead and hoped they could close their disorganized team fights around Baron. At this point, their play feels stale.</p><p>Though every successful iteration of Royal Club before has played around Uzi, they’ve refined their method by identifying how to destabilize their opponents. The more games they played against them, the better.</p><p>The 3-0 against OMG by Royal in the 2013 LPL Regional final wasn’t the only victory Royal had had over them that day. A nine game slog began with Royal taking the first game of the best of three against Oh My God.</p><p>Royal expected OMG's invade, presumably based on studying their VODs, and expected OMG to wait in Royal’s blue side red buff buff after laying vision. In response, Royal rushed to their own bottom side tri bush, circumventing OMG’s wards, and counter-ambushed OMG in their trap.</p><p>Royal’s efforts landed them two kills. From there, Tabe and Uzi could zone the mid lane effectively and close the game. It snowballed almost entirely off understanding Oh My God’s habits and responding to them in a creative way. Both series between OMG and Royal in the qualifier and later at the World Championship had interactions where Royal abused some of OMG’s tendencies to get the better of them.</p><p>A very similar phenomenon happened between Oh My God and Star Horn Royal Club at the 2014 World Championship. Royal Club and OMG played 12 games in playoffs and the Regional Qualifier that season prior to the World Championship. OMG bested Royal in their two best of fives in playoffs, but again lost the series that qualified Royal Club for Worlds.</p><p>In all of those 12 games, Oh My God heavily targeted inSec. Loveling invaded his jungle and denied his camps. They levied multiple bans against him, preventing him from using Kha’Zix or Lee Sin, knowing he would often then default to Jarvan IV, in which case he would engage too eagerly and trap himself to die instantly without the mobility of Kha’Zix or Lee Sin to escape.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/8672/cropped_cap.jpg?ts=1459285818"><figcaption>Oh My God at the Season 3 World Championship</figcaption></figure><p>But at Worlds, Royal had prepared specifically for this scenario. They had Pantheon and Fiddlesticks to answer for OMG’s bans, and OMG, with internal problems of their own and disagreements among their ranks, struggled to avoid the stacked teamfight composition Star Horn Royal Club ran with Fiddlesticks.</p><p>"I have often asked myself this question," OMG’s cool said earlier this year, "Why did we lose to Royal? When we played against Royal, we had less confidence than when we played against NaJin. We had lost some matches against them in the qualifier, and even before during the regular season. I think both OMG and Royal knew each others' playstyles well. When they’re well prepared, confidence matters a lot."</p><p>Both previously successful Royal Club rosters had a pluckiness to them, a determination to find small advantages and improve against opponents they had lost to many times before. Mid laner <a href="http://lol.15w.com/zt/scw09/">Wh1t3zZ recalled</a> of Royal’s 2013 run: "Before, Tabe would just go knock on [the other teams'] doors to ask if they would scrim with us. We had almost no connections. At that time, we had almost a little self-importance, but then [when we did get scrims] we basically didn’t win at all."</p><p>"Loss is a difficult thing to accept," Wh1t3zZ said, "and we also lost so much we’d fight a lot, but outside of the arguments, we all wanted to win … To sum up a bit, 34 days later, every scrim, our win rate generally increased."</p><p>In their reflections, both Wh1t3zZ and GodLike noted that in 2013, OMG refused to scrim them at the World Championship, but their laundry list of frequent scrim partners included Fnatic. By the time they faced Fnatic in the semifinals, they were well-acquainted with how Fnatic reacted to aggressive bottom lane pressure and knew to counter-pick mid laner Enrique "<strong>xPeke</strong>" Cedeño Martínez. Wh1t3zZ mentioned Royal also applied double jungling, something they had learned from OMG, to defeat Fnatic.</p><p>It’s possible, this time around, the same phenomenon can occur for Royal, but so far there hasn't been any evidence it will. They didn’t take games off their biggest domestic competitors in the LPL final or the regional this time. They didn’t display the same level of confidence or ingenuity after repeated losses to LPL's giant.</p><p>The Uzi Worlds buff doesn’t exist. There isn’t a magic incantation that will make him invincible at international events. Uzi plays to contest creeps beautifully, though sometimes at the expense of wave control or attention to the mini map. He targets well in teamfights and sometimes clashes both stylistically and argumentatively with a his teammates.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11037/cropped_2475-4061-218662.jpg?ts=1469397866"><figcaption>Photo: 刘一村</figcaption></figure><p>Uzi will and always has played his game the way he plays it. Even with the increases in consistency he has made over time, he's still Uzi. What Royal are missing this time around is the synergy that old rosters carefully developed and the perfect circumstances that allowed Royal to face the opponents with which they were most familiar in their bracket stages.</p><p>It’s still not clear what Royal will emerge from their Korean bootcamp when the World Championship begins in San Francisco, but it's clear given the stacked Group D Royal Never Give Up face, that the incline this time around is much steeper than it has ever been. To make it up the slope, they'll need more than a myth.</p><p><em>Header image credited to <a href="http://migrator.alltuu.com/albuml">刘一村</a>.</em></p><p><em>Kelsey Moser is a feature writer for theScore esports. She doesn't hate Uzi. You can <a href="http://twitter.com/karonmoser">follow her on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9825</guid>
            <title>Peace at Worlds: The subtle joys of a one-patch meta</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9825</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 20:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>Tim "Magic" Sevenhuysen</dc:creator>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/6238/w1080xh810_22650126751_dbb6d7bd6a_k.jpg?ts=1446309384">
                <media:credit>Riot eSports Flickr</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Change is good. Sometimes, though, the absence of change is even better.</p><p>League of Legends is an inherently dynamic game. Several new champions come out each year. Entire classes of champion are reworked, with items altered accordingly. Neutral objectives like dragons and towers are adjusted or completely remade. In between all of these potentially landscape-altering events, less drastic balance patches are released biweekly.</p><p>In professional play, the implications are far-reaching. A changing game can, in some ways, make for a more exciting viewer experience. Champions cycle in and out of the meta, ideally bringing some freshness with them. New strategies emerge, adding further novelty for the fans and analysts.</p><p>The downside is that teams are constantly in reaction mode, trying to hit a moving target with their preparations. Coaching staff and players invest a great deal of time into adjusting to patch changes, to see whether the latest nerfs and buffs should shift their draft and play style priorities. Fundamental skills like communication always carry over, but there is limited opportunity to refine strategies tied to specific team compositions or scenarios.</p><p>The shifting sands of the LoL<em> </em>game<em> </em>balance landscape are a basic fact of the game&rsquo;s nature. But occasionally we are given the opportunity to freeze the forward motion of the meta game, lock the professional scene into a single patch, and eagerly watch what emerges.</p><h3><strong>One patch to rule them all</strong></h3><p>Regional playoffs and international tournaments are always played on one consistent patch. In the recent summer playoffs and regional qualifiers, that patch was 6.15, with the International Wildcard Qualifiers making the jump to 6.16. At the World Championships, patch 6.18 will take over.</p><p>While 6.15 itself brought a pretty sizeable change, modifying towers to lock teams into standard 1-1-2 lane setups, not much has changed since then. There have been the usual tweaks to a variety of champions and items — minus 5 AD here, plus 10 damage per skill point there — but nothing fundamental has been altered.</p><p>This is great for two main reasons. First, the relative stability of patches 6.15 through 6.18 is a welcome relief compared to the insanity we were dealing with just one year ago, when<a href="http://na.leagueoflegends.com/en/news/game-updates/patch/patch-516-notes"> patch 5.16</a> landed.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/6240/cropped_Champs.jpg?ts=1446310386"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Worlds 2015 was the era of the “Juggernauts.” Massive reworks came in for Mordekaiser, Skarner, Darius, and others, along with some new items to complement them.</p><p>It was chaos.</p><p>With virtually no competitive games being played in the Juggernauts meta, the state of balance for the Worlds group stage was a total crapshoot. As it turned out, Mordekaiser and Gangplank were immensely over-tuned, and both had to be banned by the red side team nearly every single game. LoL had been turned upside-down. While things eventually settled down somewhat, and the final results of the tournament ultimately came down to performance, the suboptimal timing of the Juggernauts fiasco left a bad taste in many people&rsquo;s mouths.</p><p>The 2016 World Championships have deked anything on that level of insanity, and thank god for that.</p><p>Second, since we are entering Worlds 2016 with a reasonably established idea of the current meta, we will have that much more opportunity to watch one of the rarest, subtlest and yet most fascinating expressions of game mastery that exists in pro LoL<em>:</em> the evolution of a one-patch meta.</p><p>During the season, most of the adjustment and innovation that we see comes down to figuring out which champions are the most powerful at a given time. Some players or coaches excel at finding the “hidden OPs,” or “overpowered” champions that aren’t seeing much play. That power may come from a lack of difficult matchups among the champions who are currently popular, or the ability to directly counteract a champion who has so far been difficult to deal with, or maybe a power spike that fits perfectly into a certain style.</p><p>The problem is that by the time these hidden OPs have begun to emerge in any stable way, the next balance patch has often already landed. Instead of spending time truly exploring the strengths and weaknesses of the emerging cadre of champion options, the coaches and players are dragged into the beginning of another cycle of speculation and experimentation as they search for the <em>next </em>patch’s hidden OPs.</p><p>In effect, champions rarely rise and fall in the meta naturally or organically, through a process of innovation and counter-innovation by the players and teams themselves. Instead, champions mostly cycle through the meta by virtue of direct balance changes.</p><p>Naturally, this is an oversimplification. Champions do sometimes become popular without being buffed, or unpopular without being nerfed. It is possible for teams to find ways to handle the new OPs without spending bans and waiting for the nerfs to arrive, but it is relatively rare. An example from this year was the arrival of Anivia as a counterpick to Vladimir. For a while, teams who understood the proper use of Anivia had a great tool for shutting down a champion who, until then, had seemed virtually impossible to deal with. Some teams failed to use the Anivia counter properly, but it was effective in the right hands. Ultimately, though, Vladimir remained popular and Anivia faded away, not because of external influences, but because of the evolution of how teams executed on both sides of the matchup.</p><p>This type of evolution, this internal rather than external balancing of the game, is truly fascinating. And one-patch metas like the World Championships are where we get to witness it in the purest form LoL<em> </em>is able to produce.</p><h3><strong>A whole new Worlds</strong></h3><p>You may wonder why I’m disproportionately excited about Worlds being on a single patch when the playoffs and regional qualifiers were on a single patch, as well. The difference is that playoffs and regional qualifiers are somewhat distorted by “series metas.” In the playoffs, every game is part of a best-of-five. Pick and ban strategies are heavily influenced by scouting the opposing team going in, then very quickly reacting to specific things that happen from game to game.</p><p>In a tournament setting, though, the group stages are more open and fluid. There are no series metas, at least until the bracket stage: teams may prepare for one another, but not with the same focus or intensity as if they were playing a full series. Because of this, the pick and ban phases are more oriented towards a general consensus of OPs and counters. Each team learns from its opponents from day to day and week to week, and there’s time in between to make more meaningful adjustments than are possible within a single series.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/9553/cropped_26732961792_a4e8331c80_k.jpg?ts=1462725711"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>We saw an example of this evolution at the 2016 Mid-Season Invitational, as the<a href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/lol/news/7859"> ranged support meta</a> kicked in over the course of the group stage and shifted the entire dynamic of the event. The intermingling of different regional styles, combined with the stability of the environment, allowed adaptation to take place. MSI, though, was a relatively small, short event compared to the World Championships. With a two-week group stage and 16 teams, we’re likely to see even more innovation and counter-innovation taking place.</p><h3><strong>Great expectations</strong></h3><p>Over the past several weeks, we’ve already seen some natural evolutions. The rise of Kennen as a counterpick to Gnar was a long time coming, for example. A lone Skarner game from Kang “<strong>Ambition</strong>” Chan-yong in the Korean regionals was partly just an outlier, but may also be a sign of coming diversity due to a shake-up to the jungle meta after nerfs to Gragas and Rek’Sai.</p><p>These and other innovations will be put to the test when the group stage of the World Championship kicks off on Sept. 29. There will be a brief feeling-out period as teams adjust to the differences between their scrim metas, which are being shaped being closed doors as we speak, and the on-stage variations that emerge when the games actually start to count. Within a few days, the cross-pollination will begin.</p><p>At Worlds, unlike at any other point in the LoL calendar, there is enough time, and enough intensity, for teams to innovate from day to day and week to week. Teams are not confined by the time limits of series metas, and not thrown off balance by the next looming patch. On top of the other factors, the crossover between regions forces even more agility, since there are always some differences in how each league approaches the game and where they see their opportunities.</p><p>The net result is that Worlds brings about a creativity and evolution that is unique from any other part of the year.</p><p>May the best adaptors win.</p><p><em>Tim "<strong>Magic</strong>" Sevenhuysen runs </em><a href="http://oracleselixir.com/"><em>OraclesElixir.com</em></a><em>, the premier source for League of Legends esports statistics. You can <a href="http://twitter.com/TimSevenhuysen">find him </a></em><a href="http://twitter.com/TimSevenhuysen"><em>on Twitter</em></a><em>, unless he’s busy giving one of his three sons a shoulder ride.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9784</guid>
            <title>EITHER/OR with G2 Esports</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9784</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 14:08:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>theScore esports Staff</dc:creator>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11895/w1080xh810_G2-Either-Or.jpg?ts=1473432624">
                <media:credit>theScore esports</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Beach or pool? Twitter or Instagram? Lane swaps or no?</p><p>Get to know the League of Legends players of G2 Esports better in theScore esports&#39; original series: EITHER/OR!</p><h2>Trick</h2><figure class="article-segment--embed"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UM_WuMBe6I8?list=PL5aiD_mmsFojNR67f70FGDbjqlxl-aruE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure><h2>Perkz</h2><figure class="article-segment--embed"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gkiNhBleO1Y?list=PL5aiD_mmsFojNR67f70FGDbjqlxl-aruE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure><h2>Zven</h2><figure class="article-segment--embed"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tIdBVMA_jh8?list=PL5aiD_mmsFojNR67f70FGDbjqlxl-aruE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure><h2>Mithy</h2><figure class="article-segment--embed"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9RpL_yKJ1sU?list=PL5aiD_mmsFojNR67f70FGDbjqlxl-aruE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure><h2>Bonus: YoungBuck</h2><figure class="article-segment--embed"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rw1I-EzNT5I?list=PL5aiD_mmsFojNR67f70FGDbjqlxl-aruE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure><p><em>For more video interviews and highlights, be sure to subscribe to theScore esports on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCSCoziKHqjqbox3Fv3Pb4BA">YouTube</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10410</guid>
            <title>MonteCristo not invited to cast Worlds, DoA declines to attend</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10410</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 16:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/1155/w1080xh810_IMG_9006.jpg?ts=1426880414">
                <media:credit>Dennis Gonzales / theScore eSports</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>In what appears to be the latest development in an ongoing dispute between Riot Games' esports division and OGN caster Christopher "<strong>MonteCristo</strong>" Mykles, MonteCristo claims that he was deliberately excluded from the LoL World Championship casting team, which was announced Friday morning.</p><p>In an interview with <a href="http://www.espn.com/esports/story/_/id/17496928/why-montecristo-doa-cast-worlds">ESPN's Jacob Wolf</a>, <span style="line-height:1.5em"> MonteCristo said he was notified on Aug. 9 that he would not receive an invitation to the event. According to ESPN, both of MonteCristo's casting partners, </span>Erik "<strong>DoA</strong>" Lonnquist and Chris "<strong>PapaSmithy</strong>" Smith, were invited by Riot to cast the event. PapaSmithy will attend to represent the South Korea region, but DoA said in the interview that he declined due to conflicting obligations in South Korea.</p><p>"Riot decided not to invite me to this year's League of Legends World Championship," MonteCristo told Wolf. "I'm sorry to my fans that I will miss this opportunity, but pleased to say that I have upcoming casting projects that I am very excited about for the remainder of 2016."</p><p>This will be the first time MonteCristo has not been involved with Riot&#39;s Worlds broadcast since he first appeared there in 2013. It will also be the second Riot-hosted event that he sits out this year, after he and his fellow OGN casters <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/6892" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/6892">boycotted the Mid-Season Invitational</a> in March. At the time, Monte, DoA and PapaSmithy issued a joint statement claiming that Riot offered sub-standard wages to cast the event.</p><p>Riot, which announced its <a href="http://www.lolesports.com/en_US/articles/worlds-2016-air-team">casting lineup</a> for Worlds on Friday morning, has not officially commented on MonteCristo&#39;s exclusion from the list. In his ESPN interview, MonteCristo gave no details about how he was notified about the decision or the motivation behind it.</p><p>However, the caster and ex-team owner has been vocally critical of Riot&#39;s esports policies since he and his former team, Renegades, were <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/7684" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/7684">banned from the NA LCS</a> in May. In a tweet following the ESPN report Friday, he implied that his exclusion from Worlds was related to his past conflicts with Riot&#39;s esports team.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I wish that the Riot league ops team and I could have buried the hatchet, but no dice.<br><br>Sorry to my fans that I won’t be at Worlds.</p>— MonteCristo (@MonteCristo) <a href="https://twitter.com/MonteCristo/status/776792001144557568">September 16, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>In social media and in the press, MonteCristo <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9416" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9416">has argued</a> that Riot&#39;s decision to ban Renegades was unfair and non-transparent, claiming that the publisher did not give him an adequate opportunity to present a defense before issuing its ruling. Riot banned Renegades over its alleged connections with banned former team owner Chris Badawi, as well as alleged mistreatment of players and collusion with Team Dragon Knights. </p><p>MonteCristo, as the team&#39;s owner, was banned for one year from owning a team that participates in any Riot-sanctioned league, though the ruling stated it would not affect his casting career with OGN, which is not owned by Riot. In August, MonteCristo sold Renegades, which still operates CS:GO and Call of Duty teams, to <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/10128" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10128">Celtics forward Jonas Jerebko</a>.</p><p>In his most recent comments about Riot &mdash; which were published after MonteCristo claims Riot notified him he was not invited to Worlds &mdash; the caster vehemently criticized the company and its co-founder, Marc &quot;<strong>Tryndamere</strong>&quot; Merrill, over the way it controls sponsorship in the LCS. Among other criticisms, he accused Riot of playing favorites with league teams and owners, comparing the company to a &quot;<a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9984" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9984">f**cked up tyrant Santa Claus</a>&quot; that doles out rewards and punishments to teams it considers &quot;good&quot; or &quot;bad.&quot;</p><p>In a <a href="https://twitter.com/MonteCristo/status/776806538019151872">tweet Friday</a> following ESPN&#39;s report, MonteCristo said that further criticism would be forthcoming. &quot;Now that I have zero business ties to Riot, I will be releasing many vlogs on my experiences with the company when I get back from vacation,&quot; he said.</p><p>Though MonteCristo and DoA's fans will not get a chance to see them at Worlds, <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/10407" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10407">the two are set to cast</a> OGN's new $170,000 Overwatch league, Overwatch APEX, beginning in October. They will also continue to broadcast OGN's coverage of League Champions Korea in 2017.</p><p><em>Sasha Erfanian is a news editor for theScore esports. <a href="https://twitter.com/SashaErfanian">Follow him on Twitter</a>, it'll be great for his self-esteem.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10385</guid>
            <title>The Offscreen Play: Sencux and Splyce's slow build</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10385</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 14:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11223/w1080xh810_spy.jpg?ts=1470050752">
                <media:credit>EU LCS / lolesports flickr</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>When the skirmish started, jungler Jonas &quot;<strong>Trashy</strong>&quot; Andersen was already dead. Caught over-extending on top side of the map, Fnatic&rsquo;s jungler Lee &quot;<strong>Spirit</strong>&quot; Dayoon had lost his engage ultimate by using Hecarim&#39;s Onslaught of Shadows to pursue the kill.</p><p>But Fnatic were 3,000 gold ahead at the 25 minute mark. They had Splyce’s blue buff area pink warded and had a man advantage. After Martin "<strong>Rekkles</strong>" Larsson and Mateusz "<strong>Kikis</strong>" Szkudlarek pursued Splyce’s bottom lane into the choke point between the blue buff and the wolves camp, Fabian "<strong>Febiven</strong>" Diepstraten Teleport flanked from the blue buff bush on Karma. His combo and Rekkles’ ultimate almost completely eliminated Kasper "<strong>Kobbe</strong>" Kobberup’s health bar. Rekkles used Arcane Shift, his one remaining escape after the burn of his flash, to secure the kill over the blue buff wall.</p><p>That’s when it became obvious that — somehow — Rekkles had also lost most of his health bar. While the rest of Fnatic collapsed onto Kobbe and Mihael "<strong>Mikyx</strong>" Mehle, Splyce’s mid laner Chres "<strong>Sencux</strong>" Laursen had stayed off camera. All the audience witnessed was the particles of a Force Pulse from the corner of the screen while Rekkles lost 80 percent of his health.</p><p>Perhaps, after that, Rekkles already knew he was dead, but his Arcane Shift trapped him in the blue buff area with Splyce&#39;s top laner, Martin &quot;<strong>Wunder</strong>&quot; Hansen. When Sencux&rsquo;s Kassadin joined him via Riftwalk, the entire game upended. Febiven&rsquo;s too-close-to-the-wall positioning made Wunder&rsquo;s Fiora Lunge a technicality, and Splyce&rsquo;s solo laners duo tore through Fnatic&rsquo;s final carry threat while Mikyx performed feats of distraction against Spirit&rsquo;s Hecarim.</p><p>Just like this teamfight, Splyce&rsquo;s climb up the European LCS rankings was a late surprise. Some of their greatest feats take place on the mini map or just off the screen in a teamfight, making it easy to underrate their individual skills. The patience of Sencux&rsquo;s Kassadin, spotting the opening in Fnatic&rsquo;s drawn out chase, won Splyce only one of countless games from behind.</p><p>Yet people have referred to Splyce as a team of only moderate talents that win games through macro play. </p><p>"I think if you don't have good individual players then you're not going to win that many games," Sencux said. "Macro play is a big thing, but now it's [that] you need both macro and individual skill."</p><p>There are players who tunnel on the laning phase and find the concept of winning the game with a deficit daunting, and then there's Splyce,<a href="http://oracleselixir.com"> a team that's averaged a gold deficit</a> of around 1.5k in the playoffs and 49 in the regional qualifier at 15 minutes despite placing second in the former and winning the latter. Splyce have become a patient team who use their knowledge of the map to look for openings and flex their skill later in the game.</p><p>From Sencux, a mid lane prodigy who was heralded for his explosive Ahri play coming from the EU CS, it wasn’t what we expected — especially not what he demonstrated at the start of the year.</p><p>In <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZMB10PCResw">Sencux&rsquo;s first EU LCS game</a>, he locked in Varus, who at the time was a relatively immobile pick that safely cleared waves under the comfort of his own turret. He faced off against Unicorns of Love&rsquo;s Hampus &quot;<strong>Fox</strong>&quot; Myrhe&#39;s Zed, hardly daring to contest creeps in the unfavorable matchup. Even when Fox disappeared to gank bottom, Sencux remained fearfully hugging his turret.</p><p>Simply put, Sencux struggled to find the confidence to make plays when he first entered the EU LCS.</p><p>"It can be not wanting to [make] mistakes, it can be — I see some player playing a bit aggro, I sometimes think they definitely have support behind them, even though I know they shouldn't, so I would play further back than I normally would have. I think that was the main problem," he said.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12000/cropped_sencux.jpg?ts=1473923874"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Even in better matchups, though Sencux would push out further in lane, his impact wouldn’t feel as strong. It wasn't until Splyce’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xC8zDnEz5jM">fourth EU LCS game</a> against Team ROCCAT that the audience caught a glimpse of the Sencux that has become more commonplace in the EU LCS.</p><p>ROCCAT had already lost both of their outer turrets in the side lanes. After picking up his blue buff, Sencux saw an opportunity to use his Ahri Charm against Karim &quot;<strong>Airwaks</strong>&quot; Benghalia and Felix &quot;<strong>Betsy</strong>&quot; Edling. The two of them had pushed far up on Splyce&rsquo;s mid-tier outer turret, and Sencux capitalized on their greed for a kill in what turned into Splyce&rsquo;s first LCS win.</p><p>Top laner <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/8310" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/8310">Wunder credits </a>a lot of Splyce&rsquo;s improvements to the spring split, despite their poor placement, as their rookie season paved the way to their second place summer split finish and helped them better understand macro play.</p><p>"You need to know what will happen next," he said. "You need to know what the team you're playing will do next and how to force something on that play. ... We would fall behind and then just slowly lose."</p><p>While Sencux’s reflection on the spring split included Wunder’s point about their weaker macro understanding, he had an addendum. </p><p>"Personally in the spring, after we qualified for LCS, I could have played a lot more and sometimes in lane I could have done a lot more than I did in spring," he said. "I didn't work as hard in the offseason as I could have because I had like a five months’ break, and I didn't know what to do."</p><p>Compared to Luka &quot;<strong>Perkz</strong>&quot; Perković&#39;s explosion onto the pro scene, Sencux&rsquo;s showings were disappointing. While the spring regular season ended with analysts hotly debating whether Perkz or his teammate, jungler Kim &quot;<strong>Trick</strong>&quot; Gangyun, deserved the MVP award, Sencux&rsquo;s hot-and-cold performances were a distant memory as Splyce dropped into the Promotion Tournament.</p><p>In part because of Perkz&rsquo;s successes as another rookie from the EU CS, Sencux constantly felt that he could do better.</p><p>&quot;I just wanted to work harder,&quot; he said. &quot;[After the start of spring], I played so much every single day. When we got to scrims in the summer, I felt I was a lot better of a player.&quot;</p><p>As a pro player, taking a five-month break and missing out on game updates can be trying. Sencux felt it was nearly fatal, and his struggles were a lesson in humility. "I think just playing a lot more and knowing matchups in and out and knowing that, just because you're on stage and people are watching, you can't play differently," he said.</p><p>Repeated play on stage helped Sencux accept that mistakes will happen. If he felt confident in a matchup from solo queue or scrims, he just had to overcome the stage fright that went hand-in-hand with the need to get ahead early.</p><p>It’s surprising, in light of the way Splyce played in the EU LCS this summer, that Sencux used to struggle with keeping a clear head when the laning phase didn't go his way. Playing with the jungler giving attention to different lanes is a relatively new development for Sencux. </p><p>"I can play with a lot of jungle pressure," Sencux said. “In the past, it was what I usually played. Now I don't mind just playing to maybe not win the lane, but go even.”</p><p>For Sencux, there’s a clear turning point when he realized that being stubborn and unwilling to work from a lane disadvantage wouldn’t cut it. </p><p>"I remember specifically one game in a scrim a long time ago where I just kept going forward [after dying to a gank], and that kind of backfired because I kept dying and dying and dying. It doesn't work like that. I would say I could tilt in the past, but that doesn't happen anymore," he said.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/10779/cropped_sencux.jpg?ts=1468106011"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Sencux projects a relatively calm demeanor as he talks about some of the changes in his attitude. Despite being exhausted from travel when he talks to me, he answers patiently. The image of the meandering Splyce from earlier this year that either closed games with a fed Sencux boasting more than five kills or not at all is an image many of Splyce&#39;s critics still hold onto.</p><p>A difference between the Challenger Series and spring split Splyce and summer Splyce may seem like a revolution, but it isn&rsquo;t. Much as how the team wins many of their games from behind, they have doggedly built their success, looking for small advantages and openings. Sencux&rsquo;s perspective has slowly altered along with it.</p><p>"The main thing I tried to work on throughout the challenger series was trying not to be that emotional and try not to be effected by a lot of random shit," Sencux says. He also had advice for other players with similar hang-ups. "Accept that you make a mistake was the first thing, and if you get mad and say something bad to a teammate, then apologize for it and move on."</p><p>This more patient Sencux defines the success that Splyce have been able to achieve this split. The sweeping comeback against Fnatic in the first game of their second summer split encounter is only one example of the team finding openings from a deficit.</p><p>Watching Sencux, he looks for openings in flanks or ways to apply pressure in a side lane. These plays are harder to highlight than a 1v1 outplay in the laning phase, but certainly require a high amount of intelligence and technique. A lot of pro players, including his teammate Wunder, have said it&rsquo;s easiest to judge another player by how they play in lane. Sencux, who <a href="http://oracleselixir.com">averaged a CS deficit</a> of 7.9 in the playoffs, 3.8 in regular season, and 4.6 in his regional qualifying series, might be harder to point out as an intimidating opponent in a direct matchup.</p><p>When the sore subject of the laning phase comes up, Sencux admits it’s still one of the team's flaws. "I just think sometimes the way we pressure [doesn’t have] the best timings," he said. "Obviously it's something that we have to work on." According to Sencux and jungler Trashy, this will be a major focus of their Korean boot camp.</p><p>But one of Splyce's strengths is their ability to admit this flaw, at least temporarily. Splyce had a successful Game 1 against Unicorns of Love by relying on Taliyah, but in Game 2, they failed to exert any early pressure, and Sencux’s Taliyah ended with a 0/0/0 score line.</p><p>&quot;This series, I kind of realized there&#39;s no point in playing to their strength,&quot; Sencux said, praising Unicorns of Love&#39;s early game, &quot;so I wanted to stall out the early game and get to mid game by playing Malzahar.&quot;</p><p>Keeping a clear head and admitting when something isn’t working has made Splyce’s series play impressive. In the second game against G2 in the EU LCS final, they answered Perkz’s pesky Ekko pick with Vladimir to counter the matchup and they were rewarded with their only win of the series.</p><p>In general, Sencux still sees Perkz as a strong rival despite meta changes making Perkz’s play appear more unstable. But if there’s something that might give him an edge, Sencux thinks "maybe it's been playing new champions that seem to rise up in priority first, realizing when they're actually good or not. We were one of the first to play Taliyah … and Kassadin."</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11981/cropped_29464007251_8880ef7306_k.jpg?ts=1473723016"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>If there’s a takeaway for me from Splyce’s summer, it’s their adaptability and resourcefulness. Their toolkit, from champion picks to the way they see the game is vast. Though still a very young team, Splyce excel more when backed into a corner. If there’s an opponent out of position or a free objective for the taking, Splyce will react almost immediately.</p><p>But critics will dwell on Splyce&rsquo;s laning phase or their struggles playing around the bottom side of the map. Trashy, like Sencux, acknowledged that these are both things they&rsquo;re trying to work on while in Korea.</p><p>"A lot of teams," Trashy said, "They are really good at playing around bot, while we are not as good. I think it really showed in our final against G2 where we couldn’t play around bot as we wanted to in some cases. We have really good synergy around top, mid, jungle where we understand each other really well. We just need to put it on another level."</p><p>Sencux admits that they only adapted in the Unicorns of Love series to play more in their comfort zone because they couldn&rsquo;t fix major problems between games. But with some teams at Worlds (specifically Royal Never Give Up, a team in Splyce&#39;s group) looking to snowball the laning phase despite an inability to closeout games, they might find Splyce&#39;s knack for identifying openings and capitalizing with their solo laners surprising.</p><p>Several analysts and pros have referred to the increased importance of the laning phase as something that will be Worlds' deciding point. But even after admitting it’s a problem for Splyce, Sencux rated laning phase overall much lower in importance than expected. </p><p>"I don't think [laning phase] is everything in the game. I think that's like 30 percent," he said.</p><p>Splyce are a team that have taken the concept of reactive play very seriously. They study their opponents and can anticipate the mistakes they are prone to making. I&rsquo;m personally skeptical that they&rsquo;ll be able to fix their laning phase woes in time for Worlds, but with the importance of supports and mid laners coordinating with their junglers, direct 1v1s have been overvalued.</p><p>Relative to expectations, Splyce are late bloomers, but they didn’t let their spring failures loom over them this summer, and they don’t let gold deficits discourage them. Splyce will make their Group D opponents fight for every win, just as they’ve fought for recognition this Summer.</p><p>Attention-grabbing, laning phase bulldozers can be terrifying, but Splyce’s deadliest work won’t be at the center of the spectator. Key moments for Splyce will happen on the fringe of a team fight or in movements on the mini map. They’ll pray on your over-confidence, because they what it’s like to have been knocked down.</p><p>For Sencux and Splyce, this year has been a slow build. For every player on the team, 2016 will mark their first World Championship. Sencux’s expectations are modest. </p><p>"The biggest thing for me is going to Korea and scrim teams and play Korean solo queue. I just want to take as much from it as possible and try to get out of groups. So it's fine for me just using it as a learning experience," he said.</p><p>But if Splyce do surprise, it won’t be quick and decisive. It will be almost 30 minutes in from at least a 3,000 gold deficit. An internationally experienced AD carry like Yiliang "<strong>Doublelift</strong>" Peng or Jian "<strong>Uzi</strong>" Zihao who beat down the Splyce bottom lane in the early game, for a split second, won’t check his flank...</p><p>And in a moment, he’ll be eliminated, gutted by a Force Pulse from just off screen.</p><p><em>Data from <a href="http://oracleselixir.com">OraclesElixir.com</a>.</em></p><p><em>Kelsey Moser is a feature writer for theScore esports. you can <a href="http://twitter.com/karonmoser">follow her on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10402</guid>
            <title>UCI League of Legends team to feature former Team Vulcun support BloodWater
            </title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10402</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 23:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12012/w1080xh810_esports_160913_01_sz.jpg?ts=1473980540">
                <media:credit>University of California at Irvine</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>The University of California at Irvine is <a href="https://news.uci.edu/science-and-tech/ics/uci-to-launch-esports-arena-introduce-first-ever-varsity-league-of-legends-players/">set to launch an esports arena</a> with a new League of Legends roster that features former Team Vulcun support Lyubomir &quot;<strong>BloodWater</strong>&quot; Spasov.</p><p>UCI's esports scholarship program is similar to most university's traditional sports scholarships, with top LoL players receiving scholarships to study at the university while playing on their collegiate teams. According to a press release, BloodWater has been awarded a scholarship for the school's computer science. </p><p>"UCI’s new eSports program gives talented League of Legends players the opportunity to study what they love and to continue their passion for competitive gaming," BloodWater stated in the press release. "When I heard about the scholarship, I was very happy to know that I had a chance to attend one of the best universities in California – or anywhere – and to earn a degree in computer science.”</p><p>BloodWater is best known for his time on Team Vulcun, with whom he attended the Season 3 World Championships in 2013. The team placed third in the 2013 NA LCS Summer Playoffs, qualifying them for Worlds. Vulcun went on to place 11th-12th after placing second in their group with a 3-5 record.</p><p>The university has three other members of their LoL team set. The players are Youngbin Chung (Mid), James Lattman (ADC), Loc Tran (ADC) and Parsa "<strong>Frostalicious</strong>" Baghai (Jungle). The team will hold tryouts for a top laner starting Sept. 26.</p><p>“We’re honored to work with UCI to create a permanent home for gamers on campus and hope this will inspire similar programs at colleges and universities across North America,” Riot Games' head of collegiate esports Ramon Hermann stated in the press release.</p><p><em>Daniel Rosen is a news editor for theScore esports. <a href="http://twitter.com/daniel_rosen">You can follow him on Twitter.</a></em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9823</guid>
            <title>theScore esports' top players at the LoL World Championship 2016</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9823</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 15:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>theScore esports Staff</dc:creator>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12006/w1080xh810_maxresdefault.jpg?ts=1473954187">
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>With the 2016 League of Legends World Championship just around the corner, we asked our LoL experts to break down who they see as the strongest players ahead of the biggest tournament of the year. This year, we have commentary from <strong><a href="https://twitter.com/karonmoser">Kelsey Moser</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/leagueofemily">Emily Rand</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/TimSevenhuysen">Tim Sevenhuysen</a>.</strong></p><h3><strong>The Criteria</strong></h3><p><strong>Kelseys&#39; criteria:</strong> This year&#39;s player rankings were far from simple. Reconciling players who have traditionally been dominating with their current form is never easy. That&#39;s a big part of why, this time around, I decided to heavily devalue longevity. We&#39;ve done several rankings of great players in history and the past, but at Worlds it&#39;s important to understand which players will heavily influence the outcome of the game. While players like Mata are incredible, they haven&#39;t been this summer, and they aren&#39;t expected to be at Worlds.</p><p>I also chose to take this summer split more holistically. This lead to removing players who I expect to perform very well at Worlds like FORG1VEN. By not playing most of the split, it&#39;s difficult to praise FORG1VEN for consistency throughout Summer, a quality I find important, as it will give some indication of whether a player will perform well under pressure at Worlds.</p><p><strong>Emily's criteria: </strong>My criteria hasn’t changed from when I ranked players at the past <a data-in-app-uri="" href="">2016 Mid-Season Invitationa</a><a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/7557" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/7557">l</a>. I value flexibility and adaptability very highly. For me, the ability to play at a consistently high level across multiple iterations of an ever-changing game is something that separates the very best from simply being good. Recent performances are weighted a bit higher than the player’s full career since this is a list of the best players at the World Championship, but their entire body of work is also considered. This is likely where my list will stand out against Tim and Kelsey’s picks. The road that each team took to qualify and players’ importance to the team’s success is also considered as a deciding factor.</p><p><strong>Tim's criteria: </strong>As I wrote when ranking players for the Mid-Season Invitational, when I’m ranking players, I tend to look at each player’s ability to be game-breaking, consistent, and versatile. By “game-breaking,” I mean playmaking and carry potential. I want to see a player go out and individually create wins, either through their own strength or by enabling their teammates in notable ways. By “consistent,” I mean the player’s ability to maintain their level of play without mixing in too many big mistakes or throwing away advantages. By “versatile,” I mean both the ability to fill different roles (supporting or carrying, damage or tank, engage or disengage, etc.) and the ability to adapt to changing metas and quickly pick up new champions and play styles.</p><h3><strong>Top 15</strong></h3><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/10795/cropped_2408-3979-214698.jpg?ts=1468239428"><figcaption>Photo: 一村</figcaption></figure><figure class="article-segment--table"><div class="table-responsive"><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Rank</th>
<th> Kelsey</th>
<th> Emily</th>
<th> Tim</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>15</td>
<td> mithy</td>
<td> Doublelift</td>
<td> Ziv</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>14</td>
<td> Impact</td>
<td> Karsa</td>
<td> Mata</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>13</td>
<td> Uzi</td>
<td> Zven</td>
<td> Zven</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>12</td>
<td> SwordArt</td>
<td> Uzi</td>
<td> Uzi</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>11</td>
<td> Trick</td>
<td> Maple</td>
<td> Impact</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table></div></figure><p><strong>Kelsey: </strong>After winning Europe two splits in a row primarily off executing a high degree of talent, G2 players deserved representation on a list. This time around, G2 have adapted to a new style of side lane pressure, and mithy&#39;s high level of consistency as a roamer begged mention, as did Trick&#39;s efficiency and malleability playing multiple styles in the jungle.</p><p>Between them, I included Impact, not just for his gauntlet showing, but impressive performances throughout the split. Cloud9 struggled to provide resources for him in lane swaps, and he still delivered. Uzi may be a surprise, but he&#39;s been the most individually consistent member of Royal Never Give Up despite drastic peaks and troughs in form for the other members. Any judgements of his impact on the dynamic can&#39;t deny his individual skill level. SwordArt is ranked 12th for his importance in double-timing Flash Wolves&#39; side lanes while his team&#39;s jungle and mid get ahead.</p><p><strong>Emily: </strong>This is where things are the muddiest, and I can easily see the argument for moving any of these players a few spots up or down on the list. Basically, here’s where this is more of a suggested strong players to watch for, rather than a definitive ranking of the top 15 best. Maple and Karsa have helped keep the Flash Wolves at the top of the LMS, even as SwordArt slumped a bit this season, and deserve your attention. Uzi now attends his third World Championship in the past four years, but RNG has been in complete disarray this split despite their incredible assembly of talent. Doublelift had a career-best showing for TSM in NA LCS Summer, as did Zven over in Europe for G2. </p><p>Some honorable mentions (in no certain order) include: Impact, Crown, Duke, Ziv, PraY, Mithy.</p><p><strong>Tim: </strong>Impact’s eye-catching postseason was enough to land him a spot on my list. I was an Impact appreciator before that, having <a href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/lol/news/9663">voted for him as first-team NA LCS top laner</a>, and his continued growth has been fun to watch. Right behind him are a pair of AD carries, Uzi and Zven. RNG set up many parts of their play to enable Uzi. The payoff is huge: his performances can reach some of the highest highs in the world. The amount of resources he requires is a downside, though. Zven, for his part, is a really good damage dealer and laner, but is sometimes vulnerable to getting picked off. He relies on Mithy to keep him safe, a function Mithy fills very well. The gap between Zven and Uzi is small, but I give the Chinese player the edge. </p><p>At 14, Mata’s placement may seem surprising, but his play has dipped while working with Uzi. There have been more mistakes and less coordination with the rest of the team. Still, this is Mata: at any given moment, he can take over a game. Finally, Ziv gets my last nod for his role in carrying AHQ so consistently from the top lane.</p><p>As honorable mentions, I’d include GorillA, Crown, Duke, mithy, and Road. There’s so much talent at this tournament that many different laners could justifiably deserve a spot, but every list has a cut-off somewhere!</p><h3><strong>Top 10</strong></h3><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/10952/cropped_GorillA6.jpg?ts=1468871510"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><figure class="article-segment--table"><div class="table-responsive"><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Rank</th>
<th> Kelsey</th>
<th> Emily</th>
<th> Tim</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>10</td>
<td> Crown</td>
<td> Bang</td>
<td> Bang</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>9</td>
<td> Peanut</td>
<td> Deft</td>
<td> meiko</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>8</td>
<td> Maple</td>
<td> GorillA</td>
<td> Peanut</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7</td>
<td> GorillA</td>
<td> meiko</td>
<td> Trick</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>6</td>
<td> meiko</td>
<td> Trick</td>
<td> Maple</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table></div></figure><p><strong>Kelsey: </strong>Some have dared to refer to Crown as the second-best mid laner in the world, and while I&#39;ve ranked others more highly, his individual form has been a highlight. He hasn&#39;t been as consistent as some others on the list, but he&#39;s a major reason for Samsung&#39;s success. He&#39;s beaten out in part by Maple who has continued to refine with age and make his team an international contender.</p><p>Peanut&#39;s place will hardly be contested. Aside from not seeming to know the location of his opponent as intimately as the top-rated jungler on this list, the Tigers are a team of strong players, and Peanut rounds out its top three.</p><p>The most contentious placing here may be meiko over GorillA. Both supports are fundamental to their teams&#39; successes, but meiko&#39;s form has been more consistent, especially with some of GorillA&#39;s misplays earlier in the season. meiko&#39;s warding and roaming technique also makes clearlove&#39;s style of jungling possible.</p><p><strong>Emily: </strong>Trick is the backbone of G2 Esports, and it’s safe to say that they wouldn’t be the team that they are without him. The best jungler in Europe, Trick has had a fantastic split and led G2 to a second EU LCS title — alongside the team’s new bot lane of Zven and mithy — despite inconsistent performances from mid laner Perkz and top laner Expect. This is why Trick is higher than other key players in this bracket including the two best supports at this tournament, meiko and GorillA. GorillA has a longer history and larger career, but meiko has been the star support of the LPL, overtaking Mata, who slumped significantly this past summer.</p><p>Throughout SKT’s struggles this split, Bang was a constant alongside Faker. While he hasn’t had the dazzling outplays that characterised his spring performances — and are currently a hallmark of the Deft and meiko bot lane — he plays at a consistently high level that his team has come to rely on, even when their lack of jungle pressure allows opponents to push SKT back.</p><p><strong>Tim: </strong>I’m not the biggest fan of the Flash Wolves’ chances as a whole, but I love me some Maple. He does so many things so well, and he’ll need to be at his best to give his team a chance to progress in the tournament. Trick and Peanut are both great players, but I ranked Trick slightly ahead because he is more crucial to his team’s success. Peanut has rounded into a somewhat more complete player than he was in the spring, but he still lets some recklessness and inconsistency creep in now and then. </p><p>My highest-ranked support is meiko because of how well he knows his role and executes on it. He does a great job of enabling Deft, tending to play tanky supports that allow him to defend his carry and be a disruptive presence. At 10, I have Bang. He’s a great laner and a powerful carry — he led the LCK in DPM this summer — but he hasn’t been getting enough consistency from his teammates in top and jungle. With a bootcamp under SKT’s belt, I expect Bang to again show up as one of the world’s best ADCs.</p><h3><strong>Top 5</strong></h3><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11497/cropped_smeblaughing.jpg?ts=1471545987"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><figure class="article-segment--table"><div class="table-responsive"><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Rank</th>
<th> Kelsey</th>
<th> Emily</th>
<th> Tim</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>5</td>
<td> Bjergsen</td>
<td> clearlove</td>
<td> Bjergsen</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4</td>
<td> clearlove</td>
<td> Bjergsen</td>
<td> deft</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3</td>
<td> deft</td>
<td> Peanut</td>
<td> clearlove</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2</td>
<td> Faker</td>
<td> Faker</td>
<td> Smeb</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>1</td>
<td> Smeb</td>
<td> Smeb</td>
<td> Faker</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table></div></figure><p><strong>Kelsey: </strong>If ever a Western player deserved to make Top 5, it's Bjergsen. He's been flexible, consistent, and has used intelligent trades in lane that should make him contend with Eastern giants at this event. Though TSM's style has diversified, he's still the soul of a team that is projected to perform incredibly well this year.</p><p>Both clearlove and deft making Top 5 may raise eyebrows, but these are two incredibly gifted players who have never had a better split. clearlove has been able to combine both the more reckless play from last spring and his calculated emphasis on farming with the aid of meiko's warding. deft is entering a World Championship in a meta that should favor him with a support that complements him well after a summer in which he demolished his LPL competitors.</p><p>Faker and Smeb top the list for obvious reasons, though given my criteria of consistency and recent performance, Smeb has to take the top. Though Faker is the greatest player of all time and has, despite hiccups, still performed well this summer, Smeb's ruthlessness and fundamental importance to Tigers can easily make him Worlds' MVP. He's the player of the entire summer split and the player I think will perform best at Worlds.</p><p><strong>Emily: </strong>This may come as a shock to some — and by no means does it take away Faker’s title as the best League of Legends player in the history of the game — but for this past split, Smeb was the best top laner in the world, and also the best player. The rise of Smeb has run parallel to the rise of the Tigers, with their top laner surpassing the one and only Faker as the best player in the world going into Worlds.</p><p>Also likely to be contentious are Peanut and Bjergsen’s placements at three and four. Yes, Peanut did not perform to the top-tier level he is capable of in the recent LCK Summer 2016 Finals against Score and KT Rolster. But Score isn’t here, and Peanut’s jungling was the missing piece that the Tigers needed to become the best team in the world — that’s how integral he has been across both splits for this team.</p><p>Similarly, despite Doublelift’s phenomenal bot lane performances, I’m not sure if Team SoloMid would be at the World Championship without Bjergsen — that’s how important he is to his team’s success. This past year, his adaptability, stunning teamfighting. and constant pressure in and out of lane have allowed TSM breathing room on multiple occasions, even as their team was struggling to adapt. More recently, he’s taken a backseat to Doublelift in hard carry potential, but still controls TSM’s teamfights and provides Svenskeren significant pressure from the mid lane, allowing the TSM jungler to go where he pleases.</p><p>Smeb and Peanut make the Tigers who they are today, Faker is SKT, Bjergsen is TSM and lastly, EDG is clearlove.</p><p><strong>Tim: </strong>Faker’s trademark aggression and proactivity haven’t waned — he still treats every champion like an assassin, and finds much more individual success than failure. The problem is that he hasn’t had enough help in the playmaking department to buy him time and space, but that’s a team issue, not a Faker issue. In my opinion, he is still the best player in the world. </p><p>That said, Smeb is hotter on Faker’s heels than anyone has been for a very long time. He wins his lane, moves smoothly around the map, and is effective on both carries and tanks. There’s no debate that Smeb is the world’s best top laner by a wide margin. I rank clearlove number three because of his central importance to EDward Gaming. He’s arguably the best jungler in the world, based on how effective he is at both carrying games himself and creating snowballs for his laners, particularly deft. If we’re lucky, we’ll get to see clearlove on his signature Evelynn. </p><p>Speaking of deft, he’s in world class form, and is thriving in a team environment where he gets help from meiko and clearlove to enable his high-pressure laning. He rewards those resources beautifully, with some of the best AD carry team fighting in the world. To round out my top five, I’m looking to Bjergsen. He’s less flashy than Faker, but it’s very impressive how well Bjergsen can suck up pressure in the mid lane while still influencing the entire map and making all of his teammates look good.</p><h3><strong>Aggregate exercise </strong></h3><p>As a final exercise, we've combined all three lists to create an aggregate Top 15. Players were awarded points based on how highly they ranked in each list. The only tie occurred between Zven and Crown, and the 14th place was awarded to Zven as he appeared on two lists (Emily and Tim's), while Crown appeared only on Kelsey's.</p><figure class="article-segment--table"><div class="table-responsive"><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Rank</th>
<th>Player</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>1</td>
<td> Smeb</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2</td>
<td> Faker</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3</td>
<td> clearlove</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4</td>
<td> Bjergsen</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5</td>
<td> deft</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>6</td>
<td> Peanut</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7</td>
<td> meiko</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>8</td>
<td> Trick</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>9</td>
<td> Maple</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>10</td>
<td> GorillA</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>11</td>
<td> Bang</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>12</td>
<td> Uzi</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>13</td>
<td> Impact</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>14</td>
<td> Zven</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>15</td>
<td> Crown</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table></div></figure><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10386</guid>
            <title>Steeelback leaves ROCCAT</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10386</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 12:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/10295/w1080xh810_steeelback.jpg?ts=1466265557">
                <media:credit>EU LCS / lolesports flickr</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Team ROCCAT AD carry Pierre &quot;<strong>Steeelback</strong>&quot; Medjaldi has left, according to a Facebook post made by the team Thursday.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><iframe src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FTEAMROCCAT%2Fposts%2F509416755920016&amp;width=500" width="500" height="502" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></figure><p>The player made a <a href="https://www.facebook.com/Steeelback/photos/a.711358265585180.1073741829.704055519648788/1073113679409635/?type=3">farewell post on Facebook</a> and hinted that he&#39;s found a new team in Europe.</p><p>&quot;Regarding 2017, I can already tell that I&#39;ll be staying in Europe,&quot; he said. &quot;I&#39;ve been playing for a lot of teams during my career, but I really hope that I am going to stay there for a long time. I want to build something strong to be able to compete on the world&#39;s stage next year and I&#39;ll do everything possible to achieve that goal.&quot;</p><p>The French ADC joined <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/7595" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/7595">ROCCAT on May 3</a> to compete in the EU LCS 2016 Summer Season, but the team performed poorly and finished in last place with a 2-6-10 record.</p><p>ROCCAT were forced to compete in the 2017 Spring Promotion series, but after a 3-2 win over Millennium in the Elimination Round and a 3-1 win over Schalke 04 in the Qualifying Round, they retained their spot in the EU LCS.</p><p>Steeelback played 36 games as part ROCCAT, and his most played Champions were Jhin and Lucian, both played 11 times. His Lucian had a KDA of 7.00 averaged across all games, while his Jhin had a 6.44.</p><p><em>Dennis "<strong>Tarmanydyn</strong>" Gonzales is a news editor for theScore esports who enjoys whiskey, D&amp;D and first-picking <s>Abaddon</s> <s>Slardar</s> <s>Clinkz</s> <s>Medusa</s> <s>Oracle</s> <s>a</s> <s>P90</s> my Souvenir Negev. <a href="http://twitter.com/Tarmanydyn">You can follow him on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9824</guid>
            <title>Meiko or Break: Why EDward Gaming's support is their MVP</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9824</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 20:08:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11944/w1080xh810_2683-4311-239086.jpg?ts=1473589076">
                <media:credit>刘一村 / LPL / 刘一村's album</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>When trying to assess the most valuable player on a team, a common pitfall is to look for its best player. For a team like EDward Gaming, support Tian "<strong>meiko</strong>" Ye is rarely considered next to giants like Kim "<strong>deft</strong>" Hyukkyu and Ming "<strong>clearlove</strong>" Kai. clearlove has gained a lot of international recognition thanks to a meta that celebrates strong junglers, while deft, as ADC, deals<a href="http://www.wanplus.com/lol/playerstats"> 32.1 percent of his team’s damage</a> on average. </p><p>They are certainly EDward Gaming’s strongest individual players. But the advantages they are able to consistently turn into wins don't come from nowhere. Arguably, a team's MVP is the player who controls the flow of the game and creates the most opportunities for the team to succeed — who is able to set up and create multiple openings for victory. For EDward Gaming, that person is meiko.</p><p>Based on how much recognition clearlove has been getting recently, the natural conclusion made by someone who hasn't watched a lot of EDG matches is that he's a heavy play-making jungler. But it's his followup plays that truly stand out. As a jungler, clearlove focuses much more on farming and counter-ganking, turning the bottom lane after an opponent's engagement. When he controls the enemy jungle, he does so only after vision has been placed.</p><p>As for deft, he was much less aggressive before coming to China. meiko’s ruthlessness in lane and his control of the flow of the 2v2 have facilitated deft's development as a more punchy laner. Among LPL bottom lanes, deft and meiko’s greatest strength is their synergy, particularly in how they control their wave to set up a bait or a thoughtful invade. Unlike many duos, they’ll make plays for early advantages even in weak lane matchups.</p><p>As the World Championship draws near, bottom lanes and junglers will figure prominently in analysts' rankings. With the popularity of Teleport and weaker bottom turrets, bot will be the lane to control in the early game. Rather than opening up the map through the mid lane, the bottom lane will be where victory starts and trickles upward, spreading in rashes of vision throughout the map.</p><p>Does the team control bottom lane through a jungle advantage, or control the jungle through a bottom lane advantage? That will be a near-semantic distinction to draw when classifying Worlds contenders.</p><p>For EDward Gaming — a team with some of the best players in jungle, ADC and support roles — the line is especially blurred. But more often than not, they control the jungle by establishing a lead in the bottom lane first.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11945/cropped_2683-4311-239046.jpg?ts=1473589161"><figcaption>Photo credit: 刘一村</figcaption></figure><p>There are a few methods they tend to use to achieve early bottom lane control, and almost all of them revolve around meiko. The first involves controlling the wave on the bottom side of the map in order to place vision, an approach they used in the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kbgigPFjXaI">first game of their LPL semifinal</a> against Team WE. deft and meiko pushed out the lane aggressively, engaging WE in a trade and using the threat of their Tahm Kench to head off an Alistar all-in. </p><p>The pressure was successful, forcing their opponents back and allowing meiko to place a ward at the entrance to WE’s bottom-side jungle. That ward spotted Xiang "<strong>Condi</strong>" Renjie, and<strong> </strong>clearlove invaded WE’s jungle to force out Condi’s flash, which gave EDG easy control of bot side. On the surface, it looked like the play came from clearlove’s initiative and aggression, but it was meiko and the bottom lane that made it possible.</p><p>In a variant on this strategy, meiko and deft will use their control of the lane and the vision they set up to prepare a pincer on their opponents. They will push out the lane quickly to place a ward in the second bottom lane bush, then let the enemy team build up a large minion wave, intentionally avoiding last hits. As their opponents push forward, Chen "<strong>mouse</strong>" Yuanhao Teleports in to flank. </p><p>In some cases, after they exert control on the wave, meiko and deft will allow the enemy team to push back in order to bait them into a dive and set up an easy counter-gank for clearlove. This situation can lead to problems, however, if EDG have the weaker jungle matchup or don&#39;t properly expect the first gank. For example, in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LPArqUwFfLg">Game 3 of WE vs EDward Gaming</a>, and meiko, deft and clearlove set themselves up for a gank or jungler and duo lane 3v3 in the bottom tri bush. But when Condi initiated, WE&rsquo;s burst killed meiko almost immediately, and in the followup, EDG lost clearlove as well.</p><p>Even if the jungle matchup is even or favors EDG, when meiko and deft are too greedy in a weak 2v2 matchup, the entire team struggles. In <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VQk2UrcnaqA">their second game against Saint in Week 9</a>, meiko and deft made their usual play for early bot lane control, but as Kalista and Alistar against Sivir and Nami, they lost the trade. The game became an uphill battle, though EDG did eventually win.</p><p>These early pushes make or break EDward Gaming. Knowing this, meiko and deft will frequently look for early opportunities to invade and get an edge before even getting to lane. Even at Worlds in 2015, meiko commented that studying the early game was something EDward Gaming did frequently. That came in <a href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/4160">especially useful against H2K</a>, when they predicted an early invade.</p><p>Invades like this were seen throughout the LPL season, but surprisingly, they tended to be led by the bottom lane, rather than clearlove. meiko highlighted his thought process at the press conference after the LPL final when he explained why he decided to invade Royal’s jungle <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zwEmmEbCouY">in Game 2</a>. "When I sent to their bush," meiko said, "Taliyah didn't come, so I could judge that there wasn't a ward there." From that, meiko judged RNG wouldn’t anticipate the invade, and knew it was time to strike.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11947/cropped_2683-4311-238856.jpg?ts=1473589281"><figcaption>Photo credit: 刘一村</figcaption></figure><p>Playing around vision and keeping track of vision timers appears to be one of meiko's greatest strengths. If he pings a ward, he and the rest of the team are good at keeping track of when it will die, and he rarely roams in that area until it expires. Part of the reason EDG have been more successful on their blue side is that it’s easy for meiko to walk up the river and place a ward near the enemy blue buff on red side, which helps EDG with map control substantially. Whereas, on red side, roaming to get vision of the blue-side red buff is riskier.</p><p>It’s really important to underscore that clearlove, in contrast with a jungler like Royal Never Give Up’s Liu "<strong>Mlxg</strong>" Shiyu, is much less likely to initiate a gank or some other action without knowledge of the enemy jungler. He understands that he needs to keep himself and his laners ahead, so he avoids getting trapped in situations where the enemy team can counter-gank him or counter-jungle while he ganks.</p><p>For this style of play, it's crucial to have either a good mid laner or support to secure vision and back up invades. Lee "<strong>scout</strong>" Yechan, who's playing his rookie split, has been more of a beneficiary of clearlove than a facilitator. The jungler has prioritized ganking mid much more this split, despite his reputation for favoring bottom lane pressure — in the summer playoffs, he averaged a nearly 50 percent mid-lane gank rate in the first 10 minutes of every game.</p><p>clearlove hasn't had a whole lot of choice in the matter. scout was heavily focused by Condi and WE mid laner Su "<strong>xiye</strong>" Hanwei in the semifinal, and afterward a distraught clearlove <a href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/lol/news/9799-lpl-playoffs-the-new-patch-communication-and-close-series">commented in the press conference</a> that he felt WE’s mid and jungle were "stronger than ours." In the final, clearlove adapted by ganking mid early in two out of three games. He even hovered around the mid lane looking for a gank opportunity without actually finding one — twice — which he didn’t do for either top or bottom throughout either series.</p><p>Though EDG's map control begins on the bottom side, holding mid remains important. Luckily, with meiko’s agency and vision control, EDG’s bot can set up risky trades while clearlove focuses his pressure on mid. It’s a system EDG may apply more often at the World Championship. If that’s the case, any early lead EDG gain falls at meiko’s feet.</p><p>meiko and deft’s control of the bottom wave also provides the best opportunity for mouse to get ahead in top lane. By placing wards to set up Teleport opportunities, mouse is less isolated. That helps to make up for the lower priority clearlove has placed on top lane — across nine games in semifinals and finals, clearlove only ganked top once, and mouse averaged a CS deficit relative to his opponent of 6.27 at 10 minutes for the entire summer split.</p><p>With the way EDG plays, top lane will be a natural liability, but if meiko and deft can push out the wave and bring it back to turret reliably after placing a ward, mouse will have a strong bottom lane to fall back on to get back into the game. On the other hand, this puts even more pressure on meiko’s shoulders.</p><p>Following the laning phase, meiko serves as the primary initiator in teamfights, and his peels for deft have been instrumental. Two games that stand out in my mind are <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V5ZnpyJVw68">his Nami game against Royal Never Give Up</a> in the summer regular season, and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DczMMic7StA">his Bard game</a> (despite EDG's loss) against RNG in the spring final. In both games, Royal had more answers in their draft, but EDG were able to rely on meiko to reset fights. He managed surpass expectations, in particular outperforming legendary support Cho "<strong>Mata</strong>" Sehyoung.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11950/cropped_2683-4311-239064.jpg?ts=1473589666"><figcaption>Photo credit: 刘一村</figcaption></figure><p>Those who didn’t watch LPL closely this year expect Mata to still be the greatest support coming out of the region. Though Mata has bested meiko in <a href="http://www.wanplus.com/lol/playerstats">wards placed per minute</a>, he hasn’t worked as efficiently with his jungler and ADC, and he hasn’t been able to extend his presence to the rest of the map as effectively, getting caught out in solo warding missions more frequently or attempting foolish 1v2s after Jian "<strong>Uzi</strong>" Zihao backs. Some of meiko’s greatest moments this season were against Mata, invoking a comparison few dare breathe aloud.</p><p>Last year, meiko <a href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/lol/news/1833">was still a rookie for EDG</a>. He rose to the occasion at the 2016 Mid-Season Invitational with the most consistent performance of any player on the team. Despite this, he lived in the shadow of giants, and observers scrambling to find a player to blame for the team's faults settled on meiko.</p><p>This time around, meiko’s synergy with deft will be hard to ignore. Perhaps the most exciting thing about EDG is how well their bottom laners complement one another. meiko’s aggression is augmented by deft’s positioning, and this allows EDG to get lane advantages early. Sometimes their greed can backfire, and they end up in a disadvantageous position, but as long as meiko finds an opportunity to roam, EDG react well.</p><p>The team's unstable setup phase has meant they have averaged a smaller gold lead at 10 minutes relative to other Chinese teams heading to Worlds. But once meiko places the necessary vision, EDG become a team that reacts incredibly well to information, snowballing at an increasing rate throughout the next 10 minutes of the game.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11942/cropped_cap.jpg?ts=1473588253"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Royal’s focus on the bottom side of the map whenever they face EDG isn’t just about keeping deft down, it's about preventing meiko’s roams as well. The key to defeating EDG is keeping meiko in lane and not allowing EDG to control the wave. As soon as meiko has freedom, he can set up wards that allow EDG comeback opportunities in the mid game. From there, meiko’s synergy with deft in teamfights allows the AD carry more freedom to position aggressively.</p><p>With the highest kill participation on the team at 73.5 percent this summer, meiko facilitates most of the action in EDG's games. Almost nothing the team does doesn’t go through meiko, whether it's setting up wards or instigating an engagement. </p><p>Throughout much of his career, clearlove has struggled to find a balance between his natural farming style and the need to create early game advantages for his team. With meiko this year, that balance has been much easier to strike. Not only is meiko EDG’s primary playmaker and MVP, he’s the best LPL support heading to the World Championship.</p><p>At MSI 2015, during meiko’s rookie year, his <a href="http://www.liquidlegends.net/forum/lol-general/485245-translation-post-msi-aaron-sanshao-interview">coach Ji "<strong>Aaron</strong>" Xing said</a>, "He’s not a support who’s content to be just a support. I think he will at the very least become on par with Mata… All he’s lacking is some experience."</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11943/cropped_2683-4311-239129.jpg?ts=1473589011"><figcaption>Photo credit: 刘一村</figcaption></figure><p>A year and a half later, meiko has proven himself instrumental to EDward Gaming’s domestic victories. He has overcome Mata this summer, even with the playing field level and teams of similar talent around them.</p><p>But Mata still has the legacy. He’s earned his respect internationally. Despite meiko’s past stability on the international stage, if he truly wants to aim higher, he’ll have to earn the same respect. </p><p>Teams at Worlds will study EDG’s games and realize how important meiko’s role is in the team’s success. Teams that tunnel in on clearlove without understanding meiko’s role will fail. meiko is not without his flaws — observant competitors will devise ways to pin him down and limit clearlove’s ability to act. He approaches trades with deft as if it doesn’t occur to him that they could lose, and sometimes they do. It’s easy enough to exploit with a strong support matchup. With more teams looking to counterpick support in red side last pick, this shouldn't be overlooked.</p><p>With all three of EDward Gaming’s stars performing better than they ever have, and a meta that favors them, meiko will still be the make or break factor in EDG’s final placement. No matter the outcome, viewers will know he isn’t just a footnote. </p><p><em>Photos from <a href="http://migrator.alltuu.com/albuml">刘一村's album</a>.</em></p><p><em>Kelsey Moser is a staff writer for theScore esports who fervently believes EDG are out of excuses for not making semifinals. You can <a href="http://twitter.com/karonmoser">follow her on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9355</guid>
            <title>Ask the Pros: Which player did you look up to before going pro?</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9355</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 19:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>theScore esports Staff</dc:creator>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11071/w1080xh810_maxresdefault.jpg?ts=1469558543">
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>They may be the best of the best but before they became League of Legends stars, there were others that made it before them.</p><p>We asked some LCS players which player they looked up to before becoming a pro.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JRDEc8mqH_8" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure><p><em>For more video interviews and highlights, be sure to subscribe to theScore esports on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCSCoziKHqjqbox3Fv3Pb4BA">YouTube</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10361</guid>
            <title>The Third Time is the Charm: INTZ's Tockers on going to the World Championship
            </title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10361</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 16:58:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11992/w1080xh810_29436272715_30948e6adc_h.jpg?ts=1473793160">
                <media:credit>Riot Games Brasil/lolesportsbr / IWCQ 2016 / Riot Games Brasil
                </media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>It's a moment nearly two years in the making, and the celebration unfolds as expected. Shouting, hugging, crying, their coach jumping into the fray as the five members of INTZ e-Sports jump in unison before turning to the deafening crowd, arms raised. </p><p>After two failed attempts at making a major international tournament, INTZ finally advance as a Wildcard representative. Four weeks from now, they'll attempt to fight their way out of Group C at the 2016 League of Legends World Championship.</p><p>Now come the questions of overall strength compared to the major regions, how they&#39;ll prepare, and how they feel about finally making Worlds.</p><p>"Oh god, I don't know," Gabriel "<strong>Tockers</strong>"<strong> </strong>Claumann says a week later. He sighs loudly. "It feels like I'm not there yet. I think when I see which group we're in I'll ... I don't know the words."</p><p>The mid laner for the Brazilian wildcard team INTZ, Tockers, and his team have been trying for a year and a half to make it to the World Championship. They haven’t had a true day off in the past nine months.</p><p>As a team from a minor region, INTZ have no automatic qualification into major international tournaments like the Mid-Season Invitational or Worlds. Instead, they rely on the feeder International Wildcard tournaments to qualify. While this is perfectly reasonable — in no way is Brazil as strong as their closest major region counterparts of North America and Europe — the level of difficulty in preparing for a Wildcard event is incredibly high.</p><p>The closest that major region teams come to preparing for the seven other teams that Wildcard regions must study for their feeder tournaments is the MSI event, where teams are required to learn as much as they can about five other teams for a round robin best-of-one group stage.</p><p>"It's really really difficult to prepare for a tournament like that because there are eight regions, you face all of them," Tockers says. There’s no heightened emotion in his voice, no hint of complaint, just the matter-of-fact tone that states the obvious. "You get to know a team's style by playing against them but in a best of one, they can surprise you and it's done, you lost one game. This is the hardest thing about Wildcard, it's a best-of-one [group stage] and preparing for all of the other teams."</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11803/cropped_29402042066_9eeaaca8f5_h.jpg?ts=1472962095"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Despite all coming from minor regions, the task of researching seven other teams is an exhausting task, especially with various regional finals ending at different times. </p><p>In 2015, INTZ&rsquo;s own CBLoL Finals series finished a mere two days before their arrival in Turkey for the International Wildcard Invitational. This year, the Latin America North Closing Cup Finals took place only four days before the 2016 International Wildcard Qualifer in Brazil. While LAN champions Lyon Gaming didn&rsquo;t have to adjust to large amounts of jet lag like 2015 INTZ, they had their own lack of prep time that made things difficult for themselves and opponents alike.</p><p>Yet, Lyon took the group stages by storm, only dropping one game — to CIS’ champions Albus NoX Luna — in the round robin group stage.</p><p>The first team to face Lyon was none other than INTZ. Heavily-favored to win the 2016 IWCQ due to rumblings of scrim success during INTZ’s European bootcamp, INTZ’s loss to Lyon was shocking to both the team and the masses of Brazilian fans cheering for them on home turf.</p><p>Tockers admits that they took Lyon too lightly.</p><p>"The truth here is that their finals ended a few days before Wildcard started so we didn't research them,” he says. “We knew a few of their picks but not much about their game play and we hid one or two picks the first day that really screwed us. They were good and when you do this against a good team, you lose. We didn't know that they were good. We just took the history of the region — they weren't ever good, but then we faced them the first day and they were good."</p><p>He credits the preparation of their coaching staff with INTZ’s IWCQ success. With seven teams to beat, paring down the amount of time spent on each opponent is key. Scrutinizing every team isn’t always a necessity, but assumptions based on that region’s previous results at Wildcard tournaments inevitably creep into the preparation process as coaches try to discern who their strongest adversaries will be, and how to channel more time into preparing for them specifically.</p><p>This year, prior regional strength could not have determined just how strong Lyon Gaming would be. LAN teams had often languished at the bottom of Wildcard tournament standings in the past two years. Similarly, the GPL’s previous success with the Bangkok Titans and Saigon Jokers across the three most recent International Wildcard events gave little indication that they would fail to produce any sort of competent team for the 2016 IWCQ. Yet, at this most recent event, the Saigon Jokers were significantly worse than all of their Wildcard opponents.</p><p>In the case of INTZ, they had studied Turkey’s Dark Passage and CIS’ Albus NoX Luna closely. Both regions had a history of sending strong teams to Wildcard events. Turkish teams have represented Wildcard regions at two MSI’s and the CIS representative has always made the bracket stage.</p><p>“We scrimmed Turkish and CIS teams [in Europe],” Tockers says. “We were 18-0 against CIS teams and we were about 15-2 against Turkish teams. When we got back [to Brazil], we lost our levels, maybe because we weren't in that competitive environment. We weren't playing as well in the Wildcard as we did in Europe so it felt really bad."</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11794/cropped_29196464931_27f2375595_h.jpg?ts=1472846299"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Their most recent bootcamp is the second time that INTZ has travelled to Europe and the third time they have had an international bootcamp to prepare for either their own regional finals or a Wildcard tournament. Being the strongest team in Brazil has its obvious limits — once they reach the top, a first-place Brazilian team has no stronger opponents in their immediate area to play against and continue to improve. Tockers describes this most recent bootcamp as one of their more difficult ones, simply due to their initial lack of basic mechanical skill to keep up with their European opponents.</p><p>"It was four weeks of bootcamp. When we got there it was really, really hard because, it wasn't even macro play, teams were just better than us mechanically," Tockers says. "We would literally lose every lane."</p><p>After consistent losses and general practice on European solo queue ladder in addition to their scrims, INTZ saw a massive amount of improvement in their play. Yet, simply reaching a level where they could keep up mechanically took two weeks. Once the team got the basics down, they could then begin to discuss more complicated but necessary improvements in their macro play.</p><p>“When we weren't just losing lanes, at that point we could improve our macro,” Tockers says. “We started to have really good results against top teams there. By the end of the bootcamp we were really good, but I don't think that translated in the Wildcard."</p><p>Lauded as the team to beat prior to the tournament, INTZ underperformed from the start in the group stages. They looked shaky in their first match against Kaos Latin Gamers and dropped their second game against the aforementioned Lyon Gaming. On Day 3, INTZ lost to the Chiefs. At that point, dropping out of the IWCQ in the group stages became a real possibility for the once-favorites of the tournament.</p><p>Following this defeat, the team had an important meeting that changed the way they looked at their team’s performance in the tournament.</p><p>"In our loss against the Chiefs we had multiple problems in draft and in game," Tockers says. More important than their drafting and coordination was the simple fact that they were playing scared.</p><p>"We were watching the game and we weren't making plays. You never see INTZ not making plays," Tockers says. He laughs incredulously before continuing, as if he can’t believe that his team forgot something this essential to their team identity.</p><p>"We never play passive, we always try to be in control of the game, making plays, getting deeper vision and it didn't happen against Chiefs. We saw that we were scared of making a mistake and losing. When you play passive and don't make plays you just slowly lose the game. Just forgetting about pressure and making mistakes, and just playing our normal game."</p><p>Many more mistakes were to come throughout INTZ’s journey in this year’s IWCQ yet what they discussed that night in their team meeting remained a constant. Despite their sloppy performance against Dark Passage in their qualifying best of five, INTZ was a more proactive unit than their group stage performances with strong team coordination and split-second decision-making. When they couldn’t make the aggressive play, they waited for Dark Passage to fight them, relying on their superior 5v5 teamfighting.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MFCqbJ6BSRs?start=2493" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure><p>Their newfound confidence in making decisions led to plays such as a key Tahm Kench ultimate to the bot lane where INTZ decided that they could kill Dark Passage top laner Kaan "<strong>Elwind</strong>" Atıcı’s Trundle while also stopping the Turkish team from taking Baron. Tockers and INTZ support Luan<strong> “Jockster” </strong>Cardoso used Abyssal Voyage to meet up with their top laner Felipe <strong>“Yang”</strong> Zhao in the bot lane to collapse onto Elwind. Naturally, across the map, the rest of Dark Passage started in on Baron. Using Stand United, Yang teleported to the Baron pit via jungler Gabriel <strong>“Revolta”</strong> Henud and proceeded to take on three members of Dark Passage on his own.</p><p>"Jockster and I were talking wondering if we could kill [Elwind] fast enough," Tockers says. "We figured that even as two against four we could stop baron. Yang was so strong that Sivir could hit him for an hour and not kill him because Shen was really strong. If we had any other champion but Shen we couldn't have pulled it off."</p><p>This baron play turned the tide of the game into INTZ’s favor. Five minutes later, the Brazilian team became the first Wildcard team of 2016 to qualify for the World Championship. The third time was actually the charm for this roster.</p><p>“Coming into the Wildcard we were the best team, I think,” Tockers says. “We couldn't show that and we were sad because we thought we would just win. The pressure started to affect us and it was really hard to try and not think about it. The pressure really got to us. If it weren't for our coaching staff and psychologist we wouldn't have won this time."</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11993/cropped_29327313872_c2175cc204_h.jpg?ts=1473793187"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Between their defeat at the 2016 IWCI and the start of the second CBLoL split this year, Tockers seriously considered the idea of retiring — worn out from continuously losing when it mattered most. Perhaps this contributes to his inability to describe what the victory means in words. Yet, when it comes to looking forward, he remains eager to prove himself.</p><p>"It was a hard time. I wanted to retire because I didn't think I could get here," he says. "And then, I didn't retire — now that I’m finally here it feels really good. I'm happy but I still want more. It feels good that we could make it but it's still not the end. I want more."</p><p><em>Emily Rand is a staff writer for theScore esports. You can <a href="https://twitter.com/leagueofemily">follow her on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10366</guid>
            <title>Kelsey Moser explains her World Championship power rankings</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10366</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 16:14:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11997/w1080xh810_maxresdefault.jpg?ts=1473869636">
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>theScore esports&#39; Kelsey Moser covers the more controversial choices in her 2016 World Championship <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9819" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9819">Power Ranking list</a>, explaining the criteria she used in her choices, a comparison between INTZ and ahq e-Sports Club, and a closer look at where she ranked H2K Gaming, Splyce Pro Team, Royal Never Give Up and Cloud9. She also takes a look at the tight race between SK Telecom T1, EDward Gaming and Team SoloMid.</p><p><em>Kelsey Moser is a feature writer for theScore esports. You can discuss her opinions with her <a href="http://twitter.com/karonmoser">on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10368</guid>
            <title>Reignover coaching Xmithie at CLG pre-Worlds bootcamp</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10368</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 15:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content
                url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/7658/w1080xh810_23842101294_26615a65c4_k.jpg?ts=1454802461">
                <media:credit>Riot Games/lolesports / NA LCS Spring 2016 / Riot Games</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Immortals jungler Yeu-jin &quot;<strong>Reignover</strong>&quot; Kim will be Counter Logic Gaming&#39;s jungle-position coach during the team&#39;s pre-World Championship bootcamp in South Korea, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/gg.Immortals/posts/1605848719709644:0">Immortals announced Tuesday.</a></p><p>According to the statement, Reignover will be working alongside CLG&#39;s jungler Jake &quot;<strong>Xmithie</strong>&quot; Puchero and head coach Tony &quot;<strong>Zikz</strong>&quot; Gray in order to sharpen the player&#39;s early game. In the press release, Reignover said that during the break he took after the Regional Finals he decided he wanted to stay in a competitive environment and join a bootcamp. He says he chose CLG because he&#39;s friends with the players.</p><p>"I plan to help CLG by working with Xmithie and figuring out the jungle meta for Worlds together," Reignover said in the press release. "CLG is a really good team at closing out games when they have a lead, so I think by assisting them with the early game, they will have a better chance at Worlds. I’m excited to be here and look forward to working with CLG."</p><p>According to Oracle&#39;s Elixir, Reignover had the second-highest KDA of any jungler in the 2016 NA LCS Summer regular season with a 5.5 KDA, while Xmithie finished the regular season in fifth with a 3.9 KDA. Immortals ended the season in second with a 16-2 record, while CLG finished fourth with a 10-8 record.</p><p>Earlier this month, Immortals CEO Noah Whinston announced that <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/10278" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10278">he had granted permission</a> to all of Immortals&#39; League of Legends players to explore offers from other organizations in the LCS. He also said that Immortals had placed some of their players in other North American teams&#39; pre-Worlds bootcamps.</p><p>&quot;This opportunity also comes as part of our continuing effort as an esports organization to provide a healthy environment that prepares our players for life beyond their competition,&quot; Whinston said in Tuesday&#39;s press release. &quot;Coaching is one of several sustainable career paths for retired players, and we&rsquo;re confident this experience will support Reignover&rsquo;s future endeavors.&quot;</p><p><em>Daniel Rosen is a news editor for theScore esports. He's all about that zero and ten lifestyle. <a href="http://twitter.com/daniel_rosen">You can follow him on Twitter.</a></em></p><p> </p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
