
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us"><author><name>Blizzard Entertainment</name></author><title type="text">StarCraft® II</title><updated>2016-09-21T07:56:03.431Z</updated><id>3</id><entry><title type="text">StarCraft II Editor Improvements</title><published>2016-09-21T00:00:00.000Z</published><updated>2016-09-21T07:56:03.431Z</updated><id>20274193</id><link href="http://us.battle.net//arcade/en/blog/20274193"/><summary type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">We’ve added new functionality to the StarCraft II Editor in the last few patches that we’d like to highlight. </div></summary><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><style type="text/css">#blog .detail img {
    -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 10px #0F3D70;
    -moz-border-radius: 4px 4px 4px 4px;
    -webkit-border-radius: 4px 4px 4px 4px;
    box-shadow: 0 0 10px #0F3D70;
    border-radius: 4px 4px 4px 4px;
    border: 1px solid #0F3D70;
    max-width: 575px !important;
    padding: 1px;
    }
    #blog .detail td:hover > a img, #blog .detail a img:hover {
    border: 1px solid #5BBFD3;
    }
    #blog .detail hr {
    width:100%;
    height: 8px;
    background:url('https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_folder_media/uc/UC41OX15L4721447100108007.jpg') center center no-repeat;
    border: none;
    margin-top: 30px;
    margin-bottom: 40px;
    }
    #blog .detail .schedule {
    margin-top: 1px;
    width: 100%;
    background-color: #000819;
    }
    #blog .detail .schedule th {
    background-color: #001935;
    color: #fff;
    font-weight: bold;
    height: 30px;
    padding-left: 5px;
    text-align: left;
    }
    #blog .detail .schedule .status {
    padding-left: 0;
    width: 70px;
    }
    #blog .detail .schedule td {
    border-bottom: 1px solid #00214B;
    vertical-align: top;
    height: 26px;
    padding-left: 5px;
    }
    #blog .detail .schedule tr:hover {
    background-color: #0C5EAF;
    }
</style>
    In Patch 3.5, we introduced improved functionality to the Terrain editor in the form of transform manipulators. In the most recent 3.6 Patch, we’ve further improved on these features to aid in the creative process of our amazing modding community. Today we’d like to cover these new features for those that want a brief tutorial on these tools.
    <p>If you are familiar with the Starcraft II Editor’s Cutscene Module or content creation packages, such as 3ds Max or Maya, you may have seen these before:</p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/KKQQ33A493901474411696486.png" style="width: 600px; height: 246px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></em></strong></p>

    <p>In the Cutscene Module, these are known as the translation, rotation, and scaling manipulators. The Editor development team has been hard at work to add new functionality to the manipulators in the Cutscene Module as well as add their functionality to the Terrain Module.</p>

    <p>These additions and improvements do not remove any existing placement functionality within either the Terrain or Cutscene Modules. So if you’ve grown comfortable with the existing manipulator functionality, you won’t have to change a thing. However, we believe these changes will increase your productivity once you learn how to take advantage of them.</p>

    <p>If you’re familiar with what the Starcraft II Editor currently offers, feel free to jump on ahead to the section, “<em>New Features</em>.” If you’re familiar with what other content creation tools offer with manipulators, feel free to jump right into the Editor and start trying things out!</p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/ME6FNIASJM7U1474411733914.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></p>

    <p>In this section, we’ll outline the previous feature set within the Terrain and Cutscene Modules, and highlight some areas where we felt improvements could be made. Again if you are familiar with these features, jump ahead to the New Features section.</p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/DZQVWVTA6PT71474411733936.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></p>

    <p>In the Terrain Module, placed objects (doodads, units, regions, etc) could be positioned in a few ways:</p>

    <ol>
        <li>Keyboard shortcuts</li>
        <li>Mouse clicks and drags with keyboard modifiers (shift, ctrl, alt)</li>
        <li>The Object Properties Dialog<br/>
            <strong><em><a class="lightbox" href="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/CGO7B7DKL60O1474411696846.jpg"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/RBCKIDKRZ8NQ1474411696796.jpg" style="width: 150px; height: 193px;"/></a></em></strong></li>
    </ol>

    <p>The first two methods create a reliance on prerequisite knowledge of keyboard and mouse click or drag combinations and other keyboard shortcuts. On top of this learning curve, they only offer a small set of positioning options, such as:</p>

    <ul>
        <li>Limited to world space transforms.</li>
        <li>Difficult to rotate around X or Y axes.</li>
        <li>Fixed incremental scaling with no configuration on increment size.</li>
    </ul>

    <p>The Object Properties Dialog allows us to position an object arbitrarily in the world without needing to know any of these keyboard commands, but suffers from:</p>

    <ul>
        <li>Being a textual way to place objects visually.</li>
        <li>A lack of context of placement alongside other objects in the map.</li>
        <li>A cycle of trial and error for finding correct values.</li>
    </ul>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/QZD1JJFGORGR1474411733151.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></p>

    <p>In the Cutscene Module, manipulators have existed for some time. The Cutscene Module contained basic manipulator support for:</p>

    <ul>
        <li>Translation in world space</li>
        <li>Rotation in world space</li>
        <li>Scaling in object space</li>
    </ul>

    <p>It also provided modes for Eye and Target manipulation for certain types of Cutscene Nodes, such as spot lights and cameras. This allows positioning of the “eye” and “target” separately from the entire object.</p>

    <p>Here’s an example of positioning a Game Camera in the Cutscene Module. We start in Normal mode, where the entire object is moved at once.</p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/ICD9G7J1I4UC1474412401466.gif" style="width: 600px; height: 300px;"/></p>

    <p>We then switch to Eye mode, and are able to just move the camera.</p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/33Y1KSP8I1ZS1474412401432.gif" style="width: 600px; height: 300px;"/></p>

    <p>Finally, we use Target mode to position where the camera is looking.</p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/658UR85L6TUU1474412401439.gif" style="width: 600px; height: 300px;"/></p>

    <p>This worked well, but it did not provide the functionality necessary for more interesting and dynamic positioning and placement like:</p>

    <ul>
        <li>Rotating one object around another</li>
        <li>Moving an object along its own axes, separate from world coordinates</li>
    </ul>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/RZWYOCRHA1IO1474411733696.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></p>

    <p>Now let’s go over the new functionality introduced with patch 3.5 and 3.6. At this point, there are very few differences between the Terrain and Cutscene Modules, so we won’t worry about distinguishing between them.</p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/SAGC23XIH36R1474411733601.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></p>

    <p>There are three manipulator types available in the Terrain and Cutscene Modules. Each performs one of the major transformation types. They are:</p>

    <ul>
        <li>Translation</li>
        <li>Rotation</li>
        <li>Scale</li>
    </ul>

    <p>You can change the manipulator type using the toolbar:</p>

    <p><strong><em><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/T6H7Q93EOZD11474411696869.jpg" style="width: 330px; height: 84px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></em></strong></p>

    <p>Or through the menu under Tools > Manipulator Type:</p>

    <p><strong><em><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/EGC8IJ1CD1V31474411696697.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 300px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></em></strong></p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/G7VBUS2BGX1N1474411733599.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></p>

    <p>We’ve formalized the definition of three spaces the manipulators can operate in. Spaces act as the basis coordinate system for transforms. Our goal here was to emulate other common content creation software, such as 3ds Max and Maya.</p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/ROT9KU92ANFZ1474411733963.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></p>

    <p>In world space, we use the level’s local space as the basis for transform. Think of the level as the world, wherever the level’s up, forward, and right vectors are, that’s your basis for transforms in world space.</p>

    <p>You can use world space in all manipulator types.</p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/NPX6ONXVQMRD1474412403197.gif" style="width: 600px; height: 300px;"/></em></strong></p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/N5V3867KP4WS1474411733358.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></p>

    <p>Local Space – Transforms happen relative to the last selected object’s local space.</p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/DU21FKL8IVSK1474412403029.gif" style="width: 600px; height: 300px;"/></em></strong></p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/9BQGFQA0UHIU1474411733803.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></p>

    <p>Object Space - Transforms happen relative to each individual object’s local space.</p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/FPAQP9TMQKCK1474415201917.gif" style="width: 600px; height: 300px;"/></em></strong></p>

    <p>You can change between these three manipulator spaces by using the toolbar:</p>

    <p><strong><em><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/H88YVRV0YQZH1474411696957.jpg" style="width: 330px; height: 84px;"/></em></strong></p>

    <p>Or through the menu under Tools > Manipulator Space</p>

    <p><strong><em><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/FBR99EX5L7P61474411696669.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 300px;"/></em></strong></p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/L7UM46EU9C2W1474411733124.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></p>

    <p>As we added new functionality to the Terrain Module that overlapped with the Cutscene Module, we ran into issues with conflicting keybinds. All of the pre-existing keybinds for the manipulators in the Cutscene Module were assigned away onto other tasks in the Terrain Module!</p>

    <p>For our internal team, neither Terrain or Cutscene Module users wanted to give way, so we created the “Command Profiles” system. A Command Profile allows us to create a distinct set of default keybinds. Any custom keybinds will override the defaults from the command profiles. For now, we have created two profiles – Classic and Modern.</p>

    <p>The Classic Profile preserves the experience that users in the Terrain Module had prior to 3.5. The manipulator keybinds were moved to unused keybinds in the Terrain Module.</p>

    <p>The Modern Profile preserves the experience that users in the Cutscene Module had prior to 3.5 with the existing manipulators. Conflicting keybinds in the Terrain Module were moved to unused keys.</p>

    <p>On your first run of the Starcraft II Editor after Patch 3.5, you will be presented with a dialog to choose your default controls:</p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em><a class="lightbox" href="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/K1P343OS2UBB1474411696196.jpg"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/EYY73TTQL8MF1474411696191.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 300px;"/></a></em></strong></p>

    <p>If you ever change your mind, you can always go into File > Configure Keybinds to change your selection. Just pick your desired option in the dropdown, and click apply. Your changes should take effect immediately, without needing to restart the editor.</p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em><a class="lightbox" href="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/GDRUNFD4U7BT1474411696459.jpg"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/ZBBLCFIKMD3C1474411696208.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 300px;"/></a></em></strong></p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/6IUU2RFTT60I1474411733382.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></p>

    <p>Manipulator modes change the default position of the manipulator.</p>

    <p>You can change the Manipulator mode through the menu under Tools > Manipulator Mode:</p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/VLBHG67PN0VD1474411696611.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 300px;"/></p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/OJNNK64A4DXR1474411733780.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></p>

    <p>Normal mode is the default mode for the manipulators. In Normal mode, the manipulator is positioned at the origin of the last selected object, and transforms are applied to the selected objects.</p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/VA296PCB83HN1474412402778.gif" style="width: 560px; height: 280px;"/></p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/H5C14KFQ7VB61474411733804.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></p>

    <p>Pivot mode allows you to translate and rotate the pivot of the last selected object to an arbitrary position in the world. The arbitrary pivot means that we can rotate objects around a static object or static terrain features.</p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/N6CNBA4DSY8E1474415201740.gif" style="width: 600px; height: 300px;"/></em></strong></p>

    <p>The pivot can be reset to the original position for the last selected object using Tools > Manipulator Mode > Reset Selected Pivot:</p>

    <p><strong><em><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/KWP26H7ZWO101474411696875.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 300px;"/></em></strong></p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/TRSGT9106K9J1474411733172.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></p>

    <p>The behavior of Eye and Target mode are unchanged in the Cutscene Module. However, you can now use manipulator spaces when transforming the Eye and Target positions.</p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/R9RRUA17XKS01474411733291.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></p>

    <p>When you are not using the translation, rotation, or scaling manipulator, we call this “Selection mode”. We have added an additional option in the Terrain Module specifically for Selection mode. In other content creation tools, such as 3ds Max or Maya, when you do not have an active transform manipulator, you cannot drag the selection to move it.</p>

    <p>Since the Terrain Module did not have manipulators prior to the 3.5 patch, left click + drag with the mouse translated objects along the XY plane. The “Enable Drag Move in Selection Mode” option preserves this behavior. It is enabled by default.</p>

    <p>You can toggle the option through the menu under Tools > Enable Drag Move in Selection Mode:</p>

    <p><strong><em><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/5TVINUZKPO2A1474411696451.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 300px;"/></em></strong></p>

    <div>
        <p>If you disable this option, the Terrain Module will no longer allow left click + drag to translate objects along the XY plane when in Selection mode. Disabling the option could be desirable if you want your Terrain Module to behave more like the Cutscene Module and other content creation tools. It will also prevent you from accidentally moving objects while attempting to select them!</p>

        <hr/></div>

    <p>We hope you find these changes as helpful as we have found them to be internally. Let us know if these changes have helped in your map-making endeavors and what else you’d like to see.</p>
</div></content></entry><entry><title type="text">Paid BattleTag® Changes Now Available</title><published>2016-09-16T17:00:00.000Z</published><updated>2016-09-16T17:02:30.849Z</updated><id>20285860</id><link href="http://us.battle.net//heroes/en/blog/20285860"/><summary type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Want to change your BattleTag® to something new? Every Battle.net account gets one free change-but if you've already used yours, you now have the option to purchase additional BattleTag changes. </div></summary><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><!-- Title: Paid BattleTag® Changes Now Available
Summary: Want to change your BattleTag® to something new? Every Battle.net account gets one free change-but if you've already used yours, you now have the option to purchase additional BattleTag changes.
-->
    <p>Looking to change up how you identify yourself in the Blizzard online community? The BattleTag® you originally chose doesn’t have to be your nickname for all eternity—sometimes you want to switch to something more suited to the hero (or villain) you’ve become since you first arrived in the Blizzard universe.</p>

    <p>While we’ve always provided players with one free BattleTag change per account, now we’re pleased to offer an additional paid <a href="https://www.battle.net/shop/product/battle-tag-name-change" target="_blank">BattleTag change service</a> for those of you who would appreciate the opportunity to choose yet another new moniker.</p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_folder_media/AHESEMNR6BPO1446678694683.png"/></p>

    <h3><span style="color:#9933ff;">FREE FIRST CHANGE</span></h3>

    <p>If you’re ready for something new and haven’t already used your free BattleTag change, simply visit your <a href="https://us.battle.net/login/en/?ref=https://us.battle.net/account/management/&amp;app=bam&amp;cr=true" target="_blank"><strong>Account Management Dashboard</strong></a>, and click the Change link under your Account Details to the right of your current tag.</p>

    <p/>

    <p>If you haven’t used your free change yet, don’t worry—BattleTag changes don’t expire and yours will be waiting for you if and when you ever decide to use it.</p>

    <p/>

    <p>If you’ve already used your first free change and still feel like a new nickname would be a better fit, the option to purchase an additional change will be available within Account Management. Changes are available for $10 each, and your new moniker will be reflected on your friends list automatically after making the change.</p>

    <p/>

    <p>For more details on the feature, check out our <a href="https://us.battle.net/support/en/article/400005" target="_blank">support article</a> or visit the <a href="https://www.battle.net/shop/product/battle-tag-name-change" target="_blank">Shop page</a>.</p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_folder_media/AHESEMNR6BPO1446678694683.png"/></p>

    <h3><span style="color:#9933ff;">PAID BATTLETAG CHANGE FAQ</span></h3>

    <p><span style="color:#0099ff;"><strong>If I want to change my BattleTag, does it have to be something unique?</strong></span></p>

    <p>BattleTags do not need to be unique. You can use any name you want, as long as it follows our Naming Policy. Each BattleTag is assigned a numeric ID to create a unique identifier (for example, FallenSlayer#3592).</p>

    <p><span style="color:#0099ff;"><strong>Will changing my BattleTag affect my friends list?</strong></span></p>

    <p>Your friends will now automatically see you listed under your new BattleTag, but otherwise your friends list will not be affected by this change.</p>

    <p><span style="color:#0099ff;"><strong>Will new accounts still get a free name change upon creation?</strong></span></p>

    <p>Yes. All new Battle.net accounts will continue to receive one free BattleTag change upon creation.</p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_folder_media/g6/G6G0N80EOC941426801305139.png"/></p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="InvisibleDividerLine_800x50.png" data-id="14509591" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_folder_media/6VA2831Q81IU1403137406234.png"/></p>
</div></content></entry><entry><title type="text">Get a Sneak Peek at the BlizzCon® 2016 In-Game Goodies</title><published>2016-09-15T17:00:00.000Z</published><updated>2016-09-16T00:58:13.362Z</updated><id>20288667</id><link href="http://us.battle.net///en/blog/20288667"/><summary type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Take a look at the in-game goodies BlizzCon® 2016 attendees and Virtual Ticket holders will get when they join us for this year’s show. </div></summary><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Every BlizzCon®, we give out a treasure trove of in-game goodies to attendees and Virtual Ticket holders to commemorate the occasion. Take a look at what you’ll get for your favorite Blizzard games when you join us for BlizzCon X.</p>

    <h5>World of Warcraft® – Legionnaire Murky &amp; Knight-Captain Murky</h5>

    <p><a class="lightbox" href="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/MGB6YIX9XVH71473865010467.jpg"><img alt="Blizzcon2016_Goodies_444x250_WoW.jpg" data-id="20291270" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/MT87305NXS231473864988260.jpg"/></a></p>

    <p>There comes a time when every murloc must choose a side. Will you mrglgglllgl for the Horde alongside Legionnaire Murky, or dive into battle for the Alliance at Knight-Captain Murky’s command?</p>

    <h4/>

    <h5><strong>Overwatch® – BlizzCon 2016 Bastion Skin</strong></h5>

    <p><a class="lightbox" href="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/EV3HNL6HAL201473865010379.jpg"><img alt="Blizzcon2016_Goodies_444x250_OW.jpg" data-id="20291268" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/O0N3690RBCUL1473864988246.jpg"/></a></p>

    <p>A curious automaton has been spotted exploring the halls of a local gaming convention. Cosplay as a BlizzCon-bound Bastion unit in your next match of Overwatch with this commemorative skin.*</p>

    <h5>Diablo® III – Diablo 20th Anniversary Pet</h5>

    <p><a class="lightbox" href="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/X012JE075C3H1473865010034.jpg"><img alt="Blizzcon2016_Goodies_444x250_D3.jpg" data-id="20291266" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/F4K5HY0ABTAB1473864988166.jpg"/></a></p>

    <p>Celebrate two decades of terror with this anniversary-themed Diablo pet, based on the Dark Lord’s design from the original game.*</p>

    <h5>Hearthstone® – "Welcome Inn" Card Back</h5>

    <p><a class="lightbox" href="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/JNBKCFQRHQEY1473865010047.jpg"><img alt="Blizzcon2016_Goodies_444x250_HS.jpg" data-id="20291267" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/5YK6ZQ83NFX91473864988172.jpg"/></a></p>

    <p>Pull up a chair by the fireside at BlizzCon’s Hearthstone Tavern, then play a few hands with this year’s convention-innspired card back.</p>

    <h5>Heroes of the Storm® – Nexus Tiger Mount</h5>

    <p><a class="lightbox" href="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/6QG9OXJYZ20V1473865010046.jpg"><img alt="Blizzcon2016_Goodies_444x250_HotS.jpg" data-id="20291265" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/RYE4WLRFZ0C41473864988169.jpg"/></a></p>

    <p>Introducing the latest BlizzCon mount to add to your menagerie—the Nexus Tiger! Dash onto the Battlegrounds riding this ferocious beast and show the opposing team they’re in for a fight.</p>

    <h5>StarCraft® II – Mystery Goodies</h5>

    <p><a class="lightbox" href="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/XQZL6G8HRNN01473865010419.jpg"><img alt="Blizzcon2016_Goodies_444x250_SC2.jpg" data-id="20291269" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/IADM6BTKNX1X1473864988254.jpg"/></a></p>

    <p>Show your opponents you were at BlizzCon with a new portrait—and as a bonus, be among the first to unlock a fun new piece of upcoming StarCraft II content.† Stay tuned for more details!</p>

    <p>This cache of in-game goodies will be available to you when you join us for BlizzCon X via the Virtual Ticket or in person (just redeem the Digital Bonuses code you received when you purchased your tickets).</p>

    <p>They’ll be unlocked in-game closer to the show—stay tuned for more information, and we’ll see you at BlizzCon!</p>

    <h4 style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://blizz.ly/1WC0KWx" target="_blank"><u>Order BlizzCon Virtual Ticket</u></a></h4>

    <p><em>*Diablo III in-game content for PC/Mac version only. To redeem Overwatch in-game content for PlayStation 4 or Xbox One, players must link their Battle.net account to a PlayStation Network® account or Xbox Live® account respectively. For more information on account linking, visit </em><a href="https://us.battle.net/support/en/article/linking-your-battlenet-account-on-consoles" target="_blank"><em>https://us.battle.net/support/en/article/linking-your-battlenet-account-on-consoles</em></a><em>. </em></p>

    <p><sup>†</sup><em>Bonus StarCraft II goodie will also be available separately—more details to come.</em></p>
</div></content></entry><entry><title type="text">BlizzCon® 2016 Opening Week – October 26–31</title><published>2016-09-15T14:00:00.000Z</published><updated>2016-09-16T19:33:03.400Z</updated><id>20271915</id><link href="http://us.battle.net///en/blog/20271915"/><summary type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The BlizzCon esports action is starting early again this year, and we don’t want you to miss a minute of it. </div></summary><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Elite esports players from across the globe will be traveling to North America next month to compete at BlizzCon Opening Week, all hoping to set themselves up for success on the BlizzCon stage on November 4–5. In addition to the early rounds of competition for World of Warcraft Arena, Heroes of the Storm, Hearthstone, and StarCraft II, this year’s Opening Week will host early group stage matches for the Overwatch World Cup—an international exhibition pitting nations and regions against one another.</p>

    <p>All of the action during Opening Week will be streamed live and free of charge on blizzcon.com, as detailed below:</p>

    <div class="table-responsive">
        <table border="1" cellpadding="1" cellspacing="1" class="table">
            <thead>
                <tr>
                    <th scope="row"><em>Times listed are PDT</em></th>
                    <th scope="col" style="text-align: center;"><strong>10/26</strong></th>
                    <th scope="col" style="text-align: center;"><strong>10/27</strong></th>
                    <th scope="col" style="text-align: center;"><strong>10/28</strong></th>
                    <th scope="col" style="text-align: center;"><strong>10/29</strong></th>
                    <th scope="col" style="text-align: center;"><strong>10/30*</strong></th>
                    <th scope="col" style="text-align: center;"><strong>10/31</strong></th>
                </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
                <tr>
                    <th scope="row"><strong>WoW Arena</strong></th>
                    <td/>
                    <td/>
                    <td style="text-align: center; white-space: nowrap;">11:00 a.m.</td>
                    <td/>
                    <td/>
                    <td/>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <th scope="row"><strong>Heroes</strong></th>
                    <td style="text-align: center; white-space: nowrap;">9:00 a.m.  </td>
                    <td style="text-align: center;">9:00 a.m.</td>
                    <td style="text-align: center;">9:00 a.m.</td>
                    <td/>
                    <td/>
                    <td/>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <th scope="row"><strong>Overwatch</strong></th>
                    <td/>
                    <td/>
                    <td/>
                    <td style="text-align: center; white-space: nowrap;">12:00 p.m.</td>
                    <td style="text-align: center; white-space: nowrap;"><span style="text-align: center;">12:00 p.m.</span></td>
                    <td style="text-align: center; white-space: nowrap;"><span style="text-align: center;">12:00 p.m.</span></td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <th scope="row"><strong>Hearthstone</strong></th>
                    <td style="text-align: center; white-space: nowrap;">9:00 a.m.  </td>
                    <td style="text-align: center;"><span style="text-align: center;">9:00 </span><span style="text-align: center;">a.m.</span></td>
                    <td style="text-align: center;"><span style="text-align: center;">9:00 </span><span style="text-align: center;">a.m.</span></td>
                    <td style="text-align: center;"><span style="text-align: center;">9:00 </span><span style="text-align: center;">a.m.</span></td>
                    <td style="text-align: center;"><span style="text-align: center;">9:00 </span><span style="text-align: center;">a.m.</span></td>
                    <td/>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <th scope="row"><strong>StarCraft II</strong></th>
                    <td/>
                    <td style="text-align: center;">8:30 a.m.</td>
                    <td style="text-align: center;">8:30 a.m.</td>
                    <td style="text-align: center;">8:30 a.m.</td>
                    <td style="text-align: center;">9:30 a.m.</td>
                    <td/>
                </tr>
            </tbody>
        </table>
    </div>

    <p><em>*Daylight Saving Time ends in EU.</em></p>

    <p><strong>World of Warcraft® Arena World Championship</strong><br/>
        <strong>Prize Pool:</strong> $250,000<br/>
        <strong>Number of Players:</strong> 8 Teams (3–4 players per team)<br/>
        <strong>Schedule:</strong> October 28, 11:00 a.m. PDT</p>

    <p><strong>Matches:</strong> Ahead of the Grand Finals on stage at BlizzCon, the top eight World of Warcraft Arena teams from around the world will play their first group stage matches on October 28. All eight teams will then travel to BlizzCon, where those who emerge victorious from the remaining group stages will do battle in a single-elimination bracket until the champions are crowned.</p>

    <hr/>
    <p><strong>Heroes of the Storm® Fall Global Championship</strong><br/>
        <strong>Prize Pool:</strong> $1,000,000<br/>
        <strong>Number of Players:</strong> 12 Teams (5 players per team)<br/>
        <strong>Schedule:</strong> October 26–28, 9:00 a.m. PDT</p>

    <p><strong>Matches:</strong> For three days during Opening Week, the 12 qualified teams will compete in the first of two dual-tournament group stages until only eight remain. The second group stage will get underway during Opening Week, but all eight teams will get to play on the BlizzCon stage before it concludes and the top four head into a single-elimination bracket.</p>

    <hr/>
    <p><strong>Overwatch® World Cup</strong><br/>
        <strong>Number of Players:</strong> 16 Teams (6 players per team)<br/>
        <strong>Schedule:</strong> October 29–31, 12:00 p.m. PDT</p>

    <p><strong>Matches:</strong> Following the online qualifiers, 16 teams representing nations and regions from around the globe will compete for glory during Opening Week. After three days of best-of-three, round-robin group stages, only eight teams will remain to compete in a single-elimination bracket in the BlizzCon arena.</p>

    <hr/>
    <p/>

    <p><strong>Hearthstone® World Championship<br/>
        Prize Pool: </strong>$1,000,000<br/>
        <strong>Number of Players: </strong>16<br/>
        <strong>Schedule: </strong>October 26–30, 9:00 a.m. PDT</p>

    <p><strong>Matches:</strong> Spread across no fewer than five days, this year’s Hearthstone World Championship group stages will all take place during Opening Week. Four groups of four players will compete in a dual-tournament format until only eight challengers remain, having earned the right to compete in the BlizzCon single-elimination bracket.</p>

    <hr/>
    <p><strong>StarCraft® II World Championship Series Global Finals<br/>
        Prize Pool: </strong>$500,000<br/>
        <strong>Number of Players: </strong>16<br/>
        <strong>Schedule: </strong>October 27–29, 8:30 a.m. PDT and October 30, 9:30 a.m. PDT</p>

    <p><strong>Matches:</strong> The top 16 players—seven major tournament winners plus nine based on WCS points—will compete in the Global Playoffs during Opening Week. Only the eight players who make it through the double-elimination group will advance to BlizzCon, where a single-elimination bracket incorporating best-of-five matches and a best-of-seven grand final will determine the WCS Global Champion.</p>

    <hr/>
    <p>We hope you can join us at blizzcon.com during Opening Week and, if you’re not attending BlizzCon in person this year, for the opening ceremony and throughout the event. Remember that while some BlizzCon streams are available only with a Virtual Ticket, all BlizzCon esports streams are <strong>free!</strong></p>
    <style type="text/css">#blog table {
        border: 0 none;
        border-color: rgb(41, 86, 123);
        }
        #blog table tr td, #blog table tr th {
        border: 1px solid rgb(41, 86, 123);
        padding: .5em .3em;
        }
    </style>
</div></content></entry><entry><title type="text">Patch 3.6 Feature Round-up</title><published>2016-09-12T18:00:00.000Z</published><updated>2016-09-13T14:37:48.002Z</updated><id>20273793</id><link href="http://us.battle.net//sc2/en/blog/20273793"/><summary type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">One of our biggest patches yet, Patch 3.6 is bringing all new content to Co-op Missions and more. </div></summary><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><style type="text/css">#blog .detail img {
    -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 10px #0F3D70;
    -moz-border-radius: 4px 4px 4px 4px;
    -webkit-border-radius: 4px 4px 4px 4px;
    box-shadow: 0 0 10px #0F3D70;
    border-radius: 4px 4px 4px 4px;
    border: 1px solid #0F3D70;
    max-width: 575px !important;
    padding: 1px;
    }
    #blog .detail td:hover > a img, #blog .detail a img:hover {
    border: 1px solid #5BBFD3;
    }
    #blog .detail hr {
    width:100%;
    height: 8px;
    background:url('https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_folder_media/uc/UC41OX15L4721447100108007.jpg') center center no-repeat;
    border: none;
    margin-top: 30px;
    margin-bottom: 40px;
    }
    #blog .detail .schedule {
    margin-top: 1px;
    width: 100%;
    background-color: #000819;
    }
    #blog .detail .schedule th {
    background-color: #001935;
    color: #fff;
    font-weight: bold;
    height: 30px;
    padding-left: 5px;
    text-align: left;
    }
    #blog .detail .schedule .status {
    padding-left: 0;
    width: 70px;
    }
    #blog .detail .schedule td {
    border-bottom: 1px solid #00214B;
    vertical-align: top;
    height: 26px;
    padding-left: 5px;
    }
    #blog .detail .schedule tr:hover {
    background-color: #0C5EAF;
    }
</style>
    <p>Patch 3.6 is filled to the brim with exciting new ways to enjoy StarCraft II, including a brand new Co-op Mission, a new Co-op Commander, and a whole new way of testing upcoming balance changes.</p>

    <p><u><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/XLHW2LE7DQ2C1473703340157.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></u></p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/blog/20273595/"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/ap/APSTMBHP4ORX1473468832820.gif" style="width: 600px; height: 300px; "/></a></p>

    <p>The hotly anticipated ruler of the Tal’darim is finally here to obliterate your foes in Co-op Missions. With his overwhelming power, Alarak will be an unstoppable addition to your collection of Co-op Commanders.</p>

    <p><u><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/1AVVGVRTV7YJ1473703340165.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></u></p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/blog/20245429/"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/JUORC4YZXKXZ1472606113307.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 643px;"/></a></p>

    <p>For those of you who think that the Brutal difficulty setting is a breeze, Custom Mutators are here to destroy you and your ally. With the option to activate up to TEN Mutations on one map, you are guaranteed to find yourselves in over your head.</p>

    <p><u><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/PDT1KNXRLJCG1473703340226.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></u></p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/blog/20241140/"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/K0BC8PWTJJTZ1472511958402.gif" style="width: 600px; height: 300px;"/></a></p>

    <div>
        <div>
            <p>Egon Stetmann is back and crazier than ever! Left on the planet of Bel’shir, Stetmann has become too involved with his science experiments and now needs your help.  Escort his Science Vessels while they harvest Terrazine to fulfill the wishes of our favorite scientist.</p>
        </div>
    </div>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/XY1AHXQ8F1Q41473703340150.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/blog/20241138/"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/blog_header/it/IT7QBDBNCPDB1472168727672.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 213px;"/></a></p>

    <div>
        <p>StarCraft II is constantly growing and changing for the better and competitive multiplayer is one of the core components that we are dedicated to evolving. Part of this process is gathering community feedback through our balance testing and we’re excited to make playing these changes easier than ever through matchmaking.</p>
    </div>

    <hr/>
    <p>Patch 3.6 is now live and you can find the full patch notes right <a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/blog/20273794/">here</a>. Let us know what feature you’re most excited about in the comments and we’ll see you on the battlefield!</p>
</div></content></entry><entry><title type="text">StarCraft II: Legacy of the Void 3.6.0 Patch Notes</title><published>2016-09-12T17:42:00.000Z</published><updated>2016-09-13T14:48:30.024Z</updated><id>20273794</id><link href="http://us.battle.net//sc2/en/blog/20273794"/><summary type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Patch 3.6.0 has arrived! Check out all of the updates that have been made to StarCraft II: Legacy of the Void. </div></summary><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><span style="color:#FF0000;"><strong>* This patch goes live in the Americas on Tuesday, September 13th.</strong></span></p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/M0IF77YMS8EM1472857938257.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <ul>
        <li><strong>A new Commander, Alarak, has been added to Co-op Missions.</strong>

            <ul>
                <li>Alarak is the first commander that is playable on the field while also possessing top-bar menu abilities.</li>
                <li>Alarak is an offensive-oriented hero with low survivability on his own, but as the highlord of the Tal’darim, Alarak gladly sacrifices one of his own pawns to keep himself alive. He will always be the last unit to die.</li>
                <li>Alarak is available as a standalone purchase for all players.</li>
                <li>Three new emoticons are included with Alarak’s purchase.</li>
                <li>For more information, see <a href="http://www.battle.net/sc2/blog/20273595/">our blog</a> .</li>
            </ul>
        </li>
        <li><strong>A new map, Mist Opportunities, has been added to Co-op Missions.</strong>
            <ul>
                <li>Egon Stetmann, stranded on Bel’shir since before the fall of Arcturus Mengsk, needs your help harvesting terrazine gas. Protect his automated Harvesting Bots, as they’re the only friends he has left.</li>
                <li>For more information, see <a href="http://www.battle.net/sc2/blog/20241140/">our blog</a>.</li>
            </ul>
        </li>
        <li><strong>Custom Mutators</strong>
            <ul>
                <li>Players can now create their own customized Co-op Missions challenges!</li>
                <li>Select up to 10 mutators to add to each mission.</li>
                <li>Custom Mutators mode is only available to pre-made two-player parties.</li>
                <li>Commanders must be level 5 or higher to be useable in this mode.</li>
                <li>Access this new mode by navigating to Co-op Missions > Custom.</li>
                <li>For more information, see <a href="http://www.battle.net/sc2/blog/20245429/">our blog</a>.</li>
            </ul>
        </li>
        <li><strong>A new “Testing” Matchmaker has been added.</strong>
            <ul>
                <li>A new section has been added under Multiplayer > Testing and will be available for 1v1 testing whenever new balance changes or new maps are being actively tested.</li>
                <li>The Testing matchmaker is unranked and will not affect a player’s Ranked MMR.</li>
                <li>Clicking the Balance Info button will show the balance changes that are actively being tested.</li>
                <li>For more information, see <a href="http://www.battle.net/sc2/blog/20241138/">our blog</a>.</li>
            </ul>
        </li>
        <li>The Contender list now only displays players who are eligible for promotion into Grandmaster.</li>
        <li>Worker and army unit counts are now displayed when hovering the mouse cursor over the Supply icon in the top-right corner of the in-game UI.</li>
    </ul>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/5Y237O8Q7ETL1472857944566.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/ULJVRRWF2IF01472860239302.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <ul>
        <li>Destructible Rocks have been added over the Vespene Geysers for the expansions on most Co-op Missions. This will slightly slow the rate of expanding on those maps.</li>
    </ul>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/B4EBWBZARS4O1472860239301.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/HD63LVEEZ7WS1472860667303.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <ul>
        <li>Auto cast toggle selection on Brutalisk or Leviathan is now retained through morphing into a Ravager, Guardian, or Devourer.</li>
    </ul>

    <blockquote><em><strong>Developer Comments:</strong></em> This is a quality of life change which should allow you to turn off the auto cast if you wanted the unit to remain in its upgraded form and keep its Bio Mass stacks.</blockquote>

    <ul>
        <li>Bio Mass Bonuses
            <ul>
                <li>Attack speed bonus reduced from 2% to 1% per stack.</li>
            </ul>
        </li>
    </ul>

    <blockquote><em><strong>Developer Comments:</strong></em> A unit with a lot of Biomass was dealing too much damage as well as generating too much life from life leech. Abathur would often not even need to use the Mend ability. We believe reducing the attack speed bonus slightly can bring Abathur to a more reasonable level, and the Mend ability can be more useful again without changing Abathur’s overall power level.</blockquote>

    <ul style="margin-left: 23px;">
        <li>Life bonus changed from +5 Life (flat value) to +3% Life (percentage based).</li>
    </ul>

    <blockquote><em><strong>Developer Comments:</strong></em> Percentage based life increase is more consistent across the different unit types. A Swarm Host with full stacks of Biomass was generating locusts with the same life as an Ultralisk!</blockquote>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/WU4VGSRXI0XH1472860667314.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <ul>
        <li>Battlecruisers
            <ul>
                <li>Hitpoints increased from 450 to 550.</li>
                <li>Energy removed.</li>
                <li>Yamato Cannon now has 100 seconds cooldown.</li>
            </ul>
        </li>
    </ul>

    <blockquote><em><strong>Developer Comments:</strong></em> Battlecruisers have increased life and no longer have energy. Yamato Cannon is now a cooldown based ability and can be used more often.</blockquote>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/8Q67FS6N7GCI1472860667332.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <ul>
        <li>Vorazun Emergency Recall
            <ul>
                <li>It now removes negative status effects and damage over time effects such as Fungal, Irradiate, or Parasitic Bomb, so that the units won't die immediately after being saved.</li>
            </ul>
        </li>
    </ul>

    <blockquote><em><strong>Developer Comments:</strong></em> It was not a great experience to recall units to safety then see them die immediately from the negative status effects or damage over time effects. In some cases, recalled units could kill other friendly units as well.</blockquote>

    <ul style="margin-left: 23px;">
        <li>Cooldown increased to 5 mins.</li>
    </ul>

    <blockquote><em><strong>Developer Comments:</strong></em> Emergency Recall was designed to allow Vorazun to venture out with cloaked units and have a safety net if they were detected and killed. But the cooldown was so short, so that the units were nearly unkillable in most cases.</blockquote>

    <ul style="margin-left: 23px;">
        <li>Shadow Guard
            <ul>
                <li>Cool-up time (that is, the time before an ability becomes available) is now increased to 4 minutes to be in line with other Commander abilities.</li>
            </ul>
        </li>
    </ul>

    <blockquote><em><strong>Developer Comments:</strong></em> Most Commander abilities come online around the 4-minute mark. This was not an issue with Vorazun until Mastery Points were released. Starting Spear of Adun energy should still allow players to use the abilities more often without resulting in an instant expansion for both players at the mission start.</blockquote>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/A8O1G56MOOW61472858010935.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <ul>
        <li><strong>Transform Manipulator (Gizmo) Features</strong>

            <ul>
                <li>Object Space has been added.
                    <ul>
                        <li>Objects can now be rotated, translated and scaled on their own individual axes.</li>
                        <li>In Local space, each object moves around the last selected object’s axis.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Movable Pivot Mode is now available.
                    <ul>
                        <li>Allows the pivot for the manipulator to be offset from the object. It can be translated and rotated.</li>
                        <li>Switching and toggling through modes can be done through the Tools menu, Manipulator Mode sub-menu.</li>
                        <li>Pivots can be reset to the object’s origin via the Tools menu, Manipulator Mode sub-menu, Reset Selected Pivot.</li>
                        <li>Mode preferences are now saved in the Editor.</li>
                        <li>Persists per run of the Editor.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </li>
        <li><strong>Transform Manipulator (Gizmo) Improvements</strong>
            <ul>
                <li>In the Terrain Editor, you can now toggle snap to grid when using the translate manipulator. Keybinds have been re-enabled when using the translation manipulator.</li>
                <li>Gizmos will now be more responsive in the Terrain Editor.</li>
                <li>Terrain Editor Translate manipulator now sets the ignore placement requirements flag when performing a Shift + Drag operation.</li>
                <li>The Rotation Gizmo now allows for “Ctrl + Left Click” to rotate around the Z axis without grabbing the Gizmo.</li>
                <li>Manipulators will now appear on the last selected object for both the Terrain Editor and the Cutscene Editor.</li>
            </ul>
        </li>
    </ul>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/2PQM47R2RMN01472858022097.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></strong></p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/2ALHX3SWNJW41472858029684.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <ul>
        <li>Fixed an issue where whispers could fail to be sent with an error message that the recipient was not online.</li>
        <li>Fixed multiple issues with Grandmaster where players could have been shown inaccurate ranking information.</li>
        <li>Fixed an issue where the Play with a Friend experience bonus would sometimes not be granted.</li>
        <li>Fixed an issue where the Score Screen could sometimes display incorrectly.</li>
    </ul>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/2LIFZD08V06Y1472860239316.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <ul>
        <li><strong>Nova Covert Ops</strong>

            <ul>
                <li>In Flashpoint, the Holo Decoy can no longer be loaded into units.</li>
                <li>In Flashpoint, units now have proper animations when crossing bridges.</li>
                <li>Fixed an issue where low graphic settings could cause textures to disappear in Night Terrors.</li>
                <li>Fixed multiple issues with the cutscene of Trouble in Paradise.</li>
                <li>In Night Terrors, Spider Mines now show the Adjutant portrait properly.</li>
                <li>The description for the Glutton For Punishment achievement now properly mentions that it requires Hard difficulty or higher.</li>
                <li>Fixed a display issue with the Banshee’s cloaked model when detected.</li>
            </ul>
        </li>
    </ul>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/FGSKU7TEXV431472858059663.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <ul>
        <li><strong>General</strong>

            <ul>
                <li>Warp Prism now properly appears in the Protoss Hotkeys menu.</li>
                <li>Classic Hotkeys Profile now has the Set Rally Point hotkey as “R”.</li>
                <li>Fixed an issue where the mission selection panel could become blank after purchasing a commander.</li>
                <li>The Play button for the Weekly Mutation now says Play Mutation.</li>
                <li>Enemy Ghosts now use Nuke Strikes when available to attack the bases on Brutal difficulty.</li>
                <li>Archons now have consistent animation when cloaked and revealed.</li>
            </ul>
        </li>
        <li><strong>Commanders</strong>
            <ul>
                <li>General
                    <ul>
                        <li>Kerrigan and Zagara’s Spawning Pool now shows Queens properly in the tooltip.</li>
                        <li>Fixed a graphical issue that could occur when using Abathur’s Biomass ability.</li>
                        <li>The Temporal Field mutator now properly slows Heroic units.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Abathur
                    <ul>
                        <li>Fixed multiple issues with displaying Roach Vile on the Units tab.</li>
                        <li>Viper now properly displays the energy regeneration buff on the Biomass tooltip.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Karax
                    <ul>
                        <li>Shadow Cannons now take priority over Energizers in the subgroup command for Immortal.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Kerrigan
                    <ul>
                        <li>Fixed an issue where the Leaping Strike ability allowed access to the unpathable areas around the Void Shard.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Raynor
                    <ul>
                        <li>The Bunker icon in the Units tab now properly updates with the Battle Bunkers upgrade.</li>
                        <li>Removed an unintended ability button on the Siege Tank’s command card.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Swann
                    <ul>
                        <li>Fixed an issue where Thors could have a different skin when destroyed.</li>
                        <li>Defensive Matrix now does not interact with a unit’s base shields.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Vorazun
                    <ul>
                        <li>Leviathans no longer continue to attack when affected by Time Stop.</li>
                        <li>Disruption Web’s debuff icon is now displayed in the correct color.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </li>
        <li><strong>Maps</strong>
            <ul>
                <li>Chain of Ascension
                    <ul>
                        <li>Fixed multiple issues where unit vision and minimap vision were not properly removed with the Darkness mutator in Chain of Ascension.</li>
                        <li>Fixed an issue with the Slayn Elemental’s circular pathing when engaging units at spawn.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Temple of the Past
                    <ul>
                        <li>Fixed multiple issues with placing Toxic Nests in certain locations of the map.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>The Vermillion Problem
                    <ul>
                        <li>Missiles from the Missile Madness mutator will no longer target structures.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Void Thrashing
                    <ul>
                        <li>Void Thrashers are now properly cloaked by the We Move Unseen mutator.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </li>
        <li><strong>Mutators</strong>
            <ul>
                <li>Guardian Shield’s radius of effect now properly matches its graphic with the Power Overwhelming mutator.</li>
                <li>The Speed Freaks mutator now has a proper tooltip description.</li>
                <li>Fixed multiple issues with the Micro Transactions mutator.</li>
                <li>Fixed an issue with the Blizzard mutator where storm clouds could get stuck in certain map locations.</li>
            </ul>
        </li>
    </ul>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/G2Q16JRAY6I61472858152160.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <ul>
        <li><strong>Zerg</strong>

            <ul>
                <li>Queens now start attacking from the maximum attack range.</li>
            </ul>
        </li>
        <li><strong>Maps</strong>
            <ul>
                <li>Units can no longer clip into the ramp railings in the Doraelus Hills.</li>
                <li>Mineral patches are now properly placed in the New Gettysburg LE.</li>
                <li>Tournament decals are now properly placed at the starting locations in the New Gettysburg LE.</li>
                <li>The Map Info panel for Apotheosis LE now properly displays the map description.</li>
            </ul>
        </li>
    </ul>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/AUOH7C9PSK4G1472860218261.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <ul>
        <li>Fixed an issue where the Play and Create Game buttons for Arcade games could be disabled.</li>
        <li>Fixed an issue where bookmarked games under My Bookmarks would not be displayed properly.</li>
        <li>The correct presence status is now displayed when in an Arcade lobby.</li>
    </ul>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/REZRPJYKIJPH1472858164164.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <ul>
        <li>The middle mouse button can now properly scroll the Co-op Mission selection window.</li>
        <li>Fixed an issue with the Silenced icon when a player was offline.</li>
        <li>The list of members in Groups and Clans are now properly displayed without extra spacing between the rows.</li>
        <li>Removed an unintended tooltip from the League Information panel on the Tournaments screen.</li>
        <li>The level up celebration now properly appears for each race when hitting a new level.</li>
        <li>Fixed an issue where maps with long names could not be searched for.</li>
        <li>The achievement celebration now properly appears after purchasing a Co-op commander.</li>
        <li>Fixed an issue where friend names could appear incorrectly.</li>
        <li>Fixed an issue with the lighting effects from Artanis’s psi-blade on his Landing Screen animation.</li>
        <li>The Replay Invite panel now shows its border properly.</li>
    </ul>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/wn/WN37OAC0B6DJ1472858571303.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></strong></p>

    <ul>
        <li>Fixed a crash that could occur when selecting the Translation Manipulator and executing Undo on certain Hero models in the Cutscene Editor.</li>
        <li>Fixed an issue where the Rotation Gizmo could get extremely large rotation amounts in certain cases.</li>
    </ul>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/8B6BSBO7H8ZM1472860227302.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <ul>
        <li>Fixed an issue where the Rotation Manipulator could fail to loop around the object in the Mac Editor.</li>
        <li>Fixed an issue where multiple UI elements could be offset in the Mac Editor.</li>
    </ul>

    <div class="blockquote">
        <style class="blockquote-dev" type="text/css">blockquote {
            background: #00122B;
            border-left: 1px solid #A10502;
            margin: 1.5em 10px;
            padding: 0.5em 10px;;
            quotes: "\201C""\201D""\2018""\2019";
            }
            blockquote p {
            display: inline;
            padding: 0px 0px 0px 0px;
            }
        </style>
    </div>
</div></content></entry><entry><title type="text">Get a Free In-Game Portrait When You Watch a Korean Season 2 Finals</title><published>2016-09-10T01:15:00.000Z</published><updated>2016-09-10T01:59:33.783Z</updated><id>20125925</id><link href="http://us.battle.net//sc2/en/blog/20125925"/><summary type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Tune into any of the Season 2 Korean Finals broadcasts to secure a Season 2 WCS Korea Portrait. </div></summary><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>There are a ton of Korean StarCraft II tournaments coming up over the next two weeks, and to celebrate we're giving away a unique portrait to those who tune-in live for the action!</p>

    <p>Portraits will be given away to those who<strong> link their accounts on Twitch.tv </strong>and then tune-in live to one of the upcoming <a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/blog/20280560/gsl-season-2-code-s-final-survival-guide-9-9-2016">GSL Finals</a>, <a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/blog/20280559/starcraft-ii-starleague-season-2-grand-finals-survival-guide-9-9-2016">SSL Finals</a>, or WCS Korea Cross-Finals. Read on for more details.</p>

    <hr/>
    <p><span style="color:#FFFFFF;"><strong>Unlocking Your Portrait</strong></span></p>

    <p><a href="https://www.twitch.tv/gsl">Twitch.tv</a></p>

    <p>To secure your free in-game portrait, you’ll first need to link your Twitch.tv and Battle.net accounts by doing the following:</p>

    <ul>
        <li>Log in or create an account on Twitch.tv.</li>
        <li>Navigate to the Settings menu by clicking your account name in the top-right corner of the home screen.</li>
        <li>Navigate to the Connections tab of the Settings menu.</li>
        <li>Find the Battle.net section then follow the given instructions after selecting a region and clicking Connect.</li>
    </ul>

    <p align="center"><a href="https://secure.twitch.tv/settings/connections">Click here to go straight to the Twitch settings page</a></p>

    <p>Once you’ve linked your accounts, simply watch any game in the GSL Finals, SSL Finals, or the KR Cross-Finals on <a href="http://Twitch.tv">Twitch.tv </a>to receive your portrait. Please note that the portrait should appear in your collection in the weeks following the event’s conclusion. Go <a href="https://us.battle.net/support/en/article/linking-your-twitchtv-account">here</a> for our support page on Twitch.tv account linking.</p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/bi/BIVQIXXGLCF31473462454591.png" style="width: 450px; height: 247px;"/></p>

    <p><span style="color:#FFFFFF;"><strong>Other Useful Info</strong></span></p>

    <p>The action all begins with the GSL Finals on September 10, starting at 1:30 a.m. PDT (8:30 a.m. UTC). For complete event details including players, broadcast talent, and more, check out our survival guides for the <a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/blog/20280560/gsl-season-2-code-s-final-survival-guide-9-9-2016">GSL</a> or <a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/blog/20280559/starcraft-ii-starleague-season-2-grand-finals-survival-guide-9-9-2016">SSL</a> Finals.</p>

    <p>For more StarCraft II esports, be sure to visit our <a href="http://wcs.battle.net/sc2/en">web site</a> or follow <a href="https://twitter.com/esportstarcraft">@esportstarcraft</a> on Twitter. </p>

    <p/>

    <p/>
    <style type="text/css">#blog .detail img {
        }
        #blog .detail td:hover > a img, #blog .detail a img:hover {
        }
        #blog .detail hr {
        width:100%;
        height: 8px;
        background:url('https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_folder_media/uc/UC41OX15L4721447100108007.jpg') center center no-repeat;
        border: none;
        margin-top: 30px;
        margin-bottom: 40px;
        }
        #blog .detail .schedule {
        margin-top: 1px;
        width: 100%;
        background-color: #000819;
        }
        #blog .detail .schedule th {
        background-color: #001935;
        color: #fff;
        font-weight: bold;
        height: 30px;
        padding-left: 5px;
        text-align: left;
        }
        #blog .detail .schedule .status {
        padding-left: 0;
        width: 70px;
        }
        #blog .detail .schedule td {
        border-bottom: 1px solid #00214B;
        vertical-align: top;
        height: 26px;
        padding-left: 5px;
        }
        #blog .detail .schedule tr:hover {
        background-color: #0C5EAF;
        }
    </style>
</div></content></entry><entry><title type="text">StarCraft II StarLeague Season 2 Grand Finals Survival Guide</title><published>2016-09-09T22:30:00.000Z</published><updated>2016-09-10T02:00:24.235Z</updated><id>20280559</id><link href="http://us.battle.net//sc2/en/blog/20280559"/><summary type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Dark is back, but this time facing a new opponent in Solar, at the grand finals of the second season of the SSL! </div></summary><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/9AA33FC3YIXD1456525140808.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <p>The StarCraft II StarLeague has reached new heights as the defending champion 'Dark' returns to the finals to take on 'Solar'. It all goes down on September 11 at 6:00 p.m. KST (9:00 a.m. UTC, or 2:00 a.m. PDT). With over $50,000 on the line as well as a guaranteed seat at the WCS Global Playoffs, expect both of these players to be playing the best games of their lives!</p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/EOAQZ19Z5SL31456525140812.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <p><strong style="line-height: 2;"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/3A5UFDSHVW2E1461633878646.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></strong></p>

    <p style="margin-left: 40px;"><strong><span lang="ES-CL" style="padding: 0in; border: 1pt none windowtext; font-size: 12pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">SPOTV Games</span></strong></p>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/P0RXKMM56BCB1461633878377.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></strong></p>

    <p style="margin-left: 40px;"><strong>Sunday, September 11:</strong></p>

    <ul>
        <li style="margin-left: 40px;">PDT – 2:00 a.m.</li>
        <li style="margin-left: 40px;">EDT – 5:00 a.m.</li>
        <li style="margin-left: 40px;">UTC – 9:00 a.m.</li>
        <li style="margin-left: 40px;">KST – 6:00 p.m.</li>
    </ul>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/UGVCJOCY0VR61461633878783.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></strong></p>

    <ul>
        <li>English
            <ul style="list-style-type:circle;">
                <li><a href="http://www.twitch.tv/sc2starleague">http://www.twitch.tv/sc2starleague</a></li>
                <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/ESportsTV">https://www.youtube.com/user/ESportsTV</a></li>
            </ul>
        </li>
    </ul>

    <p/>

    <ul>
        <li>Korean
            <ul style="list-style-type:circle;">
                <li><a href="http://www.e-sportstv.net/">http://www.e-sportstv.net</a></li>
                <li><a href="http://sports.news.naver.com/sports/index.nhn?category=e_sports">http://sports.news.naver.com/sports/index.nhn?category=e_sports</a></li>
                <li><a href="http://www.azubu.tv/KR_SC2_Starleague">http://www.azubu.tv/KR_SC2_Starleague</a></li>
                <li><a href="http://www.youtube.com/esportstv">http://www.youtube.com/esportstv</a></li>
            </ul>
        </li>
    </ul>

    <p/>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/72F3VNXFXU5T1456525140887.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></strong></p>

    <p>The SSL finals will feature a best-of-seven contest between Park '<a href="http://wiki.teamliquid.net/starcraft2/Dark">Dark</a>' Ryung Woo and Kang '<a href="http://wiki.teamliquid.net/starcraft2/Solar">Solar</a>' Min Soo. Prizing will be distributed as follows:</p>

    <p style="margin-left:.5in;">1<sup>st</sup> place: ~$35,850, 4,000 WCS KR Points, and a WCS Global Playoffs Seed</p>

    <p style="margin-left:.5in;">2<sup>nd</sup> place: ~$17,925, and 2,800 WCS KR Points</p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/6CIHWYY3WT011456525140946.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <p>Join in on the conversation about these games here:</p>

    <ul>
        <li>Official Team Liquid SSL Finals Thread</li>
        <li><a href="https://reddit.com/r/starcraft">Reddit.com/r/StarCraft</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/forum/13436/">Esports Forum on StarCraftII.com</a></li>
    </ul>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/97768W48B3ZN1456525140917.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <p><a href="http://wiki.teamliquid.net/starcraft2/2016_StarCraft_II_StarLeague_Season_2/Main_Event">Liquipedia Page</a></p>

    <p/>
</div></content></entry><entry><title type="text">GSL Season 2 Code S Final Survival Guide</title><published>2016-09-09T22:15:00.000Z</published><updated>2016-09-09T22:15:00.000Z</updated><id>20280560</id><link href="http://us.battle.net//sc2/en/blog/20280560"/><summary type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The climactic conclusion of GSL Code S has arrived! Check out the details about this event in our survival guide! </div></summary><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/9AA33FC3YIXD1456525140808.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <p>The "One Man Army" in Byun '<a href="http://wiki.teamliquid.net/starcraft2/ByuN">ByuN</a>' Hyun Woo will face off against the two-time WCS Global Champion Kim '<a href="http://wiki.teamliquid.net/starcraft2/SOs">sOs</a>' Yoo Jin on September 10 at 5:30 p.m. KST (8:30 a.m. UTC, or 1:30 a.m. PDT). Many wonder who will succeed, the tried and true player that has secured two global titles, or the seemingly unstoppable force that has topped the charts of Aligulac and set to shocking the world over and over as he single-handedly ascends  the mountain of team-trained StarCraft II pros.</p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/EOAQZ19Z5SL31456525140812.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/3A5UFDSHVW2E1461633878646.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></strong></p>

    <p style="margin-left: 40px;"><strong><span style="font-size:16px;">AfreecaTV</span></strong></p>

    <p><strong style="line-height: 2;"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/P0RXKMM56BCB1461633878377.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></strong></p>

    <p style="margin-left: 40px;"><strong>Saturday, September 10</strong></p>

    <ul>
        <li style="margin-left: 80px;">PDT – 1:30 a.m.</li>
        <li style="margin-left: 80px;">EDT – 4:30 a.m.</li>
        <li style="margin-left: 80px;">UTC – 8:30 a.m.</li>
        <li style="margin-left: 80px;">KST – 5:30 p.m.</li>
        <li style="margin-left: 80px;">CEST - 11:30 a.m.<br/>
        </li>
    </ul>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/VRY3UT86G8QS1461633878377.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></strong></p>

    <p style="margin-left: 40px;"><strong>English: Dan '<a href="https://twitter.com/artosis">Artosis</a>' Stemkoski and Nick '<a href="https://twitter.com/callmetasteless">Tasteless</a>' Plot</strong></p>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/UGVCJOCY0VR61461633878783.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></strong></p>

    <ul style="margin-left: 40px;">
        <li><strong>English</strong>

            <ul>
                <li><a href="http://twitch.tv/gsl">http://twitch.tv/gsl</a></li>
            </ul>
        </li>
        <li><strong>Korean</strong>
            <ul>
                <li><a href="http://gsl.afreeca.com/">http://gsl.afreeca.com</a></li>
                <li><a href="http://sports.news.naver.com/esports/index.nhn">http://sports.news.naver.com/esports/index.nhn</a></li>
            </ul>
        </li>
        <li><strong>Russian</strong>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <div>
                        <p><a href="http://www.afreeca.tv/korea20">www.afreeca.tv/korea20</a></p>
                    </div>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </li>
        <li><strong>Chinese</strong>
            <ul>
                <li><a href="http://www.huomaotv.cn/">http://www.huomaotv.cn</a></li>
            </ul>
        </li>
    </ul>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/60MGXS3WFQ1S1461633878771.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></strong></p>

    <p style="margin-left: 0.5in;">1<sup>st</sup> place: ~$33,840, 4,000 WCS KR Points, and a WCS Global Playoffs Seed</p>

    <p style="margin-left: 0.5in;">2<sup>nd</sup> place: ~$16,920, and 2,800 WCS KR Points</p>

    <p style="margin-left:.5in;"/>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/6CIHWYY3WT011456525140946.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <p>Join in on the conversation about these games here!</p>

    <ul>
        <li>Official Team Liquid GSL Finals Thread</li>
        <li><a href="http://reddit.com/r/starcraft">Reddit.com/r/StarCraft</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/forum/13436/">Esports Forum on StarCraftII.com</a></li>
    </ul>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/97768W48B3ZN1456525140917.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <p><a href="http://wiki.teamliquid.net/starcraft2/2016_Global_StarCraft_II_League_Season_2/Code_S">Liquipedia Page</a></p>

    <p/>
</div></content></entry><entry><title type="text">Patch 3.6 Preview: New Co-op Commander Alarak</title><published>2016-09-09T17:00:00.000Z</published><updated>2016-09-16T00:17:34.223Z</updated><id>20273595</id><link href="http://us.battle.net//sc2/en/blog/20273595"/><summary type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Alarak is almost ready to storm into battle. Learn more about his abilities and army in our preview blog. </div></summary><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="centered" style="margin-bottom: 25px; text-align: center;"><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qft2Jwg6GIs?theme=light&amp;color=white&amp;cc_load_policy=1&amp;HD=1&amp;rel=0&amp;showinfo=0" style="border-bottom:1px solid lightgray;" width="560"/></div>

    <p>Alarak, Highlord of the Tal’darim is making his way into Co-op Missions. He obliterates his enemies with overwhelming power while sacrificing his own army to achieve his goals. His army focuses on maximizing damage and decimating its foes with brutal efficiency.</p>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/P1M17L0MSFKD1473298059996.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></strong></p>

    <p>When we were deciding on who we’d introduce as the next Co-op Commander, the choice seemed to be clear: the community wanted Alarak, and they wanted him now. We also heard that players wanted a Hero unit that wasn’t from the Zerg race and we felt Alarak was a great fit. His over-the-top personality and devastating power meant he would have a great presence on the battlefield. We also love John DeLancie, who voices Alarak, so we jumped at any excuse to bring him back into the recording studio.</p>

    <p>As we designed Alarak and his army, we wanted to make sure his sinister nature and the brutality of the Tal’darim faction came through. We think the new Supplicant unit and Alarak’s Sacrifice ability deliver on these goals.</p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://us.battle.net/shop/en/product/commander-alarak"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/EUP3BM3E71421458604450055.png" style="width: 334px; height: 114px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></a></p>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/QOSK59498PNN1473298060237.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></strong></p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/lo/LOO5982UFGH81473298104175.png" style="width: 600px; height: 215px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></p>

    <p>Alarak is the first Protoss Commander that you’ll directly control in battle. He wields massive destructive potential, but is also relatively fragile as Hero units go. He makes up for this weakness by drawing upon the life force of friend and foe alike. His passive, Soul Absorption, restores health and shields whenever an enemy is slain. It also allows him to steal the souls of his allies whenever he is near death—with no cooldown. Alarak WILL be the last one standing! This is where the Supplicants come in. These durable servants are summoned two at a time and make for excellent meat shields. The Supplicants are Alarak’s most loyal followers and the first to willingly sacrifice their life-force. Maintaining a healthy supply of Supplicants at all times will be important to successfully controlling the Tal’darim.</p>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/XI00FLPI9PVY1473298060021.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></strong></p>

    <p>Alarak is unique as a Commander in that he has Hero abilities as well as global abilities that can be activated at the top of the screen.</p>

    <div class="cteaser" style="text-align: left;"><a class="cteaserimg lightbox" href="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/BOU325UPBQ791473297426156.gif" target="_blank"><img src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/VGR81CQ0K9F01473297492358.jpg"/></a> <a class="cteasersummary lightbox" href="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/BOU325UPBQ791473297426156.gif" target="_blank"> <span class="headline">Deadly Charge</span><br/>
        <span class="summarytext">Alarak intercepts a target enemy unit and deals a deadly strike.</span></a></div>

    <div class="cteaser" style="text-align: left;"><a class="cteaserimg lightbox" href="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/UFSTEJ8P3R0V1473297426688.gif" target="_blank"><img src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/1GFW2IPH8DHX1473297492382.jpg"/></a> <a class="cteasersummary lightbox" href="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/UFSTEJ8P3R0V1473297426688.gif" target="_blank"> <span class="headline">Destruction Wave</span><br/>
        <span class="summarytext">Unleashes a massive wave of force in a straight line, dealing damage to enemies in its path and knocking them back.</span></a></div>

    <div class="cteaser" style="text-align: left;"><a class="cteaserimg lightbox" href="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/MRCZ6BLO20WT1473297427370.gif" target="_blank"><img src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/5TFQTAU8EKQ21473297492475.jpg"/></a> <a class="cteasersummary lightbox" href="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/MRCZ6BLO20WT1473297427370.gif" target="_blank"> <span class="headline">Empower Me</span><br/>
        <span class="summarytext">Alarak temporality gains increased attack and ability damage for each nearby friendly unit.</span></a></div>

    <div class="cteaser" style="text-align: left;"><a class="cteaserimg lightbox" href="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/HNOHGTBR4P8G1473297428143.gif" target="_blank"><img src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/9Z8PV6GXKCLT1473297492505.jpg"/></a> <a class="cteasersummary lightbox" href="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/HNOHGTBR4P8G1473297428143.gif" target="_blank"> <span class="headline">Structure Overcharge</span><br/>
        <span class="summarytext">Temporarily energizes target friendly structure, allowing it to attack nearby enemy ground and air units.</span></a></div>

    <div class="cteaser" style="text-align: left;"><a class="cteaserimg lightbox" href="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/YASPMZLAKLRW1473297426660.gif" target="_blank"><img src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/2M1J03IUI7OA1473297492385.jpg"/></a> <a class="cteasersummary lightbox" href="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/YASPMZLAKLRW1473297426660.gif" target="_blank"> <span class="headline">Summon Death Fleet</span><br/>
        <span class="summarytext">Warps in a Tal’darim Mothership and Destroyers</span></a></div>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/6E0C2R00R29K1473298060090.png" style="margin-top:1em; width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></strong></p>

    <p>The Tal’darim faction has its own unique designs compared to the standard Protoss forces.</p>

    <div class="c-mediaunit">
        <div><img class="c-unit" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/RX0D3BN22MC31473382603051.png"/></div>

        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Slayer</div>

            <div class="c-content">
                <ul>
                    <li>Blink – Instantly teleport a short distance.</li>
                    <li>Phasing Armor – Prevents the Slayer from taking damage temporarily after being attacked.</li>
                </ul>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-mediaunit"><img class="c-unit" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/RIBMYILBENWJ1473382603045.png"/>
        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Havoc [DETECTOR]</div>

            <div class="c-content">
                <ul>
                    <li>Through research, can become permanently cloaked.</li>
                    <li>Target Lock – Increase damage dealt to target enemy.</li>
                    <li>Squad Sight – Increases the non-melee attack range of all nearby friendly units.</li>
                </ul>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-mediaunit">
        <div><img class="c-unit" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/CHYT06NM8VDB1473382602911.png"/></div>

        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Ascendant</div>

            <div class="c-content">
                <ul>
                    <li>Psionic Orb – Unleashes a traveling psionic orb that deals damage to all enemies along its path.</li>
                    <li>Mind Blast – Deals direct damage to target.</li>
                    <li>Sacrifice – Sacrifices a Supplicant to fully restore the Ascendant’s energy.</li>
                </ul>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-mediaunit"><img class="c-unit" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/X6946V8TX9UX1473382603082.png"/>
        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Supplicant</div>

            <div class="c-content">
                <p/>

                <ul>
                    <li>Summons in pairs.</li>
                    <li>Will always be sacrificed first to keep Alarak alive.</li>
                    <li>Can also be sacraficed to fully restore the energy of an Ascendant</li>
                </ul>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-mediaunit"><img class="c-unit" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/5MH4YJVV0XY51473382603003.png"/>
        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Vanguard</div>

            <div class="c-content">
                <ul>
                    <li>Attacks ground units with powerful splash damage.</li>
                    <li>Can be upgraded to deal additional bonus damage to armored units.</li>
                </ul>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-mediaunit"><img class="c-unit" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/YVJFSJHCGE9F1473382602917.png"/>
        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Wrathwalker</div>

            <div class="c-content">
                <ul>
                    <li>High damage, high range, single target attack.</li>
                    <li>Through research, can acquire the ability to attack air.</li>
                </ul>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-mediaunit"><img class="c-unit" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/L9FTAK01PBRT1473382602921.png"/>
        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">War Prism</div>

            <div class="c-content">
                <ul>
                    <li>Can attack air and ground units</li>
                    <li>Transforms at a rapid pace.</li>
                </ul>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/GCPS4CR3AS1Y1473298060250.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></strong></p>

    <div class="c-media">
        <div><img class="c-thumb" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/E615QHLUYLQY1473302311985.png" style="width: 90px; height: 90px;"/></div>

        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Soul Absorption</div>

            <div class="c-content">Alarak heals 20 hit points and restores 20 shields when a nearby enemy unit is slain. Alarak steals life from nearby units you control to heal himself when he is near death. This ability has no cooldown.</div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-media"><img class="c-thumb" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/U3RWXGSFQAR01473302312264.png" style="width: 90px; height: 90px;"/>
        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Overcharge Amplification</div>

            <div class="c-content">Structure Overcharge now also grants a barrier that absorbs damage.</div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-media"><img class="c-thumb" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/BONDOAG0M03J1473302311998.png" style="width: 90px; height: 90px;"/>
        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Aggressive Tactics</div>

            <div class="c-content">Increases the range of Alarak’s Deadly Charge and reduces its cooldown.</div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-media"><img class="c-thumb" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/X74HGIWZ301H1473302312248.png" style="height: 90px; width: 90px;"/>
        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Death Council Upgrade Cache</div>

            <div class="c-content">Unlocks the following upgrades at the Death Council:
                <ul>
                    <li>Supplicants gain bonus shields.</li>
                    <li>Allow Slayers to become temporarily invulnerable after taking damage.</li>
                </ul>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-media">
        <div><img class="c-thumb" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/8CWUM9Y9XYK51473302312067.png" style="width: 90px; height: 90px;"/></div>

        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Empower Me</div>

            <div class="c-content">Unlocks Alarak’s Empower Me ability, which temporarily grants him increased attack and ability damage.</div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-media"><img class="c-thumb" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/0Y9KI276AV9B1473302312152.png" style="width: 90px; height: 90px;"/>
        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Robotics Bay Upgrade Cache</div>

            <div class="c-content">Unlocks the following upgrades at the Robotics Bay:
                <ul>
                    <li>Increase the Vanguard’s splash damage area.</li>
                    <li>Increase the Wrathwalker’s attack speed.</li>
                </ul>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-media">
        <div><img class="c-thumb" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/PKZFYYIHX0JH1473302312182.png" style="width: 90px; height: 90px;"/></div>

        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Lightning Surge</div>

            <div class="c-content">Sacrificing a Supplicant causes Alarak’s next Deadly Charge to deal additional damage to an area near the primary target.</div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-media"><img class="c-thumb" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/3Z4642WUM7X21473302312263.png" style="width: 90px; height: 90px;"/>
        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">New Unit: Ascendant</div>

            <div class="c-content">Potent psionic master. Can use Psionic Orb, Mind Blast, and Sacrifice.</div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-media"><img class="c-thumb" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/SER2FZ797V701473302312101.png" style="height: 90px; width: 90px;"/>
        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Havoc Upgrade Cache</div>

            <div class="c-content">Unlocks the following upgrades at the Cybernetics Core:
                <ul>
                    <li>Increase Target Lock’s bonus damage.</li>
                    <li>Increase the radius of Squad Sight and the range of Target Lock and Force Field.</li>
                </ul>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-media">
        <div><img class="c-thumb" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/q5/Q5UKKS4AK9GT1473309261387.png" style="height: 90px; width: 90px;"/></div>

        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Summon Death Fleet</div>

            <div class="c-content">Unlocks the ability to warp in a Tal’darim Mothership and an escort of Destroyers with timed life.</div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-media"><img class="c-thumb" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/EH54UYIYLWFB1473302312014.png" style="width: 90px; height: 90px;"/>
        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Overpowered</div>

            <div class="c-content">Alarak’s attacks deal area damage while Empower Me is active.</div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-media">
        <div><img class="c-thumb" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/RPAUQY0NR8T71473302312202.png" style="width: 90px; height: 90px;"/></div>

        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Ascendant Upgrade Cache</div>

            <div class="c-content">Unlocks the following upgrades at the Ascendant Archives:
                <ul>
                    <li>Increase the travel distance of the Ascendant’s Psionic Orb.</li>
                    <li>Sacrifice grants Ascendants a stacking permanent increase to ability damage and shields.</li>
                </ul>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-media">
        <div><img class="c-thumb" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/5VDQKTZDUWCU1473302312110.png" style="width: 90px; height: 90px;"/></div>

        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Burning Skies</div>

            <div class="c-content">Unlocks the Mothership’s Thermal Lance ability and warps in 4 additional Destroyers when summoning the Death Fleet.</div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-media"><img class="c-thumb" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/MT1AZZRDP9UN1473302312056.png" style="width: 90px; height: 90px;"/>
        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Alarak Upgrade Cache</div>

            <div class="c-content">Unlocks the following upgrades at the Forge:
                <ul>
                    <li>Allow Alarak’s basic attacks to stun enemies and slow Heroic enemies.</li>
                    <li>Increase Destruction Wave’s knockback distance.</li>
                </ul>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div class="c-media">
        <div><img class="c-thumb" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/9E3OS4NH0GT01473302312175.png" style="width: 90px; height: 90px;"/></div>

        <div class="c-container">
            <div class="c-title">Wrath of the Highlord</div>

            <div class="c-content">Reduces the cooldown of Alarak’s Deadly Charge and Destruction Wave whenever a Supplicant is sacrificed.</div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/page_media/ANW0YFFQEQID1473298060259.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px; box-shadow: 0 0 0px #0F3D70; border-radius: 0px 0px 0px 0px; border: 0px solid #0F3D70"/></strong></p>

    <ul>
        <li>In the early game, use Structure Overcharge to defend against initial attack waves and focus on building up a strong economy. You can also use this to help your pathetic ally in a pinch.</li>
        <li>Since Alarak will kill his own units to selfishly stay alive, always make sure to keep an eye on his health. If he gets into too much trouble, your army will pay the ultimate price.</li>
        <li>Supplicants are an extremely important unit in any army composition. Not only do they have a high amount of life and shields for a relatively low cost, they will also always sacrifice themselves to Alarak before any other unit. Always make sure to keep a healthy supply of Supplicants around if you have a lot of high value units like Vanguard and Wrathwalkers.</li>
        <li>Havocs are Alarak’s form of mobile detection. They also have an upgrade that allows them to be permanently cloaked. In addition to providing detection they also come with a powerful buff for your army and a single target debuff for the enemy. Don’t overlook the value of this unit.</li>
        <li>Alarak’s Empower Me ability has a fairly short cooldown. Make sure to use it proactively to crush the enemy before you lose too many of your own units. Your partner’s army will also empower Alarak, so stick together and open with this ability for a huge push.</li>
        <li>The Deathfleet Mothership has a teleport ability which can let you attack multiple locations in succession. You can use this ability to help an ally or retreat from a bad situation.</li>
        <li>The War Prism is an important unit to keep around so that you can constantly reinforce on the battlefield. Without it, you might find yourself low on Supplicants in the middle of a fight, and be forced to retreat.</li>
        <li>Alarak favors a ground battle and therefore does not have any need for a Stargate. When facing an enemy that favors air units, make sure you have the right composition to take them out. A healthy combination of Slayers, upgraded Wrathwalkers, and Alarak’s own Destruction Wave can deal with both swarms of smaller units as well as large targets.</li>
    </ul>

    <div style="margin-left:.25in;">
        <hr/>
        <p/>
    </div>

    <p>Alarak is joining the fight with the release of Patch 3.6 and can be unlocked for $4.99. Considering the formidable challenge that Custom Mutators offers, the High Lord will be a welcome addition to your collection of Commanders.</p>
    <style type="text/css">#column-content {
        display: inline-block;
        }
        img {
        vertical-align: middle;
        }
        span {
        vertical-align: middle;
        display: inline-block;
        line-height: 20px;
        }
        /* for visual purposes */
        #column-content {
        /* border: 1px solid red; */
        position: relative;
        text-align:right;
        }
        #blog .detail img {
        -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 10px #0F3D70;
        -moz-border-radius: 4px 4px 4px 4px;
        -webkit-border-radius: 4px 4px 4px 4px;
        box-shadow: 0 0 10px #0F3D70;
        border-radius: 4px 4px 4px 4px;
        border: 1px solid #0F3D70;
        max-width: 575px !important;
        padding: 1px;
        }
        #blog .detail .center {
        width: 590px;
        margin: 0px auto;
        margin-bottom:50px;
        }
        #blog .detail div.ctextheadline {
        position: relative;
        display: block;
        text-decoration: none;
        line-height:1 !important;
        font-family: Arial !important;
        margin-bottom:60px;
        }
        #blog .detail div.ctextheadline h1 {
        position: absolute;
        top: 13px;
        left: 30px;
        color: #FFFFFF !important;
        font-size: 30px !important;
        text-shadow: 0 0 5px #000000
        }
        #blog .detail div.cteaser, #blog .detail img, #blog .detail div.cteaserg {
        -moz-border-radius:4px;
        -webkit-border-radius:4px;
        border-radius:4px;
        <!---moz-box-shadow:0 0 20px #000000;-->
        <!---webkit-box-shadow:0 0 20px #000000;-->
        <!--box-shadow:0 0 20px #000000;-->
        border: 1px solid transparent;
        padding: 1px;
        }
        #blog .detail div.cteaser, #blog .detail div.cteaserg {
        width: 285px;
        height: 144px;
        margin: 8px 3px 0px 3px;
        padding-top: 5px;
        background-color: #001935;
        float:left;
        }
        #blog .detail div.cteaser:hover {
        border: 1px solid #5BBFD3;
        background-color: #0C5EAF;
        }
        /* Info and Coverage Boxes */
        #blog .detail div.cninfo {
        width: 190px;
        margin: 25px 20px 10px 20px;
        float: left;
        }
        #blog .detail div.cninfo, #blog .detail div.cncoverage {
        -moz-border-radius: 8px 8px 8px 8px;
        -webkit-border-radius: 8px 8px 8px 8px;
        border: 1px solid #5BBFD3;
        border-radius: 8px 8px 8px 8px;
        box-shadow: 0 0 10px #000;
        -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 10px #000;
        background-color: #001935;
        background-image: url();
        background-repeat: repeat-x;
        }
        #blog .detail div.cncoverage h1, #blog .detail div.cninfo h1 {
        margin: 0px;
        padding: 3px 10px 3px 10px;
        color: #fff;
        font-weight: bold;
        }
        #blog .detail div.cncoverage p, #blog .detail div.cninfo p {
        margin: 5px 10px 5px 10px;
        }
        #blog .detail .cteaser .cteaser
        , #blog .detail .cteaserg div.cteaserimg {
        display: block;
        width: 125px;
        height: 140px;
        text-align: center;
        float: left;
        }
        #blog .detail .cteaser .cteaserimg img, #blog .detail .cteaserg div.cteaserimg img {
        -moz-border-radius:10px;
        -webkit-border-radius:10px;
        border-radius:10px;
        -moz-box-shadow:0 0 20px #000000;
        -webkit-box-shadow:0 0 20px #000000;
        box-shadow:0 0 20px #000000;
        border: 1px solid #001935;
        vertical-align: middle;
        width: 109px;
        height: 94px;
        margin-top: 10px;
        padding: 1px;
        }
        #blog .detail .cteaser .cteasersummary, #blog .detail .cteaserg div.cteasersummary {
        display: block;
        padding-right: 3px;
        padding-left:5px;
        line-height: 1.4 !important;
        width: 157px;
        height: 140px;
        float: left;
        }
        #blog .detail .cteaser .cteasersummary span.headline, #blog .detail .cteaserg div.cteasersummary span.headline {
        color: #00d683 !important;
        font-size: 17px !important;
        text-weight: bold !important;
        }
        #blog .detail .cteaser .cteasersummary span.summarytext, #blog .detail .cteaserg div.cteasersummary span.summarytext {
        color: #5ca6ca !important;
        font-size: 12px !important;
        }
        .top-list tr:nth-child(2) td {
        color: #5ca6ca;
        background-color: transparent;
        }
        .top-list-interior table tbody tr td {
        background-color: none !important;
        color: #EFC9A0 !important;
        font-weight: normal !important;
        vertical-align: top;
        }
        .top-list-interior table tbody tr:hover td {
        color: #fff !important;
        }
        #blog .detail td:hover > a img, #blog .detail a img:hover {
        border: 1px solid #5BBFD3;
        }
        #blog .detail hr {
        width:100%;
        height: 8px;
        background:url('https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_folder_media/uc/UC41OX15L4721447100108007.jpg') center center no-repeat;
        border: none;
        margin-top: 15px;
        margin-bottom: 15px;
        }
        #blog .detail .schedule {
        margin-top: 1px;
        width: 100%;
        background-color: #000819;
        }
        #blog .detail .schedule th {
        background-color: #001935;
        color: #fff;
        font-weight: bold;
        height: 30px;
        padding-left: 5px;
        text-align: left;
        }
        #blog .detail .schedule .status {
        padding-left: 0;
        width: 70px;
        }
        #blog .detail .schedule td {
        border-bottom: 1px solid #00214B;
        vertical-align: top;
        height: 26px;
        padding-left: 5px;
        }
        #blog .detail .schedule tr:hover {
        background-color: #0C5EAF;
        }
        .c-media {
        width: 100%;
        display: flex;
        align-items: flex-start;
        margin: 1.5em 0;
        }
        .c-thumb {
        width: 90px;
        height: 90px;
        margin-right: 1em;
        -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 10px #0F3D70;
        -moz-border-radius: 4px 4px 4px 4px;
        -webkit-border-radius: 4px 4px 4px 4px;
        box-shadow: 0 0 10px #0F3D70;
        border-radius: 4px 4px 4px 4px;
        border: 1px solid #0F3D70;
        padding: 1px;
        }
        .c-title {
        margin: 0px 0 0;
        padding: 0;
        font-size: 1.15em;
        font-weight: bold;
        color: white;
        }
        .c-unit {
        width: 110px;
        height: 117px;
        margin-right: 1em;
        -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 10px #0F3D70;
        -moz-border-radius: 4px 4px 4px 4px;
        -webkit-border-radius: 4px 4px 4px 4px;
        box-shadow: 0 0 10px #0F3D70;
        border-radius: 4px 4px 4px 4px;
        border: 1px solid #0F3D70;
        padding: 1px;
        }
        .c-mediaunit {
        width: 100%;
        display: flex;
        align-items: center;
        margin: 1.5em 0;
        }
        .c-content {
        display: block;
        margin: 0 0 6px;
        padding:0
        }
    </style>
</div></content></entry><entry><title type="text">Afreeca StarLeague Finals: Survival Guide</title><published>2016-09-08T19:00:00.000Z</published><updated>2016-09-09T17:13:58.064Z</updated><id>20280558</id><link href="http://us.battle.net//sc2/en/blog/20280558"/><summary type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Afreeca StarLeague has reached its epic conclusion! Find out all the details about the impending finals inside our exclusive blog. </div></summary><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/9AA33FC3YIXD1456525140808.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <p>After three months of intense Brood War action, the Afreeca StarLeague has arrived at its Grand Finals featuring none other than Shuttle vs Sharp. Both players faced extreme adversity on their way to this stage of the tournament, as players as notorious as Flash, Sea, and Last were knocked out in the earlier stages.</p>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/EOAQZ19Z5SL31456525140812.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <p><strong style="line-height: 2;"><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/3A5UFDSHVW2E1461633878646.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></strong></p>

    <p style="margin-left: 40px;"><strong><span lang="ES-CL" style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; border: 1pt none windowtext; padding: 0in;">AfreecaTV</span></strong></p>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/UC54KWSDCQIL1461633878381.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></strong></p>

    <p style="margin-left: 40px;"/>

    <p style="margin-left: 40px;">Stage of Neugdong Forest at Children’s Grand Park</p>

    <p/>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/P0RXKMM56BCB1461633878377.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></strong></p>

    <p/>

    <ul style="margin-left: 40px;">
        <li><strong>PDT</strong> – Friday, September 9 @ 10:30 p.m.</li>
        <li><strong>CEST</strong> – Saturday, September 10 @ 7:30 a.m.</li>
        <li><strong>KST</strong> – Saturday, September 10 @ 2:30 p.m.</li>
    </ul>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/74/74EL1VN1SIOJ1462817118211.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></strong></p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"/>

    <p><strong>English:</strong></p>

    <p/>

    <ul>
        <li><strong>Commentator:</strong> Nick ‘<a href="https://twitter.com/CallMeTasteless">Tasteless</a>’ Plott</li>
        <li><strong>Commentator:</strong> Dan ‘<a href="https://twitter.com/artosis">Artosis</a>’ Stemkoski</li>
    </ul>

    <p><strong>Korean:</strong></p>

    <ul>
        <li><strong>Commentator: </strong>Park Sanghyun</li>
        <li><strong>Commentator: </strong>Lim Sungchoon</li>
        <li><strong>Commentator: </strong>Lee Seungwon</li>
    </ul>

    <p/>

    <p style="margin-left: 40px;"/>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/content_entry_media/UGVCJOCY0VR61461633878783.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></strong></p>

    <div>
        <ul>
            <li><strong>English:</strong> <a href="http://blizz.ly/ASL">http://blizz.ly/ASL</a></li>
            <li><strong>English Alternate: </strong><a href="http://twitch.tv/gsl">http://twitch.tv/gsl</a></li>
            <li><strong>Korean</strong>: <a href="http://www.twitch.tv/starcraft">h</a><a href="http://http//afreeca.com/afgsl">ttp//afreeca.com/afgsl</a></li>
            <li><strong>Korean Alternate</strong>: <a href="http://sports.news.naver.com">http://sports.news.naver.com</a></li>
        </ul>
    </div>

    <p><strong><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/72F3VNXFXU5T1456525140887.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></strong></p>

    <p>The ASL Finals will feature a best-of-5 battle between Jo '<a href="http://wiki.teamliquid.net/starcraft/Sharp">Sharp</a>' Giseok and Kim '<a href="http://wiki.teamliquid.net/starcraft/Shuttle_(Player)">Eyewater</a>' Yoonjung,</p>

    <p style="text-align: center;"/>

    <p><strong>Total event prize pool</strong>:  ₩24,000,000 KRW (~$21,600 USD)</p>

    <ul>
        <li>1st place: $13,500</li>
        <li>2nd place: $2,700</li>
    </ul>

    <p style="margin-left:.5in;"/>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/6CIHWYY3WT011456525140946.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <p>Join in on the conversation about these games here!</p>

    <ul>
        <li><a href="http://www.teamliquid.net/">TeamLiquid.net</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://reddit.com/r/starcraft">Reddit.com/r/StarCraft</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/forum/13436/">Esports Forum on StarCraft2.com</a></li>
    </ul>

    <p><img alt="" src="https://bnetcmsus-a.akamaihd.net/cms/gallery/97768W48B3ZN1456525140917.png" style="width: 600px; height: 50px;"/></p>

    <p><a href="http://wiki.teamliquid.net/starcraft/2016_Afreeca_Starleague">Liquipedia Page</a></p>
</div></content></entry></feed>