<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- generator="Joomla! - Open Source Content Management" -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>StarCraft: Legacy</title>
        <description></description>
        <link>http://sclegacy.com/index.php/component/content/?view=featured</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 08:16:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Joomla! - Open Source Content Management</generator>
        <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://sclegacy.com/index.php?format=feed&amp;type=rss"/>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <item>
            <title>Blizzard @ Gamescom 2016 - Video Games Live StarCraft II LotV Intro Cinematic</title>
            <link>http://sclegacy.com/index.php/news/9-events/1399-blizzard-gamescom-2016-video-games-live-starcraft-ii-intro-cinematic</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sclegacy.com/index.php/news/9-events/1399-blizzard-gamescom-2016-video-games-live-starcraft-ii-intro-cinematic</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<div class="feed-description"><center><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/gamescom16/blizzardgamescom2016.png" /></center>
<p> </p>
<p>For the last few days, <strong>Blizzard</strong> has been putting on an excellent show in Cologne, Germany at <strong>Gamescom 2016</strong>. During this event, Blizzard has produced show matches, tournaments, signing sessions, a cosplay contest, hosted community streamers, provided interviews, and unveiled a host of new content for all of their franchises. This year it seems like Blizzard has worked hard to provide the Europeans with an experience similar to BlizzCon. Not since the discontinued <strong>World Wide Invitational</strong> events, has Blizzard released this amount and quality of content programming exclusively at a European event. It's a welcome change considering that the last World Wide Invitational took place June 28 - 29, 2008 in Paris, France and Blizzard's audience is now truly global.</p>
<p>On Saturday night, Blizzard invited the <strong>City of Prague Philharmonic Orchestra</strong>, conducted by Blizzard's Audio Director/Composer <strong>Russel Brower</strong>, to perform a special <strong>Video Games Live</strong> concert set against Blizzard montages and cinematics. The entire event was live streamed across the world and it included several never before performed pieces, including the music/choral accompaniment to the <em>StarCraft II: Legacy of the Void</em> intro cinematic.</p>
<center>
<p><blockquote class="twitter-video" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">.<a href="https://twitter.com/VideoGamesLive">@VideoGamesLive</a> joins the Khala! More <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/gamescom2016?src=hash">#gamescom2016</a> content here: <a href="https://t.co/2gahYa6Gl3">https://t.co/2gahYa6Gl3</a><a href="https://t.co/bw83RcQqgN">https://t.co/bw83RcQqgN</a></p>&mdash; StarCraft (@StarCraft) <a href="https://twitter.com/StarCraft/status/767375121908502528">August 21, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async src="http://sclegacy.com///platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
</center>
<br />
<p>Watching the <em>Legacy of the Void</em> cinematic come to life was impressive. In addition, the set also included music from <em>Wings of Legacy</em>. At Gamescom, Blizzard and Video Games Live provided an excellent performance that included pieces spanning the width and breadth of Blizzard's games. You can watch the entire concert <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mVlpkEGBpno">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Sources:</strong> <br /><a href="https://gamescom.blizzard.com/en-gb/">Blizzard.com - Blizzard Entertainment - Gamescom 2016</a> <br /> <a href="https://twitter.com/StarCraft/status/767375121908502528">Twitter.com - @StarCraft - Video Games Live Joins the Khala!</a> <br /> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mVlpkEGBpno">Youtube.com - Video Games Live Concert at Gamescom 2016</a></p></div>]]></description>
            <author>lordofascension@gmail.com (LordofAscension)</author>
            <category>Featured</category>
            <category>Events</category>
            <category>News</category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 02:12:43 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Nova: Covert Ops Announced</title>
            <link>http://sclegacy.com/index.php/news/22-starcraft-ii/1395-nova-covert-ops-announced</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sclegacy.com/index.php/news/22-starcraft-ii/1395-nova-covert-ops-announced</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<div class="feed-description"><p>A new set of missions has been announced, featuring Nova as the main character.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NImK4R5wEfg" frameborder="0" width="560" height="315"></iframe></p>
<p> </p>
<p>The first set of mission packs is set to be released in Spring 2016.</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong><br /><a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/blog/19953693/nova-covert-ops-announced-11-6-2015" target="_blank">Battle.net - Nova Covert Ops Announced!</a><br /><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NImK4R5wEfg" target="_blank">YouTube - StarCraft II: Nova Covert Ops</a></p></div>]]></description>
            <author>nova1492_mephisto@yahoo.com (KDraconis)</author>
            <category>Featured</category>
            <category>StarCraft II</category>
            <category>News</category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 21:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Legacy of the Void Launch Trailer</title>
            <link>http://sclegacy.com/index.php/news/22-starcraft-ii/1394-legacy-of-the-void-launch-trailer</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sclegacy.com/index.php/news/22-starcraft-ii/1394-legacy-of-the-void-launch-trailer</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<div class="feed-description"><p>The launch trailer for Legacy of the Void has been released, showing some new footage.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8UyMAPr-G44" frameborder="0" width="560" height="315"></iframe></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong><br /><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8UyMAPr-G44" target="_blank">YouTube - StarCraft II: Legacy of the Void Launch Trailer – Legacy</a></p></div>]]></description>
            <author>nova1492_mephisto@yahoo.com (KDraconis)</author>
            <category>Featured</category>
            <category>StarCraft II</category>
            <category>News</category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 20:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>StarCraft II Patch 3.0 - Battle.net UI Upgrades Preview</title>
            <link>http://sclegacy.com/index.php/news/25-battle-net/1393-legacy-of-the-void-battle-net-ui-upgrades</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sclegacy.com/index.php/news/25-battle-net/1393-legacy-of-the-void-battle-net-ui-upgrades</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<div class="feed-description"><center><a href="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/battlenetnews/sc2-ui-refresh/lotv-ui-interface-refesh-large.jpg"><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/battlenetnews/sc2-ui-refresh/lotv-ui-interface-refesh-small.png" /></a></center>
<p> </p>
<p>In anticipation of <em>Legacy of the Void</em><em>'s </em>release next month, <strong>Blizzard</strong> has announced a significant refresh to the <em>StarCraft II </em>user interface. The updates will be released with the forthcoming Patch 3.0 for all instances of <em>StarCraft II</em>, including <em>Wings of Liberty, Heart of the Swarm</em>, and even the <em>Starter Edition</em>. The overall goal of the revisions was to create a more social experience in the client and the specific areas of focus were a direct result of community feedback. The update provides extensive improvements to the Arcade, the chat system, and the menus throughout the client, including the introduction of additional hotkeys.</p>
<p>One of the most impactful changes is that the menu navigation is has been localized entirely within the top-left corner of the screen. The Arcade menu has been completely overhauled, placing map info directly in the menu screen and moving 'Open Games' to be the default module. Accordingly, the 'Open Games' list is now quicker and easier to browse. Chat now has a permanent space along the right side of the player's screen and the interface has been designed so that it will never interfere with the new menu navigation. Blizzard has eliminated the multi-window regime from the previous design and instead has streamlined the chat experience into one chat window with multiple conversation tabs. To learn more about all of the changes, you can read <a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/blog/19911221/new-user-interface-coming-to-starcraft-ii-10-2-2015" target="_blank">Blizzard's announcement post</a> and watch a summary video below:</p>
<p> </p>
<center><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qXB6sIVdg04" frameborder="0" width="560" height="315"></iframe></center>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<blockquote><strong>Overhauling the UI<br /></strong>To ensure this new chat system would work well with the rest of the UI, it became clear we would have to redesign the rest of the game’s screens so we meticulously overhauled the spacing, format, and content of every section. In order to give our content more space, we moved the navigation, sub-navigation, and the party panel to the top of the screen. With this extra room, we saw an opportunity to inlay new 3D scenes into every screen to further bring the StarCraft universe to life in the UI. </blockquote>
<p> </p>
<p>As an homage to the nostalgia that has persisted for more than seventeen years, Blizzard redesigned the <em>StarCraft II </em>campaign menu in the style of the original <em>StarCraft </em>and <em>Brood War </em>menus. While we are delighted by the throwback, technically, <em>Wings of Liberty, Heart of the Swarm, and Legacy of the Void</em> represent episodes 7, 8, and 9, in the <em>StarCraft saga</em>. Blizzard likely wishes to avoid the resulting confusion from new players to the franchise and view the <em>StarCraft II</em> campaigns as a standalone trilogy. However, we would love to see an alternative naming convention the respects the continuity of the story line. Better yet, having placeholder menus for the older campaigns that open short summaries and have links to the <em>StarCraft </em>and <em>Brood War </em>game clients would be an excellent gateway mechanic to entice a new generation to experience the original source material.</p>
<p> </p>
<center><a href="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/battlenetnews/sc2-ui-refresh/sc2-campaign-screen-refresh-large.jpg"><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/battlenetnews/sc2-ui-refresh/sc2-campaign-screen-refresh-small.png" /></a><em><br />The Redesigned StarCraft II Campaign Menu</em></center>
<p> </p>
<center><a href="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/battlenetnews/sc2-ui-refresh/starcraft-campaign-interface-large.png"><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/battlenetnews/sc2-ui-refresh/starcraft-campagin-interface-small.png" /></a><em><br />The Original StarCraft Campaign Menu</em></center>
<p> </p>
<center><a href="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/battlenetnews/sc2-ui-refresh/brood-war-campaign-interface-small.png"><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/battlenetnews/sc2-ui-refresh/brood-war-campaign-interface-small.png" /></a><em><br />The StarCraft: Brood War Campaign Menu<br /></em></center>
<p> </p>
<p>The new interface design appears to inspired by minimalist design principles and due to the resulting simplicity, it possesses a clean modern aesthetic. By streamlining the menu and chat systems, Blizzard has addressed many of the longstanding original user interface issues that have caused vocal and widespread concern throughout the community since the introduction of Battle.net 2.0. The community has <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/starcraft/comments/3n9ggp/new_user_interface_coming_to_starcraft_ii/" target="_blank">responded positively</a> to the portions of the refresh previewed and, perhaps more importantly, to this example of Blizzard's willingness to invest in fundamental revisions to existing systems. Many in the community have noted and celebrated the similarities between the changes inherent in this revamp and the original Battle.net features found in <em>Brood War</em>, perhaps proving that great gameplay wasn't <em>Brood War's </em>only legacy. A perfect mix of new and old, Blizzard has always been forthright about their iterative process and this redesign is a perfect example of the goodwill and success that results that come from that strong commitment to game's ecosystem. These adjustments to the UI have the potential to drastically improve both current and future fans' <em>StarCraft </em>experiences.</p>
<p>While no specific date has been announced for Patch 3.0, luckily fans do not have long to wait, the update will be coming before <em>Legacy of the Void's </em>launch on November 10, 2015.</p>
<p><strong>Sources:</strong><br /><a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/blog/19911221/new-user-interface-coming-to-starcraft-ii-10-2-2015">Battle.net - New User Interface Coming to StarCraft II</a><br /><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qXB6sIVdg04" target="_blank">YouTube.com - StarCraft II - Patch 3.0 UI Revamp</a><br /><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/starcraft/comments/3n9ggp/new_user_interface_coming_to_starcraft_ii/" target="_blank">StarCraft SubReddit - New User Interface Coming to StarCraft II</a></p></div>]]></description>
            <author>lordofascension@gmail.com (LordofAscension)</author>
            <category>Featured</category>
            <category>Battle.net</category>
            <category>News</category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 05:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>StarCraft Pre-LotV Short Story Schedule Announced</title>
            <link>http://sclegacy.com/index.php/news/22-starcraft-ii/1392-starcraft-pre-lotv-short-story-schedule-announced</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sclegacy.com/index.php/news/22-starcraft-ii/1392-starcraft-pre-lotv-short-story-schedule-announced</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<div class="feed-description"><p>As Blizzard's <strong>James Waugh</strong>, Director of Story Development &amp; Lead Writer for <em>StarCraft II, </em>recently announced at TwitchCon, there are five new <em>StarCraft</em> lore short stories currently in production. Today, Blizzard announced the release schedule for all five stories.</p>
<p> </p>
<center><a href="http://sclegacy.com/public_html/images/uploaded/starcraftiinews/lotvlaunch/starcraft-lore-pre-lotv-short-story-schedule-large.jpg"><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/starcraftiinews/lotvlaunch/starcraft-lore-pre-lotv-short-story-schedule-small.png" /></a></center>
<p> </p>
<p>Blizzard has been slowly producing lore focused <em>StarCraft</em> short stories by various authors for several years now. The heaviest concentration of new material has consistently been released to build up hype leading up to the game launches and relevantly, these newest stories will all be published before <em>Legacy of the Void</em> drops on November 10, 2015. These Protoss-centric stories will likely endeavor to illustrate specific moments in their history, flesh out their culture and motivations in more detail, and act as a bridge between the previous games and what is to come in LotV. The last story, <em><a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/game/lore/short-stories/the-exit/1" target="_blank">The Exit</a></em>, by <strong>Danny McAleese</strong> was published on July 1, 2014.</p>
<p>Hopefully, these novellas will breathe some fresh air into the <em>StarCraft</em> lore and provide some great contextual clues for what is to come in <em>Legacy of the Void</em>. Check back after each short story's release for a brief summary and our review.</p>
<p><strong>Sources:</strong><br /><a href="https://twitter.com/StarCraft/status/648633352505810946">Twitter.com - @StarCraft - Legacy of the Void Short Stories Schedule</a><br /><a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/game/lore/" target="_blank">Battle.net - StarCraft II - The StarCraft Universe</a><br /><br /></p></div>]]></description>
            <author>lordofascension@gmail.com (LordofAscension)</author>
            <category>Featured</category>
            <category>StarCraft II</category>
            <category>News</category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 19:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>StarCraft Reclamation Released</title>
            <link>http://sclegacy.com/index.php/news/22-starcraft-ii/1391-starcraft-reclamation-released</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sclegacy.com/index.php/news/22-starcraft-ii/1391-starcraft-reclamation-released</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<div class="feed-description"><center><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/starcraftiinews/lotvlaunch/reclamation/reclamation-title.png" /></center>
<p> </p>
<p>Today during <strong>Blizzard's</strong> TwitchCon presentation, <strong>James Waugh</strong>, Director of Story Development &amp; Lead Writer of <em>Legacy of the Void</em>, and <strong>Matt Morris</strong>, <em>Legacy of the Void</em> Lead Campaign Designer, revealed the full version of the animated short, <em>StarCraft Reclamation</em> teased at the WCS Season 3 Premier League Finals in Kraków, Poland on September 13. You can watch the reveal <a href="http://www.twitch.tv/twitch/v/17715268" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<center><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uQnmfEka3vw" frameborder="0" width="560" height="315"></iframe></center>
<p> </p>
<p>The feature acts as a prequel to the beautiful <a href="http://sclegacy.com/index.php/news/22-starcraft-ii/1385-legacy-of-the-void-opening-cinematic-revealed" target="_blank"><em>Legacy of the Void</em> opening cinematic</a> that was also released at the WCS Season 3 finals a few weeks ago. <em>Reclamation</em> takes place on the eve of the Protoss' Golden Armada attempt to retake Aiur from the Zerg. In it, Artanis, Tassadar's protege and the Protoss Hierarch, contemplates his decision to invade Aiur and the typical burdens of leadership.</p>
<p> </p>
<center><a href="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/starcraftiinews/lotvlaunch/reclamation/reclamation-contemplation.png"><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/starcraftiinews/lotvlaunch/reclamation/reclamation-contemplation-small.png" /></a></center><center><em>Artanis and Kaldaris</em></center>
<p> </p>
<p>The short opens with Artanis contemplating the future in solitude. When Artanis' old friend, Khaldaris, the one-eyed Protoss Zealot featured in the intro cinematic, comes looking for him, Artanis shares his uncertainty of their current course. Lamenting the diminished number of Protoss that remain, he questions the wisdom of spending more lives to retake a relic of his race's past.</p>
<p> </p>
<center><a href="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/starcraftiinews/lotvlaunch/reclamation/reclamation-aiur-before-fall.png"><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/starcraftiinews/lotvlaunch/reclamation/reclamation-aiur-before-fall-small.png" /></a></center><center><em>Aiur - Before the Fall</em></center>
<p> </p>
<p>He muses whether the lost home world represents an ideal that is no longer practical or even desirable. Artanis recalls of the <a href="http://starcraft.wikia.com/wiki/Aeon_of_Strife" target="_blank">Aeon of Strife</a>, the <a href="http://starcraft.wikia.com/wiki/Dark_Templar#Origins" target="_blank">Dark Templar's choice to reject the Khala</a>, and the <a href="http://starcraft.wikia.com/wiki/Dark_Templar#Exile" target="_blank">Conclave's subsequent attempt to exterminate the rogue faction</a> - members of their own species. He believes that Aiur's version of purity was the foundation of the Protoss' destruction. So enamored with their own infallibility, Aiur became a monument to the hubris that inevitably lead to their defeat at the hands of the Zerg. </p>
<p> </p>
<center><a href="http://sclegacy.com/'http:/sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/starcraftiinews/lotvlaunch/reclamation/Kaldaris.jpg"><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/starcraftiinews/lotvlaunch/reclamation/Kaldaris-small.png" /></a></center><center><em>Kaldaris</em></center>
<p> </p>
<p>When challenged by his old friend, Kaldaris, the one-eyed Protoss Zealot featured in the intro cinematic, Kaldaris reminds him that there has been light throughout the darkness. He points out that <a href="http://starcraft.wikia.com/wiki/Khas" target="_blank">Khas</a>, the Protoss who introduced the <a href="http://starcraft.wikia.com/wiki/Khala" target="_blank">Khala</a> to the Protoss - thus ending the Aeon of Strife, forged order from the chaos. Kaldalis believes that retaking Aiur represents a new beginning for a united Protoss. He argues, that remaking Aiur as it could have been - how it could be - is worth dying for. He believes in it so much that he has volunteered to lead the vanguard and one of the first to step back on Aiur's sacred soil. He expects to perish in the attempt and in doing so provide a future for his people. Kaldaris epitomizes the ideal Protoss warrior and he is ultimately successful in convincing Artanis that Aiur is worth fighting for - it is worth dying for.</p>
<p><br />The short is elegantly animated, well scripted, and exquisitely voiced. It hits most of the major notes that many fans were hoping for, and ties-in wonderfully with the Protoss ethos. It is a compelling intro to all of the themes and Protoss characteristics that Blizzard has been saying they want to include in <em>Legacy of the Void</em>. If the material we have seen so far is any indication of <em>Legacy of the Void's</em> campaign story and dialogue, it could very well be the best of the trilogy - by far. Our only complaints regarding <em>Reclamation</em> revolve around missing references to Fenix, Tassadar, and Adun. Those warriors represent the very best of the Protoss, and all three, directly or indirectly, were major influences on Artanis. It would have been nice to have seen them included in Artanis' recollection. He has lost much and their deeds are as much a reflection of the Protoss as they are of who Artanis has become. However, <em>Reclamation</em> does do all of the right things and it is a wonderful tool to hype <em>Legacy of the Void</em>. As Blizzard continues to explore new ways to effectively continue the <em>StarCraft</em> story, short vignettes like this are, in our opinion, an excellent option - more, please.</p>
<p><strong>Sources:</strong><br /><a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/blog/19905106/starcraft-ii-legacy-of-the-void-reclamation-9-25-2015" target="_blank">Battle.net - StarCraft II: Legacy of the Void - Reclamation</a><br /><a href="http://www.twitch.tv/twitch/v/17715268" target="_blank">Twitch.tv - TwitchCon 2015 - Blizzard Announcement</a><br /><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uQnmfEka3vw" target="_blank">YouTube.com - StarCraft II: Legacy of the Void - Reclamation</a></p></div>]]></description>
            <author>lordofascension@gmail.com (LordofAscension)</author>
            <category>Featured</category>
            <category>StarCraft II</category>
            <category>News</category>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2015 06:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>StarCraft: The Story So Far - By Carbot Animations</title>
            <link>http://sclegacy.com/index.php/2-uncategorised/1397-starcraft-the-story-so-far-by-carbot-animations</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sclegacy.com/index.php/2-uncategorised/1397-starcraft-the-story-so-far-by-carbot-animations</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<div class="feed-description"><center><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/starcraftiinews/StarCrafts.jpg" /></center>
<p> </p>
<p>Check out the story so far!</p>
<center>
<blockquote>StarCraft is a series that dates all the way back to 1998, and with so much history we wouldn’t be surprised if you’ve forgotten some things along the years. With that in mind, Carbot Animations has created a video that serves as a rather jovial approach in rapidly teaching you the story of StarCraft.</blockquote>
</center>
<p><strong>Source:</strong><br /><a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/blog/19906382/starcraft-the-story-so-far-by-carbot-animations-9-25-2015">Battle.net - StarCraft: The Story So Far - By Carbot Animations</a></p></div>]]></description>
            <author>dmtower@gmail.com (David Tower)</author>
            <category>Featured</category>
            <category>Uncategorised</category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 23:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Co-op Missions: Additional Commanders Revealed</title>
            <link>http://sclegacy.com/index.php/2-uncategorised/1398-co-op-missions-additional-commanders-revealed</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sclegacy.com/index.php/2-uncategorised/1398-co-op-missions-additional-commanders-revealed</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<div class="feed-description"><center><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/starcraftiinews/Addl%20Commanders.jpg" /></center>
<p> </p>
<center>In addition to the commanders already announced (Raynor, Kerrigan, and Artanis), <strong>Blizzard</strong> has announced 3 new commanders for Co-op Missions!</center><center><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/starcraftiinews/Swan.png" /></center>
<p> </p>
<center>
<blockquote>Swann is a mechanical master of all things Terran. With Swann, you’ll have access to unique and advanced weaponry, which you can use to wreak unspeakable mayhem across the battlefield. Beginning each game with a massive laser drill, Swann will be unable to construct a Barracks. Instead, Swann relies entirely upon his mechanical prowess, and once he’s constructed his army there is little that can stop him.</blockquote>
</center>
<p> </p>
<center><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/starcraftiinews/Zagara.png" /><center><br /><center>
<blockquote>As Zagara, you’ll experience with profound clarity why the Zerg are referred to as the Swarm. You’ll multiply your economy at breakneck speeds, and spawn units in relentless waves to assault your opponents. Zagara herself will be present on the battlefield, hosting a repertoire of abilities to lend aid to your efforts. Zagara can call down sacs that rain damage and more Zerg creatures, or spawn potent Hunter Killers to take down priority targets. Zagara can even increase the combat prowess of all friendly units by sending them into a frenzy.</blockquote>
</center></center></center>
<p> </p>
<center><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/starcraftiinews/Vorazun.png" /></center>
<p> </p>
<center>
<blockquote>Vorazun leverages the advanced technology of the Protoss with the cunning and adaptable aspects of the Dark Templar to devastating effect. Gain access to some of the most mysterious powers of the Protoss, such as Dark Archons, and use ancient technologies to perform powerful feats—like stopping time itself. With Vorazun, you’ll have some of the most versatile tools in the StarCraft universe available to you . . . the question is, will you be crafty enough to claim victory?</blockquote>
</center>
<p><br /> <strong>Source:</strong><br /> <a>Battle.net - Co-op Missions: Additional Commanders Revealed</a></p></div>]]></description>
            <author>dmtower@gmail.com (David Tower)</author>
            <category>Featured</category>
            <category>Uncategorised</category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:05:16 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Blizzard Announces Partnership with Random House</title>
            <link>http://sclegacy.com/index.php/news/16-blizzard/1389-blizzard-announces-partnership-with-random-house</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sclegacy.com/index.php/news/16-blizzard/1389-blizzard-announces-partnership-with-random-house</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<div class="feed-description"><center><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/blizzardnews/blizzard-random-house.png" /></center>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Blizzard</strong> recently announced a new partnership with <strong>Random House LLC</strong> to publish new novels set in Blizzard's various universes. While only novels for Warcraft and StarCraft were disclosed, the announcement did hint that there may be future plans for tales set in Blizzard's other IPs.<br /><br /></p>
<blockquote>This new publishing line will launch in March 2016 with the novel <em>World of Warcraft: Illidan</em> by <strong>William King</strong>, followed by an original <em>StarCraft</em> novel by New York Times bestselling author <strong>Timothy Zahn</strong>.</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<p>This announcement marks the first true <em>StarCraft </em>novel since <em>Heart of the Swarm's </em>2012 <em>Flashpoint</em> by <strong>Christie Golden</strong>. However, <a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/game/lore/" target="_blank">several other short stories</a> have continued to be published on Battle.net in the intervening years. The most recent of which was <em><a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/game/lore/short-stories/the-exit/1" target="_blank">The Exit</a></em> by <strong>Danny McAleese</strong>. Not only do expanded universe projects benefit the fans, they also provide yet another means for players to become engaged in the universe. For people already invested, additional transmedia works reinforce that loyalty and passion. Perhaps it is most fitting for <em>StarCraft </em>branded projects that they form and maintain such a unique and powerful symbiotic relationship. Abathur would likely approve of the elegant efficiency.</p>
<p> </p>
<center><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ADbDN5MsUV4" frameborder="0" width="560" height="315"></iframe></center>
<p> </p>
<p>It appears that the <em>StarCraft</em> novel by Timothy Zahn will provide Blizzard an opportunity to push the story forward, past the <em>StarCraft II</em> game trilogy and focus on the aftermath of the Koprulu Sector as we have known it so far. Utilizing novels, with their limitless potential for world building, seems to be a good move by Blizzard to bridge the gap between the current story and whatever is next. Hopefully, the novel(s) will be long enough to provide serious depth, mature story lines, compelling characters. One of the developers once told us that the novels give the Blizzard the opportunity to illustrate a particular aspect of the story definitively. With fidelity to that vision and high caliber writing, quality <em>StarCraft </em>lore could live on beyond the games for years to come.</p>
<p><strong>Sources:<br /></strong><a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/blog/19897906/blizzard-entertainment-and-random-house-llc-partner-for-new-novels-9-18-2015" target="_blank">Battle.net - Blizzard Entertainment and Random House LLC Partner for New Novels</a><br /><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ADbDN5MsUV4" target="_blank">YouTube - Blizzard Entertainment Partners with Random House!<br /></a><a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/game/lore/" target="_blank">Battle.net - StarCraft II - The StarCraft Universe</a></p></div>]]></description>
            <author>lordofascension@gmail.com (LordofAscension)</author>
            <category>Featured</category>
            <category>Blizzard</category>
            <category>News</category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 03:39:44 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>BlizzCon 2015 In-Game Goodies Round-Up</title>
            <link>http://sclegacy.com/index.php/news/9-events/1390-blizzcon-2015-in-game-goodies-round-up</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sclegacy.com/index.php/news/9-events/1390-blizzcon-2015-in-game-goodies-round-up</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<div class="feed-description"><center><a href="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/blizzcon15/virtual-in-game/2015virtualgoodiesbanner.jpg"><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/blizzcon15/virtual-in-game/2015virtualgoodiesbanner-small.png" width="600" height="213" style="vertical-align: middle;" /></a></center>
<p> </p>
<p>Today, <strong>Blizzard</strong> released details of each of the in-game goodies included with the purchase of either a physical or <a href="https://us.battle.net/shop/en/product/blizzcon-virtual-ticket" target="_blank">virtual</a> BlizzCon 2015 ticket. Similar to prior years, the items will unlock shortly after BlizzCon begins and players will receive at least one in-game reward for each of Blizzard's current flagship games. BlizzCon 2015 will take place in Anaheim, California November 6-7, 2015. While tickets to attend the two-day convention have been sold out for some time, the virtual ticket is available for $39.99.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>World of Warcraft - Murkadin Pet</strong></span></p>
<p> </p>
<center><a href="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/blizzcon15/virtual-in-game/2015-wow-murkidan-pet.jpg"><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/blizzcon15/virtual-in-game/2015-wow-murkidan-pet-small.png" width="380" height="238" /></a></center>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>After consuming the shin bone of Gul'dan, this fiesty demon hunter was caged for 10,000 years by his brother Murkfurion. Now he’s ready to unleash his finfernal rage in pet battles across Azeroth!</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Heroes of the Storm - Nexus Battle Bea</strong><strong>st</strong><strong> Mount</strong></span></p>
<p> </p>
<center><a href="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/blizzcon15/virtual-in-game/2015-hots-nexus-battle-beast-mount.jpg"><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/blizzcon15/virtual-in-game/2015-hots-nexus-battle-beast-mount-small.png" width="380" height="238" /></a></center>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>Teams will tremble and Cores will crumble when you storm into combat astride the mighty Nexus Battle Beast!</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<p> <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Hearthstone - Blizzard 2015 Card Back</strong></span><strong> </strong></p>
<p> </p>
<center><a href="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/blizzcon15/virtual-in-game/2015-hearthstone-blizzard-2015-card-back.jpg"><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/blizzcon15/virtual-in-game/2015-hearthstone-blizzard-2015-card-back-small.png" width="380" height="238" /></a></center>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>Hearthstone on phones, Tavern Brawls, Blackrock Mountain, The Grand Tournament, and more—a very cool year, indeed.</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>StarCraft II - Portraits</strong></span></p>
<p> </p>
<center><a href="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/blizzcon15/virtual-in-game/2015-sc2-portraits.jpg"><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/blizzcon15/virtual-in-game/2015-sc2-portraits-small.png" width="380" height="238" /></a></center>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>Show off your status as a galactic BlizzConquerer with a pair of Legacy of the Void–themed portraits invoking the mysteries of the Xel’Naga and the power of the Spear of Adun.</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<p> <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Diablo III - BlizzCon Pennant, Pet, and Portrait</strong></span><strong><br /></strong></p>
<p> </p>
<center><a href="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/blizzcon15/virtual-in-game/2015-d3-blizzcon-misc.jpg"><img src="http://sclegacy.com/images/uploaded/blizzcon15/virtual-in-game/2015-d3-blizzcon-misc-small.png" width="380" height="238" /></a></center>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>A trio of treasures awaits! Fly the colors of the BlizzCon crusade with an all-new pennant, and <em>mrglgllglgll</em> the demonic hordes with your Murkgoblin pet and portrait.*</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<p>The <em>StarCraft</em> rewards are a little underwhelming. Something BlizzCon themed would have been preferable. For example, a special BlizzCon inspired unit skin, ala the 2014 &amp; 2015 BlizzCon <em>Heroes of the Storm </em>mounts<em>,</em> or a unique Allied Commander mission, would have been exceptional. We will just have to console ourselves with all of the new campaign, features, UI, modes, units, and skins coming with <em>Legacy of the Void</em><em>'s  </em>imminent release.</p>
<p><strong>Sources:</strong><br /><a href="http://us.battle.net/blizzcon/en/blog/19888091/blizzcon-2015-in-game-goodies-round-up-9-21-2015" target="_blank">Battle.net - BlizzCon 2015 In-Game Goodies Round-Up</a><br /><a href="https://us.battle.net/shop/en/product/blizzcon-virtual-ticket" target="_blank">Battle.net - BlizzCon 2015 Virtual Ticket</a><br /><a href="http://us.battle.net/blizzcon/en/" target="_blank">BlizzCon.com</a></p>
<p> </p></div>]]></description>
            <author>lordofascension@gmail.com (LordofAscension)</author>
            <category>Featured</category>
            <category>Events</category>
            <category>News</category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 17:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
