<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>Counter-Strike: GO | theScore</title>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10377</guid>
            <title>ESL Pro League Hot Match of Week 6: Brazilian Dynasties</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10377</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 18:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/8516/w1080xh810_hot-match.jpg?ts=1458163005">
                <media:credit>theScore esports</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>The Americas region has always been a volatile region in CS:GO, with a handful of teams scrambling to be the top of the region. Cloud9, Counter Logic Gaming and Team Liquid are the teams that first pop into mind for domestic fans, but in 2016, the true kings of the region are the Brazilians.</p><p>The SK Gaming roster's rise started as far back as mid-2015 when they were <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/3240" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/3240">acquired by Luminosity Gaming</a> and it's been a upward trajectory for the team since then. And after their back-to-back Major championship, at MLG Major Championship: Columbus and later at ESL One Cologne 2016, Gabriel "<strong>FalleN</strong>" Toledo and co. have planted a flag deep in the Americas region and the CS:GO world. However a new, yet familiar, challenger is on the rise, "the other Brazilians," Immortals.</p><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/10491/cropped_27700341962_85f99229e2_k.jpg?ts=1466455356"><figcaption>Immortals' older lineup, with Gustavo "SHOOWTiME" Gonçalves, after winning DreamHack Summer 2016</figcaption></figure><p>The Immortals squad were on the fringes of the Americas scene for much of 2015 when they were part of Brazil-based team Games Academy, but after they were <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/5945" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/5945">acquired by Tempo Storm</a> on Feb. 10, 2016 they gained opportunities to prove themselves in bigger tournaments. The team showed flashes of brilliance by winning CEVO Season 9 and finishing in second place at DreamHack Austin, but they dropped the ball during more crucial points in their career, such as when they failed to qualify for the MLG Major.</p><p>After they were <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/8142" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/8142">acquired by Immortals</a> on June 1, the team once again failed to qualify for a Major at ESL One Cologne 2016, but after the <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9280" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9280">acquisition of SK's former coach</a> Wilton "<strong>zews</strong>" Prado, the team have been cutting a swath through the Americas region. Immortals won the Northern Arena Toronto LAN by defeating Cloud9 2-1 in the Grand Finals and qualified for ELEAGUE Season 2 by defeating Team SoloMid 2-0.</p><p>IMT have seen a steady rise, but of what they&#39;ve learned about CS was taken from the SK squad, given the close relationship the teams shared. When the IMT squad was part of Games Academy SK&#39;s AWper, Gabriel &quot;<strong>FalleN</strong>&quot; Toledo, was the CEO. They&#39;re as close as two competing teams could be.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Twins are crying. This is CS passion. This is y we play this. This is one of the best day in my life <a href="https://t.co/oGCtLFCX4J">pic.twitter.com/oGCtLFCX4J</a></p>— Gabriel FalleN T. (@FalleNCS) <a href="https://twitter.com/FalleNCS/status/705462743944585216">March 3, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>And the teams are brought ever closer now that zews is IMT&#39;s in-game leader, though it&#39;s been <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9280" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9280">nearly two months</a> since that transaction. IMT have stabilized with their new lineup, but SK have run into some speed bumps in the season.</p><p>Fernando &quot;<strong>fer</strong>&quot; Alvarenga was <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9512" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9512">sidelined by an ear surgery</a> for much of August and early September and the team used former IMT player Gustavo &quot;<strong>SHOOWTiME</strong>&quot; Gon&ccedil;alves as their stand in. On Sept. 1, during SK&#39;s ESL Pro League match against Renegades, the team was served a 16-12 loss on Nuke, which was followed by another devastating loss, 16-0 on Dust 2.</p><p>It was a loss not taken lightly by coldzera, who made some regrettable comments on Twitter and <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GlobalOffensive/comments/50m7dk/did_coldzera_delete_his_twitter/d75b54c">subsequently deleted his Twitter account</a>. Though that situation has largely blown over and coldzera has <a href="https://twitter.com/coldzera/status/776936109792112640">reactivated his Twitter </a>&mdash; fer also <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/10326" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10326">returned to the roster</a> on Sept. 10 &mdash; the team is still not at 100 percent in many ways.</p><p>SK were eliminated from the iBUYPOWER Fall Invitational after losing a 1-2 to OpTic Gaming. OpTic faced IMT in the finals, but were bested 2-1 by the Brazilian's.</p><p>Given the recent happenings, IMT are primed to pull off an "upset" against SK in ESL Pro League.</p><h2><strong>Player matchups</strong></h2><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/10731/cropped_20160705_Helena-Kristiansson_ESLOneCNG_0710.jpg?ts=1467843821"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><figure class="article-segment--table"><div class="table-responsive"><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>SK</th>
<th>Rating</th>
<th>+/-</th>
<th>Rating</th>
<th>IMT</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>coldzera</td>
<td>1.33</td>
<td>0.12</td>
<td>1.21</td>
<td>hen1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>FalleN</td>
<td>1.09</td>
<td>-0.08</td>
<td>1.17</td>
<td>boltz</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>fer</td>
<td>1.08</td>
<td>-0.07</td>
<td>1.15</td>
<td>lucas1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>fnx</td>
<td>1.06</td>
<td>-0.07</td>
<td>1.13</td>
<td>felps</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>TACO</td>
<td>1.03</td>
<td>0.07</td>
<td>0.96</td>
<td>zews</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Team Average</td>
<td>1.12</td>
<td>0.00</td>
<td>1.12</td>
<td>Team Average</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table></div></figure><p><em>Average player ratings taken from HLTV.org on Sept. 19, filtered by &quot;Past 3 months&quot;</em></p><p>coldzera isn't just the highest rated player in this matchup but he's the highest rated player in the world right now and this holds true when you filter by all his games in 2016 as well. This is a daunting thing to consider when you're a team facing off against SK, but the team averages tell a different story as both IMT and SK share the same 1.12 team rating.</p><p>The most immediate difference between the teams is their setup. IMT's setup is much more rigid with hen1 as the primary AWPer and rarely make use of double AWP setups as their secondary AWPer felps is much more comfortable on a rifle. Conversely, SK have a bit more versatility with their double AWP setup from FalleN and coldzera, one of the strongest AWP duos in the world. coldzera sometimes even acts as the primary AWPer depending on the rounds, a rare situation for most riflers/secondary AWPers.</p><p>The most immediate difference between the teams is the capabilities of their AWPers. coldzera has equal capabilities as a rifler and an AWPer, and even acts as the primary AWPer on certain rounds, which is an extremely rare situation for most riflers. However, SK's primary AWPer FalleN is more than capable as a rifler. Conversely, hen1's rifling pales in comparison to his AWPing and the opposite is true for felps, IMT's secondary AWPer.</p><p>This versatility gives more wiggle room to SK in the case of picks. If FalleN gets picked, cold can pick up the AWP and the team's pick potential remains the same, meanwhile if hen1 is picked off, the rest of the team is almost better off sticking to their rifles. SK have also pulled out some double AWP setups on their T-side, something IMT almost never do.</p><h2><strong>Map matchups</strong></h2><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12085/cropped_Csgo-de-cbble.jpg?ts=1474055593"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><figure class="article-segment--table"><div class="table-responsive"><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>SK (W/L - W%)</th>
<th>Map</th>
<th>IMT (W/L - W%)</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>N/A</td>
<td>Cache</td>
<td>9/4 - 69.2%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4/2 - 66.7%</td>
<td>Dust 2</td>
<td>1/1 - 50%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5/1 - 83.3%</td>
<td>Mirage</td>
<td>9/2 - 81.8%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2/1 - 66.7%</td>
<td>Nuke</td>
<td>0/1 - 0%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>6/0 - 100%</td>
<td>Train</td>
<td>12/2 - 85.7%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>6/3 - 66.7%</td>
<td>Cobble</td>
<td>13/2 - 86.7%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5/2 - 71.4%</td>
<td>Overpass</td>
<td>10/2 - 83.3%</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table></div></figure><p><em>Stats aggregated from HLTV.org on Sept. 19, filtered by &quot;Past 3 months&quot;</em></p><p>The only time these two teams faced off in 2016 was during the DreamHack Austin Grand Finals on May 8, which was a clean 2-0 win for the SK squad, taking Mirage 16-9 and Cobble 16-9. And even though the matchup took place five months ago, the teams show a preference towards those maps even now.</p><p>Given map draft trends we likely won't see Cache, Nuke or Dust 2 played. And given SK's recent loss to OpTic on Overpass, they may look to put that map back on the drawing board. This leaves Train, and incredibly strong map for both teams, as well as the two maps from their previous matchup, Cobble and Mirage.</p><p>All things considered, IMT and SK are so evenly matched on so many metrics. All logic points to SK taking the series cleanly, but their online performances lately have left a lot to be desired, while IMT are play at their peak.</p><p>IMT have established a foothold on the Americas region and only continue to imrpove, but their climb to the top is made decidedly tougher with their Brazilian cousins in SK standing in their way.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><iframe src="https://renderer.qmerce.com/interaction/57dec5874089281870094e32" width="100%" height="404" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></figure><p><em>Dennis "<strong>Tarmanydyn</strong>" Gonzales is a news editor for theScore esports who enjoys whiskey, D&amp;D and first-picking <s>Abaddon</s> <s>Slardar</s> <s>Clinkz</s> <s>Medusa</s> <s>Oracle</s> <s>a</s> <s>P90</s> my Souvenir Negev. <a href="http://twitter.com/Tarmanydyn">You can follow him on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10467</guid>
            <title>Immortals win iBUYPOWER Fall Invitational</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10467</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 14:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/10483/w1080xh810_27183439633_ae30b76628_k.jpg?ts=1466447360">
                <media:credit>Adela Sznajder / DreamHack</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Immortals have won the iBUYPOWER Fall Invitational after they defeated OpTic Gaming 3-1 in the finals on Sunday.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">GG CARALHOOOOOO! And we win <a href="https://twitter.com/iBUYPOWER">@iBUYPOWER</a> cup!!!! :D:D we take <a href="https://twitter.com/OpTicGaming">@OpTicGaming</a> 2x1!!!!!!!!!!!!! &lt;3 <a href="https://twitter.com/Immortals">@Immortals</a> my team</p>— Wilton Prado 'zews' (@wiltonzews) <a href="https://twitter.com/wiltonzews/status/777725373748436992">September 19, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>IMT&#39;s road to the finals was a fairly easy one as they pushed past compLexity Gaming 2-0 in the quarterfinals and defeated NRG eSports 2-1 in the semis to progress to the finals.</p><p>On the other side of the bracket OpTic had ostensibly tougher opponents, even still they defeated Team SoloMid 2-1 in the quarterfinals and pulled off a 2-1 upset over SK Gaming to meet IMT in the finals.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">GG <a href="https://twitter.com/OpTicGaming">@OpTicGaming</a> very well played and we lost 1-2 ! GL in the finals. We have work to do against this gamestyle on overpass. Thanks 4 cheerin</p>— Gabriel FalleN T. (@FalleNCS) <a href="https://twitter.com/FalleNCS/status/777657144967503872">September 18, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>The first map of the Grand Finals was on Train and OpTic made the series competitive with a 7-8 half, but IMT showed that it was one of their strong maps on the CT-side and closed out 16-13. Next up was OpTic&#39;s pick on Cache, which went to overtime, but OpTic tied the series after taking the map 19-16.</p><p>The deciding map was on Dust 2, which was not a particularly strong map for either team and they traded rounds in the first half to go to a 8-7 scoreline in slight favor of OpTic. However, IMT got a ton of momentum after winning the second pistol round and ended the map with a 16-12 to win the map and the tournament.</p><p>felps stepped up for IMT during the event as he was the single-highest rated player in the tournament with an HLTV player rating of 1.42, dwarfing the next highest players, coldzera, who had a 1.28 rating and hen1, who had a 1.26 rating.</p><p><em>Dennis "<strong>Tarmanydyn</strong>" Gonzales is a news editor for theScore esports who enjoys whiskey, D&amp;D and first-picking <s>Abaddon</s> <s>Slardar</s> <s>Clinkz</s> <s>Medusa</s> <s>Oracle</s> <s>a</s> <s>P90</s> my Souvenir Negev. <a href="http://twitter.com/Tarmanydyn">You can follow him on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10457</guid>
            <title>Renegades' manager on Map 1 def loss in ECS dev. league: 'It's my ****up'</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10457</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 20:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11965/w1080xh810_kwWm2PXL_waifu2x_art_noise1_scale_tta_1.jpg?ts=1473607557">
                <media:credit>Logos / Renegades</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Following the Detroit Renegades' forfeit of Map 1 against SK Gaming in the ECS Season 2 Development League, the team's manager Chris "<strong>GoMeZ</strong>" Orfanellis released a statement on Sunday.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Our match vs SK in ECS Dev League<br><br>Read: <a href="https://t.co/wUY4GS9w6L">https://t.co/wUY4GS9w6L</a></p>— Chris Orfanellis (@GoMeZCSGO) <a href="https://twitter.com/GoMeZCSGO/status/777592233805635584">September 18, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>According to GoMeZ's statement, the forfeited map was due to a scheduling error. The team incorrectly entered a 6 p.m. start time for their game, but the game started at 2 p.m.</p><p>"Whenever we put things in the calendars we double check them and basically re-read and confirm them all to make sure mistakes like this don't happen," GoMeZ said in his TwitLonger. "I don't do it alone and get additional eyes to check it but ultimately it's my fuckup, so i'm lost for words how this did happen."</p><p>"As a result of my mistake, we are going into this match rushed and barely awake and 0-1 down in the series," he said.</p><p>GoMeZ stressed that in the three years he's been managing the team that this is the first time a mistake like this has occurred and former Renegades player Chad "<strong>SPUNJ</strong>" Burchill attested.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/GoMeZCSGO">@GoMeZCSGO</a> one mistake in 3 years mog, don't stress. You are a gun at what you do mate. Miss you guys.</p>— Chad Burchill (@SPUNJ) <a href="https://twitter.com/SPUNJ/status/777594166998077442">September 18, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>SK went on to win the first map in the series to be played, taking the win 2-0.</p><p><em>Dennis "<strong>Tarmanydyn</strong>" Gonzales is a news editor for theScore esports who enjoys whiskey, D&amp;D and first-picking <s>Abaddon</s> <s>Slardar</s> <s>Clinkz</s> <s>Medusa</s> <s>Oracle</s> <s>a</s> <s>P90</s> my Souvenir Negev. <a href="http://twitter.com/Tarmanydyn">You can follow him on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9817</guid>
            <title>Virtus.pro win DreamHack Bucharest</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9817</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 16:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12099/w1080xh810_29139187403_e8de41a4aa_k.jpg?ts=1474213208">
                <media:credit>Adela Sznajder / DreamHack</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Virtus.pro have defeated Cloud9 2-0 to win DreamHack Bucharest 2016 and the tournament's $50,000 prize.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-partner="tweetdeck"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">GG! <a href="https://twitter.com/TeamVirtuspro">@TeamVirtuspro</a> are your champions here at Bucharest! Well won! <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DHOpen?src=hash">#DHOpen</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DHB16?src=hash">#DHB16</a> <a href="https://t.co/aLJloPd6Mh">pic.twitter.com/aLJloPd6Mh</a></p>&mdash; DreamHack Open (@DreamHackOpen) <a href="https://twitter.com/DreamHackOpen/status/777548503006515201">September 18, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>The Grand Finals against C9 opened on Train, a map that the Americans have been playing on and winning quite a bit recently, but it was a signature pick for VP. The Poles went up 12-3 in the first half and pushed past C9 with a 16-9 scoreline despite losing both pistol rounds.</p><p>Next up was C9's pick, Cobble. The North American squad got off to a hot start with a 9-6 half, but VP mounted a come back on the T-side half and went on a devastating 10-round streak to close the map 16-9 to take the series.</p><p>Earlier in the tournament, Virtus.pro topped their group by defeating both Gambit eSports and Heroic in best-of-one matches. They faced Team Dignitas in the semifinals with both teams taking a map off each other, but NEO closed the series by pulling off a miraculous 1v5 clutch.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/183192242" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure><p>byali was the star player for VP in DreamHack Bucharest as he had an <a href="http://www.hltv.org/?pageid=183&amp;statsfilter=0&amp;eventid=2112">HLTV rating</a> of 1.26, the highest rated player of the tournament, but NEO and TaZ weren&rsquo;t far behind with 1.22 and 1.17 player ratings respectively.</p><p><em>Dennis "<strong>Tarmanydyn</strong>" Gonzales is a news editor for theScore esports who enjoys whiskey, D&amp;D and first-picking <s>Abaddon</s> <s>Slardar</s> <s>Clinkz</s> <s>Medusa</s> <s>Oracle</s> <s>a</s> <s>P90</s> my Souvenir Negev. <a href="http://twitter.com/Tarmanydyn">You can follow him on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10453</guid>
            <title>Watch: pasha's Pro-90 3K on C9</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10453</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 16:13:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12101/w1080xh810_psha.jpg?ts=1474214735">
                <media:credit>DreamHack Twitch</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>pasha sat in a smoke by the terrace on Cobble and patiently waited for Cloud9 to push. When the push came, C9 had no idea what was going on and pasha sprayed three of them down to put C9 on their back foot during the DreamHack Bucharest Grand Finals.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/183201266" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure><p><em>Dennis "<strong>Tarmanydyn</strong>" Gonzales is a news editor for theScore esports who enjoys whiskey, D&amp;D and first-picking <s>Abaddon</s> <s>Slardar</s> <s>Clinkz</s> <s>Medusa</s> <s>Oracle</s> <s>a</s> <s>P90</s> my Souvenir Negev. <a href="http://twitter.com/Tarmanydyn">You can follow him on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10454</guid>
            <title>Na`Vi names s1mple as second AWPer, seized as new IGL</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10454</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 17:53:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11963/w1080xh810_29443273331_ccb10ade66_k.jpg?ts=1473601733">
                <media:credit>SL i-League</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Natus Vincere <a href="https://t.co/Ci3pJ3mjnP">has officially made</a> Oleksandr &quot;<strong>s1mple</strong>&quot; Kostyliev their secondary AWPer after he took on the position during the team&#39;s ESL Pro League match against NiP on Sept. 15. Na`Vi&#39;s former second AWPer, Denis &ldquo;<strong>seized</strong>&rdquo; Kostin, has also been made the team&#39;s captain and in-game leader.</p><p>"Make no mistake, seized definitely did a great job, but changes had to be made, however, to continue to get stronger," the team said in a statement. "Just like seized, s1mple is a great AWP user and he proved that to everyone when he was playing under the Team Liquid banner."</p><p>s1mple has traditionally favored the AWP, he took on a flex role with Liquid, but while he still <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0k6tNe5mWD8&amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;t=1m1s">prefers the sniper rifle</a>, he's <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/8951" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/8951">no slouch with an AK either</a>.</p><p><strong>RELATED: <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9549" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9549">s1mple joins Na`Vi</a></strong></p><p>Na`Vi have not had a dedicated captain since Danylo &quot;<strong>Zeus</strong>&quot; Teslenko left the starting roster to make room for the team&#39;s acquisition of s1mple in August. Zeus was a long-time member of Na`Vi, playing on both their CS:GO and CS 1.6 squads. The team&#39;s coach, Sergey &quot;<strong>starix</strong>&quot; Ischuk, had fulfilled IGL duties until <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9859" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9859">Valve decided to ban in-game coaching</a> at their Majors events.</p><p>"Now we are planning on making Alexander the second sniper, we think this will be easier for both Denis and Alexander," starix said in a statement. "We'll switch positions on a couple of maps, still have some work to do."</p><p>Na`Vi&#39;s next Pro League match is against mousesports on Sept. 20, followed by PENTA Sports on Sept. 21 and <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9817" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9817">DreamHack Bucharest champs</a> Virtus.pro on Sept. 22.</p><p>However, the true test of the players' new roles will be <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/9678" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/9678">at ESL One New York 2016</a> on Oct. 1-2.</p><p><em>Sasha Erfanian is a news editor for theScore esports. <a href="https://twitter.com/SashaErfanian">Follow him on Twitter</a>, it'll be great for his self-esteem.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10449</guid>
            <title>Watch: NEO's godlike 1v5 clutch secures series against Dignitas</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10449</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 13:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12097/w1080xh810_NEO.jpg?ts=1474206796">
                <media:credit>DreamHack Twitch</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>&quot;NEO are you kidding me!?&quot; was the call from Anders Blume after NEO pulled off an impossible 1v5 clutch over Team Dignitas to secure Virtus.pro a slot in the DreamHack Bucharest Grand Final.</p><p>NEO had 4HP remaining after the play that you have to see to believe.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/183192242" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-partner="tweetdeck"><p lang="und" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/6zE9LRbcAo">pic.twitter.com/6zE9LRbcAo</a></p>— Janko Paunovic (@OnFireYNk) <a href="https://twitter.com/OnFireYNk/status/777504003206811648">September 18, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-partner="tweetdeck"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">NEO with another historic 1v5 omfg</p>— Mitch (@SelflessMitch) <a href="https://twitter.com/SelflessMitch/status/777504082458243073">September 18, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-partner="tweetdeck"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">How do you finish a match ? Call neo, 1v5 eZ</p>— Richard Papillon (@G2shox) <a href="https://twitter.com/G2shox/status/777504273164828673">September 18, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p><em>Dennis "<strong>Tarmanydyn</strong>" Gonzales is a news editor for theScore esports who enjoys whiskey, D&amp;D and first-picking <s>Abaddon</s> <s>Slardar</s> <s>Clinkz</s> <s>Medusa</s> <s>Oracle</s> <s>a</s> <s>P90</s> my Souvenir Negev. <a href="http://twitter.com/Tarmanydyn">You can follow him on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10441</guid>
            <title>Watch: FaZe don't check corner, Magiskb0Y picks up easy 3K</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10441</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 19:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12095/w1080xh810_Magiskb0y.jpg?ts=1474138773">
                <media:credit>DreamHack Twitch</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Team Dignitas&#39; Magiskb0Y patiently waited on top of the boost boxes of the A-site when FaZe Clan went aggressive on the site with a hail of molotovs, flashes and smokes. FaZe failed to check their angles on their push, gave Magiskb0Y an easy triple and gave up a round in the DreamHack Bucharest deciding match.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/183134589" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></figure><p><em>Dennis &quot;<strong>Tarmanydyn</strong>&quot; Gonzales is a news editor for theScore esports who enjoys whiskey, D&amp;D and first-picking <s>Abaddon</s> <s>Slardar</s> <s>Clinkz</s> <s>Medusa</s> <s>Oracle</s> <s>a</s> <s>P90</s> my Souvenir Negev. <a href="http://twitter.com/Tarmanydyn">You can follow him on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10435</guid>
            <title>Dignitas, nV advance to DreamHack Bucharest playoffs; FaZe, Heroic, Gambit, F3 eliminated</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10435</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 19:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12094/w1080xh810_29743109305_8bad34c339_k.jpg?ts=1474134126">
                <media:credit>Adela Sznajder / DreamHack</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>The group stage for DreamHack Bucharest has concluded with Team Dignitas and Team EnVyUs moving on to the playoffs where they will face Virtus.pro and Cloud9 respectively. Faze Clan, Heroic and Gambit eSports have been eliminated from the event.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">We have our final 4! <a href="https://twitter.com/TeamDignitas">@TeamDignitas</a> advance! They face <a href="https://twitter.com/TeamVirtuspro">@TeamVirtuspro</a> tomorrow while <a href="https://twitter.com/TeamEnVyUs">@TeamEnVyUs</a> will face <a href="https://twitter.com/Cloud9">@Cloud9</a> ! <a href="https://t.co/0SKEpx7MV3">pic.twitter.com/0SKEpx7MV3</a></p>— DreamHack Open (@DreamHackOpen) <a href="https://twitter.com/DreamHackOpen/status/777217676041195520">September 17, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>The first match of the day was Group A's elimination match between nV and Gambit on Cobble. nV took a massive 13-2 half on their CT-site, but Gambit fired back when the sides switched over. nV took two rounds to go up to match point, but Gambit took 12 rounds over the course of the half and nearly forced an overtime before nV were able to close the map 16-14. The second map, Cache, was more straight-forward for the French team as they pushed over Gambit with a 16-7 scoreline to take the map and the series.</p><p>nV moved on to the deciding match against Heroic, a rematch of Day 1's insane sextuple overtime that nV lost 34-31. The series opened on Dust 2 and nV took a 10-5 half en route to a 16-8 win, but Heroic fired back on Nuke with a 16-13 scoreline. The final map came down to Cobble, but it was a simple finish for nV as they took a 13-2 half and finished with a 16-9 scoreline to move on to the semifinals.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">We're on to the Semifinals at <a href="https://twitter.com/DreamHackOpen">@DreamHackOpen</a> in Bucharest, Romania after a 2-1 win vs <a href="https://twitter.com/heroicgg">@heroicgg</a>! The winning moment: <a href="https://t.co/wTO7XUWMhh">pic.twitter.com/wTO7XUWMhh</a></p>— Team EnVyUs (@TeamEnVyUs) <a href="https://twitter.com/TeamEnVyUs/status/777184405244645376">September 17, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>Over to Group B, the elimination match was between Dignitas and F3 was a back-and-forth affair. They traded one-sided maps as Dignitas took Train 16-7, while F3 took Cobble 16-9. The final map was on Mirage and it was another one-sided map, which was taken by Dignitas 16-6 to win the series.</p><p>With the win, Dignitas earned a rematch against FaZe, who defeated them 16-11 in the opening best-of-one match during the group stage, but the deciding match was a one-sided affair for the Danes. Dignitas won 16-7 on Nuke and won 16-6 on Cache and took a surprisingly swift series to move on to the semifinals.</p><p>With the final four teams decided, the semifinal matchups look as follows:</p><ul><li>Virtus.pro vs. Team Dignitas</li><li>Cloud9 vs. Team EnVyUs</li></ul><p>DreamHack Bucharest 2016 concludes on Sept. 18 where one team will take home the $50,000 first prize.</p><p><em>Dennis "<strong>Tarmanydyn</strong>" Gonzales is a news editor for theScore esports who enjoys whiskey, D&amp;D and first-picking <s>Abaddon</s> <s>Slardar</s> <s>Clinkz</s> <s>Medusa</s> <s>Oracle</s> <s>a</s> <s>P90</s> my Souvenir Negev. <a href="http://twitter.com/Tarmanydyn">You can follow him on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10426</guid>
            <title>ESL changes prize pool distribution for Pro League Season 4</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10426</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/8481/w1080xh810_lL94FKlvuilA.878x0.Z-Z96KYq123.jpg?ts=1457972575">
                <media:credit>Valve, ESL</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>The prize pool distribution for ESL One Pro League Season 4 has been changed due to the expansion of teams in both the regular season and LAN finals, <a href="http://en.pro.eslgaming.com/csgo/proleague/news/introducing-the-updated-prize-money-distribution-for-esl-pro-league/">ESL announced</a> Friday.</p><p>"With this season's changes including the expanded divisions (from 12 teams to 14), as well as finals (from 8 teams to 12), adjustments to the prize money distribution were in order," ESL said in a statement.</p><p>While the total prize pool remains unchanged at $750,000, the changes mean that some teams who fail to qualify for the LAN Finals will receive less money than they did for Season 3. For example, a team that finished in seventh place during the online season will now receive $18,000 as opposed to the $20,000 they would have won in Season 3. This is to compensate for the fact that there are 14 teams competing in the regular season as opposed to 12.</p><p>For teams competing in the LAN Finals, third and fourth place teams will now receive $1,000 more, while teams placing between fifth and eighth will receive $1,000 less.</p><p>The prize distribution for both the online season and LAN Finals will now be as follows:</p><p><strong>LAN Finals</strong></p><ul><li>1st: $200,000 (unchanged)</li><li>2nd: $90,000 (unchanged)</li><li>3rd-4th: $45,000 (formerly $44,000)</li><li>5th-6th: $35,000 (formerly $36,000)</li><li>7th-8th: $30,000 (formerly $31,000)</li><li>9th-10th: $25,000 (new)</li><li>11th-12th: $20,000 (new)</li></ul><p><strong>Online Season Play (North America and Europe)</strong></p><ul><li>1st-6th: Qualify for LAN Finals</li><li>7th: $18,000 (formerly $20,000)</li><li>8th: $15,500 (formerly $16,500)</li><li>9th: $13,000 (unchanged)</li><li>10th: $10,500 (formerly $9,500)</li><li>11th: $8,000 (formerly $6,000)</li><li>12th: $5,500 (formerly $3,500)</li><li>13th: $3,000 (new)</li><li>14th: $1,500 (new)</li></ul><p>The ESL Pro League Season 4 Finals will be held from Oct. 26-30, in São Paulo, Brazil.</p><p><em>Preston Dozsa is a news editor for theScore esports. <a href="https://twitter.com/prestondozsa">You can follow him on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10424</guid>
            <title>Immortals, Splyce, TSM among iBUYPOWER Fall Invitational attendees</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10424</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 23:22:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/6346/w1080xh810_IBP.jpg?ts=1447434713">
                <media:credit>iBUYPOWER</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Eight North American teams, including Immortals, Splyce, compLexity Gaming, Team SoloMid and OpTic Gaming, will be <a href="http://www.ibuypower.com/Site/Event/IBP-Fall-Invite-2016">attending the iBUYPOWER Fall Invitational</a> this weekend.</p><p>The tournament runs from Sept. 17-18 and features a single elimination, best-of-three bracket format along with a $16,000 prize pool. The teams attending attending the event are: Immortals, compLexity Gaming, OpTic Gaming, Team SoloMid, SK Gaming, Splyce, Echo Fox and NRG eSports.</p><p>TSM, coL and Echo Fox were also at the iBUYPOWER Summer Invitational in July, where coL were eliminated by Selfless Gaming in the quarterfinals. TSM and Echo Fox went head to head in the semifinals, where TSM eliminated Echo Fox 2-0 to advance to the finals.</p><p>Cloud9 beat TSM 2-0 in the finals to win the Summer Invitational. C9 are not attending the Fall Invitational as they are currently at DreamHack Bucharest.</p><p><em>Olivia Da Silva is a news editor at theScore esports. She likes piña coladas, getting caught in the rain and dank no-scopes. You're eligible for free high fives if you <a href="https://twitter.com/TheDaSilvaDaily">follow her on Twitter.</a></em></p><p> </p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10422</guid>
            <title>BPro Gaming sign spyleadeR</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10422</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 21:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/8951/w1080xh810_20160303_Patrick_Strack_Katwoice16_CSGO_070A1028.jpg?ts=1460306986">
                <media:credit>Patrick Strack / ESL</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Emiliyan "<strong>spyleadeR</strong>" Dimitrov has been signed by BPro Gaming.</p><p>BPro Gaming <a href="http://bprogaming.com/enter-the-spyleader/">released a statement</a> on spyleadeR's acquisition which said that he'll be replacing Anton ‘<strong>Affichko</strong>’ Kolev as the team captain, though Affichko will be staying on the active roster.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">i will fly to Kiev for <a href="https://twitter.com/WESGcom">@WESGcom</a> Regional finals with <a href="https://twitter.com/Bpro_gaming">@Bpro_gaming</a> wish me luck guys 👍👍👍</p>— Emiliyan Dimitrov (@spyleaderCS) <a href="https://twitter.com/spyleaderCS/status/776691842293329920">September 16, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>spyleadeR previously played for Mortal Kombat before <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/10315" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10315">announcing his departure</a> from the team last week. MK recently won the Global Grand Masters and the ESEA Season 22: Global Premier Challenge. However, spyleadeR attributed his departure from MK to a recent loss at a local event.</p><p>The team's first event with spyleadeR will be the WESG Regional Finals, which run from Oct. 6-9 in Kiev, Ukraine.</p><p><em>Olivia Da Silva is a news editor at theScore esports. She likes piña coladas, getting caught in the rain and dank no-scopes. You're eligible for free high fives if you <a href="https://twitter.com/TheDaSilvaDaily">follow her on Twitter.</a></em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10419</guid>
            <title>Peacemaker addresses Team Liquid's loss in ELEAGUE preliminaries</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10419</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 21:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/5551/w1080xh810_TeamLiquid.jpg?ts=1442372289">
                <media:credit>Team Liquid</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Following Team Liquid&#39;s loss to Echo Fox and subsequent elimination from the ELEAGUE preliminary, coach Luis &quot;Peacemaker&quot; Tadeu <a href="http://www.twitlonger.com/show/n_1sp42si">took to TwitLonger </a>to address fan concerns about the team&#39;s new roster.</p><p>"Since our recent roster changes has been made we are still figuring out the way we are playing, new roles, adapting to each other and to different situations on every map," Peacemaker said. "And also adapting to this new rule Valve brought up about the coaches.</p><p>"Unfortunately we didn't had a chance to compete that much as team yet or bootcamp, which makes our lives a bit harder. We had tough losses at the beginning and I believe that definitely made our lives a little bit harder to a point where we were kinda overthinking too much about the way we are working, and we are working hard on that part."</p><p>Over the past few months, Liquid signed Joshua "<strong>jdm64</strong>" Marzano and Jacob "<strong>Pimp</strong>" Winneche to replace Kenneth "<strong>koosta</strong>" Suen and Oleksandr "<strong>s1mple</strong>" Kostyliev, though the full lineup has seen rough results since s1mple's official departure. The team placed second at the CyberPowerPC Summer 2016 Pro Series, and lost their qualifying match in the ELEAGUE preliminary to Echo Fox 2-1.</p><p>"About the match and in my point of view, when you lose a match like that is always tougher because you have the feeling that you had a lot of chances to finish it off but unfortunately we never managed to do it," Peacemaker wrote. </p><p>"I am obviously not taking the credits out of Echo Fox and I think they have been improving a lot as a team lately, specially on Nuke they completely outplayed us in different ways, but I do believe we should have won on dust2 by far, but again, good reads from them and so many mistakes from us as a team definitely made their lives and the comeback very possible."</p><p>Prior to the switch, Liquid was considered to be one of the strongest teams in North America. The team achieved Legend status at the MLG Columbus Major with a 3rd-4th place finish after a 2-0 loss to Luminosity Gaming, and went on to place second at the ESL One Cologne Major, defeating Natus Vincere and Fnatic before being defeated 2-0 yet again by the ex-Luminosity roster, now with SK Gaming. </p><p>"This next week we will be bootcamping together before ESL NY and we will put a lot of hard work to be in shape as soon as possible," Peacemaker said. "First offline tournament are always tougher than the next ones when you have a new team but I am confident that we will be prepared enough for this first challenge."</p><p>Team Liquid was invited to ESL One New York, where they will play against Fnatic, G2 Esports, Na`Vi, Virtus.pro, SK Gaming, Astralis and one more team that has yet to be determined. ESL One New York runs from Oct. 1-2.</p><p><em>Daniel Rosen is a news editor for theScore esports. <a href="http://twitter.com/daniel_rosen">You can follow him on Twitter.</a></em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10412</guid>
            <title>Watch: DEVIL’s spray transfer into 3K forces OT against Heroic</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10412</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 16:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12081/w1080xh810_DEVIL.jpg?ts=1474042935">
                <media:credit>DreamHack Twitch</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Heroic were on match point and hit the A-site on Mirage from all sides, but Team EnVyUs&#39; DEVIL pulled off a massive spray transfer and picked off two coming from Connector. DEVIL later picked off a third and forced an overtime during the DreamHack Bucharest group stage.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/183021897" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-partner="tweetdeck"><p lang="ht" dir="ltr">g0dev1l</p>&mdash; NiKo (@mouzNiKo) <a href="https://twitter.com/mouzNiKo/status/776817177651515392">September 16, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p><em>Dennis &quot;<strong>Tarmanydyn</strong>&quot; Gonzales is a news editor for theScore esports who enjoys whiskey, D&amp;D and first-picking <s>Abaddon</s> <s>Slardar</s> <s>Clinkz</s> <s>Medusa</s> <s>Oracle</s> <s>a</s> <s>P90</s> my Souvenir Negev. <a href="http://twitter.com/Tarmanydyn">You can follow him on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10398</guid>
            <title>Immortals, SK, Echo Fox and OpTic qualify for ELEAGUE Season 2</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10398</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 13:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/6856/w1080xh810_ELEAGUE.jpg?ts=1449256255">
                <media:credit>ELEAGUE</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>The NA preliminaries for ELEAGUE Season 2 have ended, and Immortals, SK Gaming, Echo Fox and OpTic Gaming will be heading to the group stage in October.</p><p>The full team list for ELEAGUE Season 2 now looks as follows:</p><figure class="article-segment--table"><div class="table-responsive"><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Season 1 Top 8</th>
<th></th>
<th>EU Prelims</th>
<th>NA Prelims</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Astralis</td>
<td>Cloud9</td>
<td>ALTERNATE aTTaX</td>
<td>Echo Fox</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Team EnVyUs</td>
<td>Fnatic</td>
<td>Team Dignitas</td>
<td>Immortals</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>mousesports</td>
<td>Natus Vincere</td>
<td>FaZe Clan</td>
<td>OpTic Gaming</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Ninjas in Pyjamas</td>
<td>Virtus.pro</td>
<td>G2 Esports</td>
<td>SK Gaming</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table></div></figure><p>The prelims, which took place on Sept. 14, started with 16 teams hoping to snag one of four qualifier slots. That number was cut in half on Day 1, and the eight teams left standing &mdash; SK, NRG, Liquid, Echo Fox, OpTic Gaming, Renegades, Immortals, and TSM &mdash; faced off on Sept. 15.</p><p>First up was Immortals versus Team SoloMid, with Immortals sweeping TSM 2-0 with a narrow 16-14 victory on Mirage followed by 16-10 on Cobble. Immortals's Lucas "<strong>lucas1</strong>" Teles dominated the series with 52 kills to 34 deaths and 97.7 ADR.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">. <a href="https://twitter.com/TSMFNS">@TSMFNS</a> is gifted 3 kills from the "false prophet" of flashbangs <a href="https://t.co/bX5Dynjoyb">pic.twitter.com/bX5Dynjoyb</a></p>— ELEAGUE (@EL) <a href="https://twitter.com/EL/status/776474508420972544">September 15, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>NRG had the poor luck to go up against SK Gaming in their Day 2 match. With <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/10326" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10326">the return of Fernando &quot;<strong>fer</strong>&quot; Alvarenga</a> to active duty, the ESL One: Cologne 2016 champions were eager to stretch their legs. They won the match 2-0, taking Dust 2 at a handy 16-8, with both Marcelo &quot;<strong>coldzera</strong>&quot; David and fer boasting 101.2 ADR on the map. </p><p>Overpass went to SK at an even handier 16-7. On the second map, the Brazilians dominated on CT with 14 rounds to NRG&#39;s one. NRG held off defeat on the switch-over for several rounds, walking away in defeat but not in shame.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The 1v4 clutch from <a href="https://twitter.com/NRG_ptr">@NRG_ptr</a> <a href="https://t.co/XSH71WGg09">pic.twitter.com/XSH71WGg09</a></p>— ELEAGUE (@EL) <a href="https://twitter.com/EL/status/776490797206122496">September 15, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>SK&#39;s ESL One Cologne 2016 rivals, Team Liquid, went up against Echo Fox in the third match of the day. The first half of Mirage was pretty even at 8-7 in Liquid&#39;s favor, but the house Spencer &quot;<strong>Hiko</strong>&quot; Martin built pulled ahead after the half, winning Game 1 16-11. </p><p>However, it was Echo Fox that dominated Nuke, taking 11 rounds on T to Liquid&#39;s 4 and closing out the second half 16-9 on CT.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-partner="tweetdeck"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The man, the myth, the legend- <a href="https://twitter.com/Liquid_Hiko">@Liquid_Hiko</a> secures the 1v4 clutch on B-site <a href="https://t.co/2WVTpuKXBk">pic.twitter.com/2WVTpuKXBk</a></p>— ELEAGUE (@EL) <a href="https://twitter.com/EL/status/776514937493393408">September 15, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>The third game saw a wild comeback from Echo Fox. Liquid gained a massive 12-4 lead over Echo Fox, but Fox came back swinging, able to overtake Liquid with a 16-13 final score. Shahzeb &quot;<strong>ShahZaM</strong>&quot; Khan rocked a notable 1.93 KDR. With the Game 3 win, Fox took the match and advanced to ELEAGUE Season 2.</p><p>The final match of the day saw OpTic Gaming take an impressive 13-2 lead over Renegades in the first half of Cache. Renegades nearly came back in the second half, but OpTic managed to secure the three rounds needed to win the map 16-13.</p><p>Map 2 was Dust 2, with Renegades taking a strong 10-5 lead at the half, but things fell apart for the Australians on their CT-side. They could only muster three rounds, and OpTic pulled off the comeback to take the map 16-13 and qualify for ELEAGUE 2-0 over Renegades.</p><p>The groups for ELEAGUE Season 2 have yet to be announced, but the league will kick off on Oct. 21, and will end on Dec. 3.</p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10406</guid>
            <title>Epsilon eSports invited to Gfinity Invitational</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10406</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 12:19:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/8353/w1080xh810_epsilon.jpg?ts=1457302058">
                <media:credit>Epsilon eSports</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Epsilon eSports are the final invite to the Gfinity Invitational, the tournament organizers <a href="http://www.gfinity.net/news/details/epsilon-esports-team-profile-cs-go-invitational-egx-2016">announced Friday</a>.</p><p>The full team list for the event now looks as follows:</p><figure class="article-segment--table"><div class="table-responsive"><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Invited</th>
<th></th>
<th></th>
<th></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>GODSENT</td>
<td>Team EnVyUs</td>
<td>mousesports</td>
<td>Epsilon eSports</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table></div></figure><p>Epsilon are an up-and-coming Swedish team that have shown promise by qualifying for a number of notable tournaments such as DreamHack Tours and DreamHack Summer, but in both events they were eliminated in the group stage.</p><p>The team have run into a string of bad luck recently, having been eliminated from the ECS Season 2 Development League, the DreamHack Bucharest qualifier, the EPICENTER: Moscow open qualifier and the ELEAGUE Season 2 open qualifier.</p><p>This invite gives them a big shot in the arm, and a chance to prove themselves again on LAN against some big guns from the European region.</p><p>The team currently only has four players on its active roster, but according to Gfinity&#39;s announcement, the team will play with ex-Escape Gaming player Andr&eacute; &quot;<strong>BARBARR</strong>&quot; M&ouml;ller.</p><p>Epsilon eSports' roster at the Gfinity Invitational looks as follows:</p><ul><li>William "<strong>draken</strong>" Sundin</li><li>Fredrik "<strong>REZ</strong>" Sterner</li><li>Joakim "<strong>disco doplan</strong>" Gidetun</li><li>Fredrik "<strong>freddieb</strong>" Buö</li><li>André "<strong>BARBARR</strong>" Möller</li></ul><p>The Gfinity Invitational features a $100,000 prize pool and will take place on Sept. 22-25 at EGX 2016 in the National Exhibition Centre in Birmingham, England.</p><p><a href="http://www.gfinity.net/events/details/the-gfinity-cs-go-invitational-brought-to-you-by-omen-by-hp">Further details on the tournament</a>, such as the schedule and format, are expected in the future.</p><p><em>Dennis "<strong>Tarmanydyn</strong>" Gonzales is a news editor for theScore esports who enjoys whiskey, D&amp;D and first-picking <s>Abaddon</s> <s>Slardar</s> <s>Clinkz</s> <s>Medusa</s> <s>Oracle</s> <s>a</s> <s>P90</s> my Souvenir Negev. <a href="http://twitter.com/Tarmanydyn">You can follow him on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10389</guid>
            <title>DreamHack Bucharest 2016 Preview: Take Two</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10389</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 20:34:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/11998/w1080xh810_DreamHackheader1.jpg?ts=1473876560">
                <media:credit>DreamHack</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>This year&#39;s edition of DreamHack Bucharest will see a handful of the top CS:GO teams compete for a piece of the tournament&#39;s $100,000 pot. Seven of the eight teams going to Bucharest will be coming straight from Kiev, where they played in the SL i-League Season 2 Finals a week earlier. Because of that, we&#39;ll see a number of familiar matchups, but the chance at redemption for some teams should make this tournament an interesting one to watch.</p><h2><strong>Group A</strong></h2><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12004/cropped_28971414774_ee3aab2b8a_k.jpg?ts=1473948767"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><h3><strong>Top Performers</strong></h3><figure class="article-segment--table"><div class="table-responsive"><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Team</th>
<th>Player</th>
<th>HLTV Rating</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Gambit eSports</td>
<td>AdreN</td>
<td>1.17</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Team EnVyUs</td>
<td>kennyS</td>
<td>1.15</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Heroic</td>
<td>valde</td>
<td>1.14</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Virtus.pro</td>
<td>Snax</td>
<td>1.08</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table></div></figure><h3><strong>Opening matchups</strong></h3><ul><li>Virtus.pro vs. Gambit eSports</li><li>Heroic vs. Team EnVyUs</li></ul><p>Virtus.pro versus Gambit eSports is a familiar matchup, as the two teams have faced each other six times during ELEAGUE Season 1's group stage round robin, group stage playoffs and Last Chance Qualifier. Gambit only won a single map on Nuke and forced an overtime on Dust 2, but the rest of the maps were one-sided wins in favor of the Poles.</p><p>On the flipside, there are a lot of questions surrounding Heroic and Team EnVyUs&#39; matchup as they&#39;ve never faced each other before. Heroic have proven that they are one of the best teams in the highly competitive Danish scene after winning Power-LAN over Astralis and Team Dignitas, but their international forays have left much to be desired. They finished in third at Northern Arena Toronto, but only got Top 8 at SL i-League and failed to qualify for EPICENTER: Moscow.</p><p>EnVy are having the same consistency issues as Heroic, but their problems stem much farther back as they came in last place at the past two Majors. Though they&#39;ve had a handful of Top 8 finishes, such as ELEAGUE Season 1 and recently at the SL i-League Season 2 Finals, those finishes are too far and few between.</p><p>EnVy&#39;s only ray of hope seems to be kennyS, who is the one player on the team that&#39;s been able to pull himself out of the slump. With a 1.15 HLTV from the past three months, kennyS dwarfs his peers &mdash; the next highest is Happy with a 1.05 rating during that same time period. Meanwhile, apEX is barely performing better than the team&#39;s in-game leader, DEVIL, who has a 0.94 HLTV rating compared to apEX&#39;s 0.99 rating from the past three months.</p><h2><strong>Group B</strong></h2><figure class="article-segment--image"><img src="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12005/cropped_29049840403_8df92c11fe_k.jpg?ts=1473948767"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><h3><strong>Top Performers</strong></h3><figure class="article-segment--table"><div class="table-responsive"><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Team</th>
<th>Player</th>
<th>Rating</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Team Dignitas</td>
<td>k0nfig</td>
<td>1.15</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Cloud9</td>
<td>Stewie2K</td>
<td>1.14</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>FaZe Clan</td>
<td>allu</td>
<td>1.11</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>FlipSid3 Tactics</td>
<td>WorldEdit</td>
<td>1.08</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table></div></figure><h3><strong>Opening matchups</strong></h3><ul><li>Cloud9 vs. FlipSid3 Tactics</li><li>Team Dignitas vs. FaZe Clan</li></ul><p>FaZe Clan and Team Dignitas have faced off numerous times this year, though it&#39;s been a one-sided affair as FaZe have compiled an 8-3 record against them. There&#39;s a bit of an unknown factor now, since FaZe recently replaced Fox with allu, but unfortunately for Dignitas, it seemed to be a positive change across the board. As such, the Danes will need to bring out something special to beat their international rivals.</p><p>Cloud9 have been the North American hopeful in international events since they picked up autimatic and Liquid lost s1mple. They broke into HLTV&#39;s Top 5 ranking, which caused a fair amount of drama, even among C9 fans. But with a second place finish at the primarily-American tournament Northern Arena Toronto and a Top 4 placement at the SL i-League Season 2 Finals, they&#39;ve largely lived up to the hype.</p><p>C9 will have a lot of momentum going into their match against FlipSid3 Tactics, who have had their own shining moments such as securing Top 8 at SL i-League over FaZe just last week. However, F3's matchup in the quarterfinals was against C9 and the Americans took that series 2-1, so the onus will be on the CIS squad to pull off a win against C9.</p><p><em>Dennis "<strong>Tarmanydyn</strong>" Gonzales is a news editor for theScore esports who enjoys whiskey, D&amp;D and first-picking <s>Abaddon</s> <s>Slardar</s> <s>Clinkz</s> <s>Medusa</s> <s>Oracle</s> <s>a</s> <s>P90</s> my Souvenir Negev. <a href="http://twitter.com/Tarmanydyn">You can follow him on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10394</guid>
            <title>ESL Pro League Finals to host 12 teams at request of new WESA Players Council</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10394</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 17:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/8481/w1080xh810_lL94FKlvuilA.878x0.Z-Z96KYq123.jpg?ts=1457972575">
                <media:credit>Valve, ESL</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>The World Electronic Sports Association&#39;s new Players Council, <a data-in-app-uri="thescoreesports:///news/10364" href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10364">announced just yesterday</a>, has already decided on an important change to the ESL Pro League format, according to an <a href="http://en.pro.eslgaming.com/csgo/proleague/news/announcing-the-new-format-and-schedule-for-the-esl-pro-league-finals-in-brazil/">announcement on ESL&#39;s website</a>.</p><p>ESL announced that this season&#39;s LAN finals have been expanded to include 12 teams &mdash; six from EU and six from NA &mdash; up from the traditional eight teams that have attended in past seasons. </p><p>According to the release, the decision came from the new Players Council, led by chairman and Fnatic CS:GO team manager Viktor &quot;<strong>vuggo</strong>&quot; Jendeby. WESA announced the results of its Players Council election yesterday, bringing on Ninjas in Pyjamas&#39; Adam &quot;<strong>friberg</strong>&quot; Friberg, Natus Vincere&#39;s Sergey &quot;<strong>starix</strong>&quot; Ishchuk and Virtus.pro&#39;s Wiktor &quot;<strong>TaZ</strong>&quot; Wojtas, among others.</p><p>In a statement, vuggo call the old eight-team EPL format &quot;outdated.&quot;</p><p>&quot;The scene is now more competitive than ever, and so it feels natural to extend a tournament of this caliber to enable more teams to attend the finals,&quot; he said. </p><p>To accommodate the added teams, the group stage has been expanded to a best-of-one round robin with two groups of six teams each. vuggo said the Council &quot;suggested more guaranteed LAN-matches for the teams attending, and proposed a format with two groups of six &mdash; like it is used at IEM events. ESL listened and we, the WESA Player Council, are very happy with how the new format looks like, and I hope the community will appreciate it as well.&quot;</p><p>In the new format, the top three teams from each group will move forward to the playoffs, which will be a single-elimination, best-of-three bracket. The first-place teams in each group will be seeded into the semifinals, while the second- and third-place teams will face off in the quarterfinals.</p><p>The event is set to run from Oct. 26-30 in São Paulo, Brazil, with teams competing for a $750,000 prizepool.</p><p><em>Olivia Da Silva is a news editor at theScore esports. She likes piña coladas, getting caught in the rain and dank no-scopes. Feel free to <a href="https://twitter.com/TheDaSilvaDaily">follow her on Twitter.</a></em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10395</guid>
            <title>Team EnVyUs invited to Gfinity Invitational</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10395</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 16:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/12008/w1080xh810_29306389990_10f9fa4774_k.jpg?ts=1473957196">
                <media:credit>SL i-League</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Team EnVyUs are the third team invited to the Gfinity Invitational, according to an <a href="http://www.gfinity.net/news/details/team-envyus-team-profile-cs-go-invitational-egx-2016">announcement from the tournament organizers</a> on Thursday.</p><p>EnVy join previously invited teams <a href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/csgo/news/10371-mousesports-invited-to-gfinity-invitational">mousesports</a> and <a href="http://www.thescoreesports.com/csgo/news/10365-godsent-invited-to-gfinity-invitational">GODSENT</a>. The final invite is expected tomorrow.</p><p>The French team recently finished in the Top 8 at SL i-League Season 2 LAN Finals and will compete in DreamHack Bucharest on Sept. 16-18 before heading to England for the Gfinity Invitational.</p><p>Though the team's results have been up and down for much of the season, their star player Kenny "<strong>kennyS</strong>" Schrub has shown flashes of brilliance reminiscent of his heyday around two years ago. He currently has a 1.15 HLTV rating averaged from the past three months.</p><p>The Gfinity Invitational features a $100,000 prize pool and will take place on Sept. 22-25 at EGX 2016 in the National Exhibition Centre in Birmingham, England.</p><p><a href="http://www.gfinity.net/events/details/the-gfinity-cs-go-invitational-brought-to-you-by-omen-by-hp">Further details on the tournament</a>, such as the schedule and format, are expected in the future.</p><p><em>Dennis "<strong>Tarmanydyn</strong>" Gonzales is a news editor for theScore esports who enjoys whiskey, D&amp;D and first-picking <s>Abaddon</s> <s>Slardar</s> <s>Clinkz</s> <s>Medusa</s> <s>Oracle</s> <s>a</s> <s>P90</s> my Souvenir Negev. <a href="http://twitter.com/Tarmanydyn">You can follow him on Twitter</a>.</em></p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10392</guid>
            <title>Team Prospects drop out of ECS Development League after losing 3 players</title>
            <link>http://www.thescoreesports.com/news/10392</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 15:38:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator/>
            <media:content url="https://dqrt72khb0whk.cloudfront.net/uploads/image/file/8865/w1080xh810_ECSHeader2.jpg?ts=1459959394">
                <media:credit>theScore esports / ECS / FACEIT</media:credit>
            </media:content>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[<p>Team Prospects have withdrawn from the ECS Development League after losing three of the five players who played with them in the qualifiers, according to team captain Josh "<strong>JoshRT</strong>" Lee.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Damn need to forfeit the <a href="https://twitter.com/ecsleague">@ecsleague</a> dev league b/c of not being able to field 3/5 original members from the qualifiers 😞</p>— Josh Lee (@JoshRT_CSGO) <a href="https://twitter.com/JoshRT_CSGO/status/776096282494509057">September 14, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Made my fair share of mistakes but doesn't mean the end for my team. Take a step back and then 2 steps forward to prove the doubters wrong.</p>— Josh Lee (@JoshRT_CSGO) <a href="https://twitter.com/JoshRT_CSGO/status/776097249680060416">September 14, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>This week, Team Prospects had to forfeit their ECS Development League NA Week 2 matches against paiN Gaming and SofaKingGood because they were missing three of their players, according to ECS.</p><p>"Team Prospects was unable to field 60 percent of their registered lineup and have therefore forfeited their matches," a spokesperson for the league told theScore esports in an email.</p><p>Prospects qualified for the Development League in the second of four qualifiers, after defeating Vaconian, Gut Tough Gaming and bRAiNd34d in the single-elimination bracket. At the time, the team was made up of JoshRT, Caleb "<strong>sayonara</strong>" Lee, Adam "<strong>Juice</strong>" Sar, Dylan "<strong>rik0k0</strong>" Arnce and Tayler "<strong>Drone</strong>" Johnson.</p><p>However, Juice, rik0k0 and Drone left the team after their 2-0 loss to Selfless Gaming in the first week of the league.</p><figure class="article-segment--embed"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I've decided to part ways with <a href="https://twitter.com/ProspectsGG">@ProspectsGG</a>, and am currently a free agnet. Wish them the best of luck in the upcoming season.</p>— Drone (@Dronecsgo) <a href="https://twitter.com/Dronecsgo/status/775131229414952960">September 12, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></figure><p>Prospects' next ECS match was set to be against Renegades on Sept. 17. It is currently unknown whether Renegades will face another team, or receive a bye.</p><p><em>Sasha Erfanian is a news editor for theScore esports. <a href="https://twitter.com/SashaErfanian">Follow him on Twitter</a>, it'll be great for his self-esteem.</em></p><p> </p><p><small><em>Copyright &copy; 2016 Score Media Ventures Inc. All rights reserved. Certain content reproduced under license.</em></small></p>]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
